<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-19/NIG_ERF/RA2/WASH/NGO/14173</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated WASH sustainability, Hygiene Promotion and Cholera Preparedness/Response in Rann Town Kala Balge Local Government Area of Borno state</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is focused on providing an integrated emergency WASH intervention in Rann town and the 3 IDP Camps there. The intervention is in response to the widespread displacement of the conflicted affected population from the hinterlands  which enjoys relative peace leading to the overcrowding of camps and over utilization of basic amenities, WASH facilities and services inclusive. The project will address deterioration in positive hygiene practices as a result of limited supplies and sustained sensitization, insufficient safe access to water due to over-utilization or lack of proper OampM support, insufficient access to safe bathrooms and latrines fitted with hand-washing facility and lack of proper solid waste management in the 3 IDP Camps and the larger town of  Rann 
In order to reestablish improved and safe access to general WASH services to the conflict affected population in the camps and the Town the following Key WASH intervention has been designed for this project with the objective of lifesaving lives and ensuring dignity and protection of the IDPs.
1.	promoting good hygiene practices: This activity would be carried out by the 10 trained hygiene promoters for 6 months targeting 26,600 inhabitants of Rann Host Community and the 3 IDP camps namely: Boarding Primary school Camp. General Hospital Camp and Kalagaru Camp
Lifesaving hygiene practices capable of maintaining and improving the health status of the New Arrivals will be introduced/reintroduced to the camps. Community leaders, heads of households, women groups, girls of reproductive age and children will be sensitized on hygiene practices which include hand washing practices and menstrual hygiene management among other things.

2. Provision of adequate water for domestic use  
In line with sphere standards, the project will provide water for domestic use to IDPs in the overcrowded camps. It will explore the following approach: 
-	Rehabilitation and maintenance  and one shock  chlorination of 43 water points- Minor repairs of the water points, constant maintenance 
3.	Providing sanitation facilities (37 latrines and 20 bathrooms and fixing of 50 existing Latrines/showers for the 3 above mentioned IDP Camps
In line with the Sphere standard, gender dis-aggregated bathrooms and latrines and rehabilitation of 100 household latrines in Rann host Community
4.	Provision of context-specific hygiene dignity kits 1000 Adolescent girls
With the aid of a  survey of the target population, a context-specific hygiene dignity kits will be procured to adolescent girls. The kids will include sanitary pads and other identified needs of the women and girls. After the distribution and before the end of the project end line assessment will be conducted again to evaluation the impact of the intervention. 

Sustainability of the project is hinged on two principles &#x2013; 1) building the capacity of the  community (selected WASHCOM members and selected Kala Balge LGA Works, Sanitation and Environment staff) by training and involving them in the implementation of the project. 2) By providing post implementation oversight  and maintenance of WASH facilities by monitoring and following-up with concerned departments in Kala LGA 

5  Cholera preparedness and response capacity building to 30 Local Government staff
6  Cholera kits provision to 30 trained officials
7  Kala Balge WASH establishment where 30 committees would be formed and equipped with basic WASHCOM working tools 

The  Ant Cholera sustaina of the this WASH project:  The trained 30 cholera officials for which 80% would be selected from actual residents of Rann town would be equipped with 2 cholera kits. One would be given to them immediately after the training while the 2nd kit would be given to them after May 2020 when KABHUDA is pulling out to ensure sustainability in Cholera response capacity in Rann town</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kanem Borno Human Development Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kanem Borno Human Development Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-06" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Onu Aroh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>08062327449</telephone>
   <email>john.onu@kanemborno.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibrahim Bukar Wulo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>07037121919</telephone>
   <email>kabhuda@yahoo.co.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG008">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Borno</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.88898010 13.15334698</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-06"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-06"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-06">199974.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-14173">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-06">199974.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kanem Borno Human Development Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
