<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-19/NIG_ERF/RA1/S/NFI-DMS/INGO/12281</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Critical emergency shelter and non-food item assistance to newly displaced persons in Borno</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed 6 month project aims to provide critical integrated emergency response to urgent needs faced by newly displaced individuals in Borno State, through the provision of emergency shelter and critical non-food item (NFI) assistance, and implementation of rainy season preparedness and risk mitigation strategies in vulnerable IDP communities. The Action will aim to contribute to the Inter-Sectoral Working Group&#x2019;s 90-Day Response Plan, addressing the critical shelter and non-food item needs on the ground in Monguno and MMC LGA, consequent of over 44,000 new arrivals seeking safety after increased territorial gains by Organized Armed Groups (OAGs) in Kukawa LGA in late 2018 (OCHA: 90-Day Response Plan, February 2019). Further, the proposed project will support the maintenance and care of one IDP site in close collaboration with the Sector and active CCCM partner on the ground, through supporting vital rainy season preparedness activities, in order to enhance risk mitigation against severe damage and loss of property due to extreme weather anticipated during the wet season of 2019.

The project will thus contribute towards the objectives set out by the 90-Day response plan for emergency shelter and NFI assistance, and towards the objectives of the CCCM Sector by providing site care and conducting site upgrades. In alignment with core objectives of the Shelter and Non-Food Item Sector, the project will address immediate shelter and NFI needs faced by new arrivals, while ensuring equitable and safe access to life-saving assistance for vulnerable and newly internally displaced persons (IDPs). In order to provide immediate relief to new arrivals in Monguno and MMC, ACTED proposes to build on its experience and current presence on the ground in these two locations, through engagement of its dedicated Shelter and NFI Team, in order to provision emergency aid in coordination with the Sectoral response. The Action will strengthen the overall humanitarian response to address urgent needs faced by the over 44,000 new arrivals between both locations, by providing Bama type emergency shelters, and non-food item assistance, contributing towards the significant decrease of protection risks faced by displaced families that lack access to basic and essential household needs. In line with core objectives of the DMS-CCCM Sector, the Action will identify IDP sites in most urgent need of rainy season preparedness, and will deploy ACTED&#x2019;s experienced CCCM Team to conduct immediate site care and reinforcement ahead of the 2019 rain and storm season. Such activities are vital to minimize risk of personal property loss and damage experienced by IDPs throughout the wet season, mitigate adverse impact of flooding, and will thus promote quality standards of living for displaced communities.

In light of the volume of new arrivals in Monguno and Maiduguri since December 2018, with over 25,200 new arrivals in Maiduguri and 10,500 new arrivals in Monguno from November 2018 to January 10 2019, the humanitarian system has been unable to mobilize the scale of response required to meet the vast needs present on the ground. As an experienced Shelter and NFI Actor, both in Northeast Nigeria and globally, ACTED is proposing to support and strengthen the SNFI Sector-led and coordinated SNFI response, by procuring and constructing 400 Bama type emergency shelters,  and procuring, prepositioning and distributing 400 improved non-food item kits. 

To ensure inter-sectoral coverage of needs faced by newly displaced families, the Action will target the same households with both shelter and NFI assistance, based on needs. Without double counting, and applying a five-member household average, the Action will provide immediate and critical relief to  4,000 newly displaced individuals seeking refuge in MMC and Monguno LGAs. Households will be targeted with both items on a needs basis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lucy Coley</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+234 813 429 3834</telephone>
   <email>lucy.coley@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG008">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Borno</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.88898010 13.15334698</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="10" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="90" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-11-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-06">314000.89</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6306664370">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-19">21917.18</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-12281">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-06">314000.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304035528">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-11">251200.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304497128">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-18">62800.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
