<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-18/DDA-3415/SA1/H-P/UN/9706</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening SRH services, MHPSS and GBV, and referrals for displaced and conflict-affected communities in Central Rakhine through mobile services</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project, Strengthening SRH services, MHPSS and GBV, and referrals for displaced and conflict-affected communities in Central Rakhine through mobile services, aims to contribute to reducing maternal mortality and morbidity by improving the accessibility of primary health care, reproductive health services, referral services, GBV prevention and mental health and psychosocial support services (MHPSS), as set out by the Myanmar Humanitarian Response Plan 2017.

Key Objectives of the project are to:
1. To deliver integrated sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR) and primary health care services in the targeted areas to quality standards
2. To improve availability, accessibility of timely referral services in Rakhine camps and Muslim villages.
3. Increase community knowledge and support and action to demand quality reproductive health services
4. Improve availability and access to gender-based violence (GBV) and mental health and psychosocial support (MHPSS) services at community levels

Prior to the most recent wave of events in Rakhine State from August 25th, access to health facilities and skilled health workers was already extremely poor. According to the 2015-2016 Demographic and Health Survey (DHS), Rakhine State was the state/region with the highest percentage of women who did not receive any antenatal care and where less than one in five women give birth at health facilities. Intercommunal conflicts and armed conflict in Rakhine State have further exacerbated tension contributing to fear and mistrust affecting service-seeking behavior and prompted the closure of some health facilities and suspensions in the delivery of health services, thereby further deteriorating access to quality sexual and reproductive health (SRH) services. In addition, access to mental health and psychosocial support, and GBV prevention and response services remains extremely limited. As per the newly released Ministry of Health and Sports (MOHS) GBV Guidelines, there is a clear role for health care providers when it comes to screening and supporting clients who are survivors of GBV. Many of them, however, are not aware or comfortable with this role. There is need to build the capacity of service providers on GBV prevention and response and utilize their interaction with community members through service provision and outreach activities to raise awareness of GBV and its impacts as well improve referrals to more specialized case management services when they are available. 

This project will support the implementation of MISP and transition toward more comprehensive SRH ensuring that drug supplies, including contraceptives and drugs to treat rape survivors and STIs, are available without discrimination. This means that women, men, adolescents, elderly and the disabled of all ethnicities, religions and sexual orientations having equitable access to services that meet recognized standards.

Delivering a minimum initial package of sexual and reproductive health services including provision of post-rape care, and meeting the unmet need for family planning will contribute toward ensuring that the 15% of currently pregnant women who experience complications each month are more easily able to access care, and to preventing unwanted pregnancies, among other outcomes. UNFPA in collaboration with Myanmar Medical Association (MMA) will work closely with key stakeholders to strengthen the delivery, coordination, and management of SRH services in order to improve effectiveness and efficiency of the health system. The programme will deliver a minimum package of SRH services to 37 Rakhine sites and 5 Muslim camps in Sittwe. The villages and camps were selected in coordination with other health implementing agencies in Sittwe (IRC, Mercy Malaysia, MHAA, etc.) providing primary health care services to avoid duplication and ensure the broadest coverage of services in Sittwe township.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Medical Association (MMA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mollie Fair</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Response Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 9429917443</telephone>
   <email>fair@unfpa.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kazutaka Sekine</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SRHR Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 9454160579</telephone>
   <email>sekine@unfpa.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR012">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.50000000 94.00000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="80" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-19">64471.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-19">193415.41</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-9706">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-19">257887.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303565174">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-25">257887.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400301752">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-01">7162.81</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
