<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-209131-GB-CHC-209131-NF- PER</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BRITISH COUNCIL</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton fund, Peru</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton Fund prioritised themes in Peru are Health , Biodiversity, Water and Research Governance. Newton Fund Project activities managed by the British Council since 2017 have made it possible to strengthen collaborative work between researchers (500+), public and private institutions (274+), and Peruvian and British public officials (288+) around barriers, challenges and opportunities in Peru. The British Council is recognised as one of the main promoters of the research, technology and innovation agenda in Peru, with special attention to regions (outside Lima capital city) with the aim of reducing gaps by strengthening capacities and generating connections that contribute to improving the socioeconomic well-being in the country. For FY 21/22 our work is focused in 2 items: The governance of the Science, Technology and Innovation (STI), reinforcing research in biodiversity (the Bicentennial Plan 2021-24) and assistance to the new government that takes post in July 2021 (elections were held in April 2021).  In this sense, the outputs of the technical consultancies will be an input for the decision-making of the new decision-makers and public policies officials to improve the management and use of science as a multisectoral tool.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Primary target groups are early and senior career researchers, policy makers and government officials. Additionally, we involve the business sector and civil society. Communication of project impact will concern government and non-government organisations already part of multisectoral working groups to improve science in Peru.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The British Council has worked jointly with CONCYTEC, as the main local partner, in the planning and implemantation of the Newton Fund project in Peru. Furthermore, other local key stakeholders that have been involved are : the Cabinet Office, Ministry of Economics, Ministry of Production, Ministry of Environment, Ministry of Education, Ministry of Foreign Affairs , regional governments (Tumbes, Piura, La Libertad, San Martin, Tacna, Cajamarca, Moquegua, Cuzco, Ayacucho) and associations  (FabLab,CREEAS, Asociacion Pataz). Important to highlight that the research bilateral collaboration of experts and institutions also contributes to the internationalisation agenda at home, which is also a priority for CONCYTEC and Ministry of Education. In sharing UK&apos;s values and expertise, project has received the oversight from BEIS, Satellite Catapult Center, UKRI,  the Scottish Government (Environment &amp; Forestry), Botanic Gardens Conservation International (BCGI),  Cranfield university, Nesta, Oxentia Ltd., regional initiatives in Nottingham and Swindon among others.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ongoing technical assistance work seeks to provide preliminary guidelines and roadmaps that serve Consejo Nacional de Ciencia, Tecnolog&#xED;a e Innovaci&#xF3;n Tecnol&#xF3;gica (CONCYTEC), our main ally in Science,Technology and Innovation, and other relevant actors in the ecosystem, in the current process of restructuration of the governance of the STI ecosystem. 
1. Technical assistance for a roadmap to accompany the implementation of a scientific advice unit or scheme, which will provide intelligence and scientific advice to institutions responsible for public policy and technological transfer-absortion to the private sector. A scientific advice unit or scheme supports the need for evidence of sound research to be provided in a timely manner, and at earlier stages in the development and implementation of public policies. 
2. Technical assistance to design and develop a National Botanic Garden for scientific research,  biodiversity preservation, as a educational space and for the enjoyment of nature. This aligns with the country global commitments with OECD and Climate Change agenda.
Additionally, in FY 21/22 we are funding 2 projects under the Newton Fund Impact Scheme call:
1. Applying and evaluating a new quantitative method to select climate-resilient cereal varieties to improve farmer livelihoods and community nutrition in Peru
2. Translation through demonstration - moving TB whole genome sequencing in Peru from research into policy and practice.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="2" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="4" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy (BEIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <telephone>00441619577755</telephone>
   <email>IATI@britishcouncil.org</email>
   <website>https://www.britishcouncil.pe/programas/educacion/ciencia-innovacion/fondo-newton</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-id code="3936456" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lima</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-12.0235 -77.0142</pos>
   </point>
   <location-class code="2"></location-class>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton Peru is a national project and is delivered in Lima, covering the entire country.</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="11420" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">46386</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
