<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>PK-SEC-0080655-DAFPAK-PTD-update</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="PK-SEC-0080655" secondary-reporter="1" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DKT Pakistan</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DAFPAK Program Update (Project to date)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under the DAFPAK accountable grant, we have successfully delivered our results during the project-to-date period. Key achievements / milestones for the period are as follows: IMPACT INDICATOR: &#x25CF; 505 Maternal Deaths Averted (136% of project to date target) OUTCOME INDICATOR: &#x25CF; 591,475 Unintended Pregnancies Averted (137% of project to date target) &#x25CF; 179,832 Unsafe Abortions Averted (137% of project to date target) &#x25CF; 538,242 DALYs Averted (137% of project to date target) &#x25CF; 961,578 Total Family Planning Users (298% of project to date target) OUTPUT INDICATOR: &#x25CF; 2,017,105 CYPs generated ( 149% of project to date target) VALUE FOR MONEY: &#x25CF; The project to date cost per CYP is GBP 4.35. The overall revised cost per CYP target for DAFPAK is GBP 5.01 for the period Dec 2018 &#x2013; Mar 2022.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With support from DFID, DKT in the last six years has become a significant contributor in the Pakistan Family Planning landscape. Using a hybrid model (social marketing and franchising), DKT has been able to reach the hard to reach through its network of clinics and social outlets. DKT successfully demonstrated the CMW network model during the DRHR period and continues to evolve and improve the model under the current DAFPAK project, thereby highlighting the important role that CMWs can play in family planning and women health in Pakistan and improved quality / cost of products for all the key players in the sector. Speed, action and initiative is part of DKTs DNA, combine this with learning from best practices and you have innovations. Based on our experience with the CMW network of clinics and learning from other implementing partners, we are now evolving our model to empower women by helping them penetrate further into remote areas of Pakistan at the same time enabling these entrepreneurial providers to sustain themselves while continue to provide quality FP and women health services. The best part is that the existing CMW partner clinic network is scalable; women focused and develops the closest service point to the clients (increasing penetration in rural territories). Based on program learning from DAFPAK, and as we become a significant player in the family planning landscape, DKT is able to attract larger national distributors on pure business growth and strength. DKT has successfully circumvented the IUD shortage by signing an agreement with Injeflex Brazil for Pakistan. This is the only UNFPA approved manufacturer outside India. This agreement has opened access to all DAFPAK partner and NGOs to IUDs from Brazil. The first supplies will be arriving in Pakistan during first quarter of 2020. DKT Pakistan is on-track with our sustainability plan and is monitoring the same on a quarterly basis even though the reporting is annual. This will fast-track the sustainability gains.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="PK-SEC-0080655" role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DKT Pakistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DKT Pakistan, an affiliate company of DKT International, USA, has been operating in Pakistan since 2012. DKT International has offices in 24 countries and sales presence in 60 countries. While a relative latecomer to the Pakistan social marketing scene, it has shaken up the field and increased the competition. Registered as a private limited company in Pakistan, it works closely with the Government of Pakistan, making it less susceptible to Government changes.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="13030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
