<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="257" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/21439" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-2-21439</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urgent Response to the Reception of South Sudanese Refugees in Imvepi, West Nile, Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on an analysis of WASH needs, Action Against Hunger proposes to: (1) Improve access of the target population to a sustainable and reliable source of drinking water. Four new water points will be built, one of which will be equipped with a motorized pump. Two pumps with human motility will be rehabilitated and three repaired; (2) Ensure better hygiene and sanitation conditions at the community level. To this end, twenty public latrines equipped with shower space, and twenty latrines adapted for people with reduced mobility will be built to meet the needs of newcomers. In a second step, construction and hygiene kits will be distributed to increase the coverage of private latrines. Hygiene awareness actions will be conducted to ensure the adoption of these latrines and reduce the risk of developing water-borne diseases; (3) Specific action will target malnourished people to limit the impact of water-borne diseases on nutritional status, especially for women and children; and (4) the health and nutrition centers as well as the schools receiving refugees will be supported to adapt their WaSH structures and equipment to the large and rapid increase of the population.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In response to the massive and unprecedented influx of South Sudanese refugees into northern Uganda, Action Against will implement, with the support of the Crisis and Support Center, a project to cover basic needs of newcomers, in Imvepi, in terms of water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH). The deterioration of the political and security situation in South Sudan since July 2016 has led to the massive and unprecedented influx of South Sudanese refugees into Northern Uganda (647,033 South Sudanese refugees between July 2016 and March 2017). Opened in 2017, Imvepi is the last reception area to be created. Located in the Arua district, Imvepi is halfway between Arua and Yumbe, the two major cities in the area. Imvepi is located in a sparsely populated area with little infrastructure and poor soil. It is administered by the Office of the Prime Minister in partnership with UNHCR, with management from the Arua District for access to health and nutrition centers and district public schools.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">French Ministry of Foreign and European Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="UGE6A" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2-21439" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.actionagainsthunger.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="13" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-08-01">500000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">French Ministry of Foreign and European Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
