<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="257" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/21440" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-2-21440</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi-Sectoral Emergency Assistance to South Sudanese Refugees in West Nile, Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government of Uganda&#x2019;s progressive policy of welcoming refugees and the country&#x2019;s geographic position on the border of two countries experiencing protracted conflict has led to Uganda&#x2019;s hosting the largest population of refugees in Africa. As of May 1st, 2017, Uganda hosts a total population of 909,723 South Sudanese refugees and asylum seekers. An average of 2,061 new individuals continue to arrive from South Sudan per day (July 2016 &#x2013; May 2017), with immediate and unmet humanitarian needs. Over 65% of water is provided through water trucking, an unsustainable practice Action Against Hunger, DRC, and LWF plan to replace with borehole drilling and motorization. Household latrine coverage is incredibly low, and the influx of refugees is putting considerable pressure on water and sanitation facilities in existing local institutions. Open defecation by new arrivals puts all at risk to the outbreak of diarrheal diseases. Given widespread rape reported in South Sudan, there is a critical need to provide protection to the new arrivals, many of whom having experienced physical and sexual abuse. Assessments show a severe lack of child protection interventions in the settlements, with data showing that the main stressors for parents include the inability to meet basic needs, children separated or remaining in country of origin, and lack of access to healthcare and education. Leading causes of morbidity for refugees and host communities are under- and mal-nutrition, malaria, respiratory tract infections, and diarrhea.

In this consortium-led project, Action Against Hunger, DRC, LWF and Save the Children will respond to nutrition, health, water, sanitation and hygiene needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will conduct drilling and motorizing high yielding boreholes at institutional and community level, forming Water User Committees to manage the boreholes and other water sources. To help increase household latrine coverage, the organizations will distribute digging kits and sanitation kits, as well as reinforce public sanitation facilities. It will identify and train community based hygiene promoters and conduct awareness campaigns on these issues. The organizations will train and support stakeholders on Gender Based Violence prevention, response and case management. To enhance the protection of refugees, the project will install 55 solar lamps to provide for safer travel and construct persons with special needs (PSN) shelters and latrines. The organizations will provide access to high impact healthcare services through two health care teams working through a mobile clinic and a level II facility. Appropriate and optimal IYCF practices will be promoted through Village Health Teams and the setup of Mother Babies Areas, or safe spaces where mothers can rest, privately breastfeed, and bond with their children. Finally, the organizations will strengthen the capacity of staff and partners in case management to improve child protection mechanisms.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Department for International Development (DFID)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="UGG1B" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2-21440" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.actionagainsthunger.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="8" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">3866804</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Department for International Development (DFID)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="136300"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
