<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="257" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/21573" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-2-21573</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving the Nutrition Status of Children Under 5 in Gogrial West, Former Warrap State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In South Sudan ACF proposes to implement nutrition activities in Gogrial West County, Warrap State; an area in the north of the country which, as a result of the recent insecurity in the country, has seen some of the highest malnutrition rates in South Sudan during 2016. This project will form part of the Humanitarian Response Plan for 2017, which is currently being drafted, by focusing on life saving services and improving community protection and resilience through addressing the immediate and underlying causes of malnutrition.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The nutrition intervention will be divided into two components:  

Prevention: will include regular community-based MUAC screening, case identification and referrals of malnourished children under 5 years. Community Volunteers (CVs) will be trained not only on the identification of malnutrition and screening of the targeted population, but also on hygiene promotion. 

Treatment: at OTP level, SAM children will receive therapeutic treatment according to national protocols. In addition, a Therapeutic Supplementary Feeding Program will be provided to PLWs and children under 5 affected by MAM. For cases with medical complications, Action Against Hunger will provide therapeutic treatment for SAM children (6-59 months) by referring them to the Stabilization Center and ensuring they receive appropriate treatment. For children less than 6 months the focus will be on restoring exclusive breastfeeding through Supplementary Suckling Technic (SST) and individual counselling to mothers. 

The overall project will be supported by on-going education sessions on IYCF, Nutrition, Health, WASH and child care practices and by an extensive behavioral change component specifically focused on cooking demonstrations and nutrition awareness at community level. Through household level engagement ACF will ensure that these sessions include both men and women, engaging men also in addressing the issues related to improving nutrition and hygiene. Within this, ACF will mainstream gender within all phases of the project, ensuring that the design and implementation accounts for the differing needs of men, women, girls and boys and that they are involved in decision making and project design.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Canadian International Development Agency (CIDA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SSF2A" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2-21573" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.actionagainsthunger.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="8" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="CAD" value-date="2017-04-01">800000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Canadian International Development Agency (CIDA)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="22235"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
