<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="257" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/21417" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-2-21417</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Improvement of Food and Nutrition Security and Resilience Strategies for Vulnerable Households in the Lower Northwest</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger aims to sustainably improve the food and nutritional security and the health situation of the most vulnerable households in the communes of the lower Northwest, and to reinforce their level of resilience in the face of recurrence of climatic shocks in attacking the causes of food and nutritional insecurity of populations and the determinants of their vulnerabilities to shock. We will promote direct and financial access to sufficient, healthy, and diversified food produced locally and improve the overall health environment of the poorest households.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger will strengthen local food production by improving agricultural productivity to increase the availability of local food. The intervention will identify watersheds with high agricultural potential and support good management, as well as developing sub-watersheds and the rehabilitation of irrigated perimeters by the protection of sources of water. Development activities upstream of the irrigated perimeters will allow better exploitation of water resources by planters, increase agricultural production downstream through the stabilization of resources, and increase soil fertility in the upstream portion of the watershed. Coupled with the sustainable management of natural resources and the integration of composting and organic waste treatment technologies, the project will reduce the food insecurity of poor farming households and support their resilience strategies against shock. Furthermore, the organization will strengthen the technical capabilities of small local producers (agricultural training, inputs, storage, processing, marketing, etc.) and organizational producer associations (training on self-management, etc.), and encourage irrigators&#x2019; associations to allow the balanced and efficient use of their infrastructure and production resources, particularly water for irrigation. By building on existing village and VSLA agent networks in the area, income-generating activities (such as small market gardening activities) will be promoted to encourage income diversification of beneficiary households, improve their (financial) access to diversified and nutritious food. Additionally, the project will provide education sessions and sensitization on good nutrition practices, and consolidate the nutritional surveillance system of the region. Finally, by relying on water point committees and strengthening village repairers and securing the supply of spare parts, the action will strengthen the management of sanitation infrastructure, drinking water supply, and water treatment at home.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HTA4A" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2-21417" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-26" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.actionagainsthunger.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="osm_391963">
   <location-id code="391963" vocabulary="G2"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nord Ouest</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nord Ouest, Haiti (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="391963" level="1" vocabulary="G2"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.82075065 -73.03750677</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="8" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-27">1250000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-3327220">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger | ACF-USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
