<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHAS-HPC6770-4913</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHAS-HPC6770" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening health services for Syrian refugees and the host community in Lebanon</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1- Free integrated health care insurance in accordance with correct and refined standards
2- Development of the National Health Information System and Data Management
3- Supporting existing national programs such as tuberculosis and HIV / STI related to infectious diseases and speeding up monitoring them and referring them to the competent authority.
4- Participation in the routine vaccination campaigns approved by the World Health Organization and the Lebanese Ministry of Health
5- Health and nutritional education and education, promoting personal and general hygiene, limiting the spread of epidemic, contagious and communicable diseases, promoting healthy eating methods, measuring the weight and height of children, and the need to deal with cases of dwarfism and cases that need nutritional support
6- Psychological support for refugees and the host community in general, and children with physical and sensory disabilities in particular, and assisting them in reaching specialized centers to obtain the necessary medical needs
7- Providing health care services and psychological, social and nutritional support, participating in routine vaccination campaigns, and providing free medicines to Syrian refugees in the Arsal region and its countryside, and Lebanese citizens in the Republic of Lebanon.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1- The center&apos;s readiness to provide health and nutritional care, psychosocial health and diagnostic services
2- Securing job opportunities for the medical and professional staff for (62) licensed Lebanese and Syrian employees
3- Limiting the emigration of medical and professional staff
4- Providing health and nutrition services and psychological support and making them aware of specialized cadres and alleviating the suffering of Syrian refugees in Lebanon.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting a primary health care center in the Baalbek-Arsal region in providing basic health services to Syrian refugees in Lebanon while providing health services according to the standards of the World Health Organization and the Lebanese Ministry of Health.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al- Ameen For Humanitarian Support</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="4913" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-OCHA-HPC6770" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="122" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-01">938699</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-01">938699</value>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
