<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHAS-HPC6770-6628</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHAS-HPC6770" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening health services for Syrian refugees and the host community in Lebanon, Arsal Governorate - Baalbek (Phase II).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1- Providing free integrated health care according to correct and improved standards
2- Developing the national health information and data management system.
3- Supporting existing national programs such as tuberculosis and HIV/STI related to infectious diseases, and quickly monitoring them and referring them to the competent authority.
4- Participation in routine vaccination campaigns approved by the World Health Organization and the Lebanese Ministry of Health
  5- Awareness and health and nutritional education, promotion of personal and public hygiene, limiting the spread of epidemic, contagious and communicable diseases, promoting healthy nutrition methods, measuring the weight and height of children, and the necessity of dealing with cases of dwarfism and cases that need nutritional support.
6- Psychological support for refugees, the host community in general, and children with motor and sensory disabilities in particular, and help them reach specialized centers to obtain the necessary medical needs
7- Providing health care services, psychological, social and nutritional support, participating in routine vaccination campaigns, and providing free medicines to Syrian refugees in the Arsal area and its countryside and to Lebanese citizens in the Republic of Lebanon, free of charge.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing health services in accordance with the standards of the World Health Organization and the Lebanese Ministry of Health for free, while linking the provided health services to an information and technical health system that ensures sustainable follow-up and strengthening the medical referral system and the administrative system that ensures the progress of the desired medical goals in a consistent manner with the administrative and technical normative goals .</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The readiness of the center to provide health and nutritional care services, mental and social health and diagnostic services / Securing job opportunities for medical and professional cadres for (65) licensed Lebanese and Syrian employees / Reducing the migration of medical and professional cadres / Availability of health and nutritional services and psychological support and educating them from specialized cadres and alleviating suffering Syrian refugees in Lebanon.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charitable Association for Giving</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="6628" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-OCHA-HPC6770" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-01">972397</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-01">972397</value>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
