<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-30304</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SPV Cont Towers</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">-Improved mobile and broadband access: Access is one of the 3 pillars of IFC&apos;&apos;s telecoms strategy, is achieved through overall business efficiency thanks to the co-location model, as the telecoms ecosystem benefits from tower costs spread amongst multiple carriers, leading to improved access (coverage, prices, provision of additional services, etc.). The other pillars i.e. mainstreaming of private and public services and the fostering of innovation, are also achieved by a more efficient telecoms industry.     - Reduced capex and lowers operating costs: For telecoms operators, the reduced costs can translate into lower cost of services for users. Potentially, operators can unlock cash from their balance sheets (in the case existing towers are sold to independent third party operators), critical in a region like Central America, where financing options are scarce.  - Telecom sector growth Infrastructure sharing is critical in further fuelling the evolution of the telecoms market, indirectly assisting in the development of mobile broadband, and more indirectly, content and applications, mobile finance and mobile advertising, as several industry segments begin converging.  -Increased competition: co-location allows smaller operators to have access to a well managed network and they can quickly roll out their network and compete more effectively.  - Environmental benefits become evident, especially in reducing the visual burden of the explosion in tower masts (i.e., as a result of mobile telephony markets with as many as 5 operators).  - The Project also assists in the creation of both direct and indirect employment opportunities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continental Towers Holding Corporation (Continental or the Company) is a Central American telecommunications infrastructure sharing company created in 2008. The Project consists of the construction, operation and maintenance of towers in Central America, as well as the refinancing of its medium term debt. The Sponsor Terra Towers (Terra or the Sponsor), a Guatemalan company, founded Continental and together with a $70 million loan facility from Credit Suisse First Boston, started the Companys operations. Currently, the Company through its operating companies owns and operates about 500 towers in five Central American countries (Guatemala, Honduras, El Salvador, Panama, and Costa Rica). The Company is seeking $120 million of funding to: i) expand its operations by doubling its capacity, bringing its total portfolio of towers to about 1,000 by the end of 2012; and ii) refinance its existing medium term debt facility. The project also contemplates a possible geographical expansion with the penetration of other countries in the region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continental Towers Holding Corp</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-30304" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-05-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-05-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continental Towers Holding Corp. Jose Paz Managing Director Tel +(502) 2326-5000 Fax +(502) 2326-5023 15 avenida 17-40 zona 13, Noveno Nivel, Guatemala, Guatemala</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central America Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Central America Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continental Towers is incorporated in the BVI and has operating companies across Central America, including Guatemala, Honduras, El Salvador, and Panama. With the Project, the plans to expand its operations to other Central American countries.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.9000000000 -85.0333000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AD - Other (Including Satellite Telecommunications, Radio and Television Broadcasting, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $40.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-05-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-05-04">40000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-05-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-05-04">40000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continental Towers Holding Corp</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/30304/spv-cont-towers">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
