<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-28463</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grupo Poma 2009</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project consists of a corporate financing package to assist Grupo Poma (the Group) in the financing of: (i) capital expenses aimed at refurbishing existing hotels and shopping malls in Central America, including the installation of energy efficient equipment; (ii) the refinancing of existing debt; and (iii) the construction of new hotels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed investments in shopping malls will contribute to offer a safer and more convenient venue for shopping than existing alternatives. The malls offer a broad array of goods and services that benefit consumers by expanding supply and improving the quality of merchandise, services and office space. Additionally, the Group&apos;s malls have been the catalyst for surrounding residential and commercial development projects and their operations stimulate use of local supplies of goods and services in the respective countries.

The refinancing component of the Project will help the Group in strengthening its balance sheet to weather the global economic crisis and to undertake its investment program. 

The construction of new hotels will be focused on business travelers, which is largely an underserved segment within the region. The new hotels are expected to increase supply of competitive service consistent with international quality and safety standards. 

The Project will create opportunities for economic links (local and regional) between tourism and other sectors, both in the development phase (construction services and building supplies) and during on-going operations (employment and operating supplies). In addition, the Project will create both direct and indirect jobs, as well as provide training opportunities for employees. 

The Project will help further improve the Groups environmental footprint though the support of energy efficient investments. IFC is expected to assist the Group in identifying opportunities to improve energy consumption at the Groups hotels and shopping malls.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Poma Hermanos S.A. de C.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-28463" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-04-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Carlos Medina
Edificio Grupo Roble, Blvd. Tutunichapa, Costado norte de Metrocentro 
San Salvador, El Salvador
Tel (503) 2257-6000</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central America Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Central America Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The capital expenses related to the Project are expected to be implemented in different countries throughout Central America, most likely but not limited to Costa Rica, El Salvador, Panama and Nicaragua. In addition, the construction of new hotels will likely encompass a new hotel in Cali Colombia and a second one in a location pending to be determined within the Central America region or Colombia. The refinancing component of the Project will include targeted subsidiaries of the Group pending to be defined.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.9000000000 -85.0333000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Construction and Real Estate</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $50.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/28463/grupo-poma-2009">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
