<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-21/HSS10/SA1/H-P/INGO/19454</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelope 1: Integrated response for Life-saving Primary Health Care Services and Child Protection to Food Insecure IPC 5  4 Vulnerable girls and boys, women and men in Tonj East.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the proposed project SC proposes for essential health care service that prevents and reduces excess mortality and morbidity in crisis-affected populations, with a focus on primary health response: communicable diseases, reproductive health, non-communicable diseases, injury, first aid, mental health, health promotion community-level, mobile, and fixed health care facilities. The program will improve access to and scale-up of integrated quality essential health care services in Tonj East areas of 65,696  (12613 M, 13665 F, 18921 B, and 20497 G). SC currently supports four PHCUs: Akier PHCU-Palal Payam estimated catchment population 5,000 Palam PHCU-Wunlit Payam 12,909 Mapara PHCU- Paliang Payam, 11,000 Mariik PHCU-Ngapagaok Payam 4,960, with a returnee population of 1,020 and 2 mobile clinics Pan-Mourwel Malou Payam 9000, Mangen Paweng Payam 8,668 host and 13,139 newly arrived IDPs. 
These activities supported by IOM will end in July 2021, thus to extend the life-saving health intervention in Tonj East and expand coverage, SC proposes to continue the support of four PHCUs and two mobile clinics. The project will support populations in IPC severity levels 4 and 5 with the following objectives: 1) Reduce morbidity and mortality, protection threats and incidents for the most vulnerable 2): Ensure safe, equitable, and dignified access to critical cross-sectoral basic services to enable populations to meet their basic needs. SC will support community-based surveillance through mobile clinics, monitor, disseminate and analyze health information at the facilities and, mobile clinics and with the County Health Department (CHD) to ensure accurate and timely reports. SC will train and support health workers on preventive measures, screening, and basic curative care. SC will work with community health committees and existing health workers to provide health information. SC will provide immunization for children under one year of age and coordinate with MoH and other actors to obtain LLITN from other sources and distribute via static and mobile clinics. The project will support the representation and needs of vulnerable women and girls maximizing their participation and safety and access to sexual and gender-based services. COVID-19 preventive measures will be promoted at all health facilities and promote the importance of COVID 19 vaccinations.
SC will partner with Touch Africa Development Organization (TADO), a national NGO working in Tonj East. Both organizations have been coordinating with county health department and RCCE since March with respective county and state MoUs and will continue to work in partnership with the county health department who support with staff deployment and community engagement.  SC and TADO will ensure that reports are part of weekly cluster updates (5Ws) and contribute to weekly integrated disease surveillance and reports and national DHIS2 reports. SC and TADO will provide weekly updates to the national health cluster and will attend the weekly Emergency Response Meetings, the National Emergency Preparedness and Response Meetings and relevant health cluster working groups. 
Child Protection interventions will reach 9,940 persons, and will be implemented in the locations where health programs are located to ensure integrated interventions. CP systems will be established and strengthened to create a safe environment for children and their families as they have their health needs addressed. A case management system to address individual-specific concerns will be set up and implemented. Some of the key protection risks that will be prioritized include: prevention and response to family separation, GBV/SGBV, exploitation, family separation, and child labour. Mental Health and Psycho-social support platforms will also be established and strengthened to create a safe environment for children and their families.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TADO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natalie Emery</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211920874004</telephone>
   <email>Natalie.Emery@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elizabeth Berryman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Technical Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211922300179</telephone>
   <email>elizabeth.berryman@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jesca Driciru</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Protection Technical Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 920874007</telephone>
   <email>jesca.driciru@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Warrap</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.22093080 28.85968040</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="70.4" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="29.6" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-13">336027.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-13">674832.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-19454">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-13">1010859.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305195697">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-17">404343.95</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
