<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-21/HSS10/RA1/E-P/INGO/20244</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved access to integrated education and protection services for conflict affected IDPs and Host Community in Yambio County, Western Equatoria State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tambura county of Western Equatoria state experienced armed confrontation that resulted into mass killing, displacement and loss of property. About 8,065 households were displaced into Ezo and 12762 IDPs displaced into Yambio county. In Yambio, the IDPs have integrated into the host community  sharing the scarce resources. ADRA South Sudan conducted a rapid needs assessment to identify the education and protection (GBV and Child protection) needs in Yambio county for the IDP and host community members. The assessment revealed the following:

GBV cases included teen age pregnancy and forced marriages, no reported rape incidence in Yambio but women and girls expressed fear that such cases may arise and indicated they do not feel safe, especially the IDPs. They  expressed the need for dignity kits. There were fears for women and girls using negative coping mechanisms such as prostitution.

Child Protection: Children reported trauma, cases of unaccompanied and separated children and lack of recreational activities.
Cases of child labour, Unaccompanied and separated children and child abuse are common forms of child protection concerns reported by both IDPs and host community. Children expressed missing school during the displacement and expressed desire to get back to schools. As a result of the conflict that resulted to displacement, children expressed traumatic events that they observed within Tambura that involved killing of their relatives and friends. Child friendly spaces exist in Yambio run by World Vision and CMMB but are inadequate to carter for the needs of the IDP and host community children.

Education: The educational needs included learnings spaces, teaching, learning and recreational materials and incentives for teachers. WASH facilities, supplies and COVID 19 supplies were also expressed as urgent needs.  
Of the estimated 12,762 IDPs in Yambio, ADRA targets 7,933 (62%) for both education and protection activities. 4,243 individuals from the host community are also targeted to benefit from the services of this project. This will give a total 12,176 individuals. 65% of the target will be IDPs and 35% host community.
The proposed response will provide improved access to integrated education and protection services. The education component will target 20 learning centres (10 schools, 4 secondary schools, 2 ALP, 1 CGS and 3 ECD) for a total 4,558 children (boys=2300, girls=2,258).

6 TLS (3 blocks of 2 classes each), 1 block in Tindoka Community Girls&apos; school, 1 in Ikpiro and 1 in Gbiaidie primary schools and 8 rehabilitated classrooms i.e., 4 classrooms in Ikpiro, 2 classrooms in Tindoka, 2 classrooms in Alpha and Omega primary schools to provide access to 350 boys and 350 girls to safe and protective learning environment. Learning, teaching and recreational materials and COVID 19 and WASH supplies. Construct 6 blocks of 2 stance latrines in 3 schools. 2 blocks of 2 stances each in Gbiaidie Nursery and primary School, 2 blocks of 2 stances each in Tindoka primary school, 1 block of 2 stances each at Alpha and Omega primary school, 1 block of 2 stances each at Tindoka CGS. A total of 5000 individuals will benefit from the education response.

The protection cluster response will address GBV and Child protection concerns and protect women and girls, men and boys from abuses targeting 7,176 individuals. The GBV response will establish Women and Girls&apos; Friendly Space to deliver case management, PSS, community awareness, and distribution of dignity kits to a total of 1896 individuals. The child protection will establish one CFS and provide mental health and PSS, comprehensive case management, Identification, documentation and tracing of unaccompanied and separated children, establish and capacity build community-based child protection structures to prevent and respond to child protection. It will reach a total of 5,280 individuals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adventist Development and Relief Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adventist Development and Relief Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Mwanza</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211924330044</telephone>
   <email>cd@adrasouthsudan.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eseza Balyage</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211926625009</telephone>
   <email>financedir@adrasouthsudan.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Namana Simon</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director for Programs and Planning</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211928124613</telephone>
   <email>programsdir@adrasouthsudan.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU24">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Western Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.34717990 28.29943500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="65" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="35" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-11-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-23">117500.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-23">342284.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-20244">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-23">459785.45</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adventist Development and Relief Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
