<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-21/HSS10/SA1/P/INGO/19458</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelope 2: Scale up of Child Protection services to IDP communities in Bor South .</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is to ensure that children caught up in forced displacement in 5 IDP camps including the Ex PoC in Bor South, are supported through specialized child protection services that meet the needs of vulnerable children and at-risk children, through the establishment and strengthening of Child Protection systems, individual support through case management services and mental health and psychosocial support (MHPSS), awareness-raising, capacity building and monitoring and reporting. The project will directly benefit 2400 programme recipients in the Bor South Ex PoC, and 2000 indirect beneficiaries among host communities and from other IDP camps mainly through non-focused MHPSS, case management, Child Protection system strengthening community-based approaches such as awareness raising on key child protection concerns in the community, child protection prevention messaging and child help desks.

Outcome 1, reaching 1000 girls and boys, will focus on addressing the psychosocial needs of children experiencing the negative effects of protracted displacement and conflict through providing MHPSS support. Child-Friendly Spaces (CFS) will be set up in the camps, with recreational activities and play areas. Messages on MHPSS will be included in all Child Protection message dissemination to the community on prevention of and response to the various risks and concerns affecting children in the IDP settlements. 

Outcome 2 , aims to reach 450 vulnerable girls and boys from 5 IDP camps through individual support to ensure that children with various vulnerabilities which include children associated with armed forces or armed groups (CAAFAG), and unaccompanied and separated children (UASC), will be supported through comprehensive case management services, from assessment of cases, implementation of appropriate case plans and follow up.

Outcome 3 will build and strengthen a community-based child protection system by establishing functional community-based Child Protection networks, design of Child Protection messages using IEC material and disseminated through child help desks and awareness-raising campaigns to create a safe and protective environment for children in the IDP camps. This outcome will reach 2400 community members in IDP communities

Outcome 4 will focus on quality programing and capacity building ensuring that all the child protection interventions are relevant, effective, efficient and reflect the quality benchmarks according to global standards. This will be achieved through focused capacity-building initiatives such as training frontline staff and teachers on child protection in emergencies (CPIE), Comprehensive Case Management and child protection management information system (CPIMS+) among others to improve the knowledge and skills of all frontline staff for quality program delivery for the benefit of the children. This outcome will reach 160 staff and community structures. 

This project will provide a multi-sectoral response through solid collaboration with existing projects. Save the Children and partners are implementing projects in the same locations, including nutrition, education and food security livelihood (FSL) programming, ensuring a spectrum of services are being provided to vulnerable populations in the ex-POC and other IDP sites.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Alshamaa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PDQ Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211920874008</telephone>
   <email>Mohammed.Alshamaa@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natalie Emery</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211920874004</telephone>
   <email>Natalie.Emery@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jesca Driciru</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Protection Technical Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 920 874007</telephone>
   <email>jesca.driciru@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-11">99718.53</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-11">200261.18</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-19458">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-11">299979.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
