<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-21/HSS10/SA1/H/INGO/19691</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of comprehensive and integrated primary health care services to conflict-affected IDPs in Wau and sustaining Covid-19 case management capacity of Juba IDU..(USE THIS )</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The protracted  armed conflict and limited Government investment have had a devastating impact on South Sudan&#x2019;s infrastructure and basic service delivery. Health facilities are poorly equipped and having limited staffed with only one physician for every 65,574 people in the country . According to WHO health facility functionality, out of approximately 2,300 health facilities, more than 1,300 are non-functional and up to 57% of those functional facilities, are supported by humanitarian and development partners. The situation is even worse for IDPs and returnees who lives mostly in settlements further than 5 km from a functional health facility. In addition, A third of IDPs and returnees live in communities where women and girls avoid certain areas due to fear for their safety  which limit their access to basic health services outside IDP settlements. 

Wau POC was transitioned to Internally Displaced Camp in November 2020 and according to the CCM head count conducted in March 2021, 11, 681 individuals were sheltering at the camp. This includes 8,603 IDPs and 3,078 host communities. 
Wau is also one of the 9 counties which suffered from Measles outbreak in 2020, which, as stated in the 2021 Humanitarian Needs Overview, the current general situation in the country will further aggravate the health situation, the spread of existing outbreaks and the likelihood of new outbreaks this year. Like in other IDP camps, children were acutely malnourished than in the past three years and women and girls continued to face extreme levels of gender-based violence and psychosocial distress. In addition, Acute Respiratory Tract Infection, Malaria and Acute Watery Diarrhea remain main cause of Outpatient consultations in Naivasha IDP site, according to IDSR data. Moreover, the COVID-19 pandemic poses enormous risks to children, women, girls, families and communities including mental health and psychosocial distress. Thus, the critical need to sustain access to health services for IDPs particularly vulnerable children, women and people with disability. 

Despite the health need for Wau/Naivasha IDPs, there is only one Reproductive Health facility supported by IMC within the site. This facility only provides reproductive health package while the rest of primary health services were provided by a Primary Health Care Center operated by IOM outside the camp which will be closed from August 2021 leaving the IDPs without access to basic health services. 

As part of continued efforts to improve access to life-saving health care, IMC aims to provide a comprehensive and integrated package of primary health care services in Wau/Naivasha IDP site. IMC&#x2019;s main strategy is to deliverer essential health services that is complemented by regular community outreaches to increase and expand equitable coverage and access to vulnerable and displaced population within Wau IDP camp. The project will provide outpatient consultations to at least 95 % of IDP populations with 2 consultations projected a year, 95% of children aging less than 1year are targeted to benefit to EPI program among other services, Mental Health consultations will be provided to at least 1% of the population while PSS participation is targeting 8% of the population. Additionally, 10% of Host community are targeted to benefit from this project. 

As of As of July 30, 2021, South Sudan has had 11,063 cases of COVID-19 and 119 deaths distributed in two waves: one around May-June 2020 and another around February-March 2021 . 
IMC UK will provide support to the Juba Infectious Disease Unit (IDU) with the management of COVID-19 cases and support 720 beneficiaries with COVID-19 critical care for patients and training of health care staff.

Interventions at both Wau IDP camp and Juba IDU will also support a total of 12,401 individuals and their families with PSS services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD21-HEA-175680-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tom Mcnelly</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0927-000-414</telephone>
   <email>Tmcnelly@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.61440630 31.26263660</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Western Bahr el Ghazal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.64523990 25.28375850</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-14">332417.58</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-14">667582.42</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-19691">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-14">1000000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305195699">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-22">400000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
