<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-21/HSS10/SA1/WASH/INGO/19709</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelope 1: Improving access to lifesaving water, sanitation and hygiene services in vulnerable communities in IPC 4 and 5 and in areas categorized as WASH severity level 4 and 5 in Ayod and Fangak counties by emergency response team (EPR) based in Juba.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project targets Ayod and Fangak counties in Jonglei State. These locations are classified at IPC 4 and 5 and have been affected by unprecedented flooding that displaced the populations to the higher grounds, damaged the already limited water and sanitation facilities, crops, and houses. Medair had conducted a multi-sectoral needs assessment in Ayod (Ayod town, Mogok, and Pagil) in June 2021. The assessment report highlighted a proxy GAM rate of 14.7% and a proxy SAM rate of 2.5%, among children 6-59 months indicating a serious to critical nutrition situation. The community is also experiencing emergency level WASH services gap 30% of the population are collecting their drinking water from surface water, 35% from rainwater, 9% from unprotected wells, and 17% from handpumps. Flooding in Ayod County, Jonglei, displaced about 31,000 people to Ayod town. 

The current flooding in Fangak County dates back from July 2020 due to heavy rains that raised the water level of the Phow river. The heavy rains resulted in both pluvial and fluvial flooding in the greater Fangak county. The early start of this year&#x2019;s rain has worsened the already dire situation especially in Old Fangak where most villages have been submerged and dikes are collapsing leaving the people of Old Fangak at the mercy of the water. 
These counties are prioritized by SSHF 1st Standard Allocation and WASH Cluster. However, the project also aims to respond to other locations should an emergency alert arise that meets the triggers of WASH EPampR. In such circumstances, Medair will seek approval for the intervention from OCHA in consultation with WASH Cluster. 

This project provides access to safe water, safe and gender-segregated sanitation, and hygiene services to 42,200 most vulnerable people in Ayod (27,400) and Fangak (14,800) counties. In Ayod, Medair plans to support five nutrition sites through provision of famine prevention packages to 1,187 children classified as SAM/MAM and caregiver families, providing access to safe water through rehabilitating five broken handpumps in and/or around the nutrition sites, constructing ten toilet stances, and training nutrition staff on key hygiene behavior. Medair also supports both Ayod and Fangak communities through integrated WASH services. Medair plans to rehabilitate 30 boreholes (20 in Ayod and 10 in Fangak), distribute famine prevention packages including household water treatment chemicals and water containers to 4,000 most vulnerable households (3,000 in Ayod and 1,000 in Fangak), and reach 32,000 individuals (20,000 in Ayod and 12,000 in Fangak) through hygiene promotion. During famine prevention package distributions, Medair trains the community members and conducts demonstrations of the proper use of the items. The distribution sites will be selected in consultation with women, children, and persons with disabilities and Medair aims to conduct the distributions at central locations. 

Protection assessment results feed into safety audits that identify and mitigate concerns before responses. Medair&#x2019;s Senior Protection Officer will be involved throughout the planning and implementation of interventions to help identify protection concerns. In cases of significant concerns, Medair will engage with protection partners. Medair teams have received protection training and will train enumerators on protection mainstreaming Principles. Medair will utilise PDM and exit surveys to measure quality and impact of Medair response</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDAIR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDAIR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD21-WSH-176417-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anke Meiburg</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 924 143 746</telephone>
   <email>cd-southsudan@medair.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ruth Summerfield</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Funding Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 917 787 196</telephone>
   <email>funding-southsudan@medair.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sintayehu Legesse</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wash Advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 924 751 402</telephone>
   <email>washadvisor-sds@medair.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-05">184615.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-09"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-05">415384.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-19709">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-05">600000.49</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDAIR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
