<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-21/HSS10/SA1/P-CCCM/UN/19728</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENVELOPE 1 Protection and CCCM response in food insecure areas in South Sudan in Jonglei State (Pibor, Akobo, Ayod, Fangak) and Upper Nile (Nasir and Ulang)
ENVELOPE 2: CCCM response in Central Equatoria State (Mangala)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project seeks to provide a coordinated protection and CCCM response to internally displaced persons, returnees and vulnerable host communities in the following locations in South Sudan: Jonglei State (Pibor, Akobo, Ayod, Fangak), Upper Nile (Nasir and Ulang) and Central Equatoria (Mangala).

These locations are among those prioritized by the South Sudan Humanitarian Fund (First Standard Allocation 2021) and for implementation by UNHCR. These locations face an ever-worsening humanitarian situation due to intercommunal violence, floods, severe food insecurity, disruption of markets and agricultural activities aggravated by the COVID 19 pandemic and ongoing economic crisis. 

According to the Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC), 7.24 million people in South Sudan are likely to be in crisis-level acute food insecurity by July 2021. The situation has affected the most vulnerable IDPs, returnees and host communities in targeting counties, exposing them to heightened risks to their physical safety, increased exposure to violence including rampant sexual and gender-based violence, sexual exploitation and abuse, waterborne diseases, acute food shortages compounded by worsening environmental conditions. Floods have for instance destroyed crops, public infrastructure such as health care centres, schools, shelters, and road access. Extended, even low intensity conflict affects access, crops and livestock production, freedom of movement, communal and household safety nets, further limiting community capacity to cope with continued crisis situation and displacement, to feed themselves, and to care for their families and the more vulnerable members of the communities. These and many other factors have left the communities vulnerable, and it is worse with those with specific needs such as persons with disability, women at risk, elderly at risk, children at risk among others,  who continue to face protection situation that requires immediate protection response. 

The project is designed to ensure robust community participation inclusive of all groups of IDPs and host communities to participate in the decision-making process on issues that affect their lives, including those intended to support greater self-reliance in targeted locations. 

In line with the HRP strategic objectives and priorities this project will deliver a general protection and CCCM response with the following core activities in the above-mentioned locations:

1. Provide general protection support and CCCM coordination and site management activities.
2. Conduct identification of  the most vulnerable persons including individuals with disabilities through vulnerability screening  and provide timely response including through  cash assistance and other individual protection assistance (IPA) based on needs and as part of case management and referrals.
3. Case Management, referrals for child protection, SGBV case, and legal cases among others. 
4. Strengthened community-based protection, community-site level governance structures, and feedback mechanisms including PSEA in all locations (IDP sites and host communities).
5. Coordinate/Conduct joint assessments, PSN vulnerability assessments, and site monitoring to understand the needs and capacities of the displaced and host communities, identify gaps and avoid overlaps.
6. Coordinate, support and provide needed information and communication to support a coordinated humanitarian response in displacement sites with the meaningful participation of the displaced and affected communities.

UNHCR plans to target 71,887 vulnerable persons (17,538 for protection response and 54,349 individuals in communities where CCCM activities will be implemented).

Activities will be built around establishing a coordinated response between CCCM and Protection partners, with joint protection and CCCM activities reinforcing community coordinate capacities, governance and protection networks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD21-CCM-176600-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD21-PRO-176588-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Carole Laleve</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 926 923 550</telephone>
   <email>laleve@unhcr.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kimberly Roberson</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior DIMA Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 924 584 004</telephone>
   <email>roberson@unhcr.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.61440630 31.26263660</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upper Nile</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.88942020 32.71813750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="54" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="46" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-10">216068.02</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-10">433921.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="FTR_SSD_2021_1000597">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">649989.74</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-19728">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-10">649989.74</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
