<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-21/HSS10/SA1/WASH/INGO/19464</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENVELOP 2: Support to people in 6 IDP settlement sites.

Emergency WASH intervention for conflict affected IDPs in Bor Ex PoC in Bor South County.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention aims to re-establish and improve access to WASH services for the conflict affected IDPs in Bor Ex PoC. Seeking durable and more sustainable and resilient WASH solution is paramount to providing lasting improved hygiene and sanitation situation in the Ex-PoC. Through this project, IAS will ensure that the IDPs have adequate, appropriate and acceptable WASH facilities to allow rapid, safe and secure access at all times. The IDP population together with the camp management and block leaders will become progressively responsible for the maintenance and operationalization of the facilities to promote local ownership aimed at enhancing sustainability of the WASH facilities. The IDP population and local leaders will be capacity built to become responsible and accountable for ensuring regular maintenance of the WASH facilities. It is anticipated that working with the community and involving them will lead them to take ownership of the WASH facilities. This community engagement approach will encourage every community member to be responsible for safe guarding of the WASH infrastructure e.g. tap stand monitoring, latrine cleaning, drainage cleaning, garbage collection and hygiene promotion to promote community ownership and participation.

Through the intervention 2310 people will be reached with safe clean water, sanitation and hygiene services through operation of the functional water points (borehole and mini water yards), construction of elevated and lined latrines share by 3 households each stance, desludging of the filled latrines, installation of hand washing facilities, establishment and training of water management committees including sanitation and hygiene promoters/ WASH volunteers, training and sensitizing the community on WASH GBV risk factors, training of girls and young women on menstrual hygiene management, distribution of Menstrual hygiene management kits, soap, wheel barrows and ibriks/kettles to promote good hygiene behaviors.
Better-designed WASH programming can help mitigate such GBV risks as girls and women are often disproportionally affected by WASH GBV issues that arise in camp settlement settings. IAS will work with relevant stakeholders towards mitigating the risks relating to sexual violence against women and girls in the EX PoC.

The key issues surrounding the Ex-PoC are poor WASH infrastructures and GBV which have impacted negatively on the hygiene status in the camp. The implementation of this planned intervention is expected to result into general sanitation and hygiene improvement, less water borne diseases and reduction in sexual violence in a long term manner. Sufficient water and sanitation facilities will enable the IDPs to practice good hygiene behaviors. IAS commits to conform to the WASH strategy on IDP/Ex PoCs /WASH transition plan and will work towards achieving the set WASH targets and indicators.

IAS is also determined to provide a well-coordinated, effective and cost-efficient logistics system for the response aimed to save lives by ensuring a strong supply chains for the intervention to boost access and support the vulnerable IDPs in the EX-PoC. The Organization already has well oriented and skilled staff with in-depth experience in sanitation in crowded contexts besides the the trained hygiene promoters previously engaged in implementation of activities in the PoC. This is aimed at improving community ownership for excreta management and domestic waste management systems in the IDP site to facilitate improved health and enhanced ownership and sustainability of the WASH infrastructure. By the end of the implementation period the IDP community should be able to maintain their their latrines and garbage disposal pits.

However, activities such as water distribution network and desludging activities require skills and knowledge, hence may require the continued support of IAS until a sustainable long-term plan is developed where each household has its own latrine.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Aid Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Aid Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD21-WSH-176037-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DAIDA isaac</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>?+211924505378</telephone>
   <email>daida.isaac@lakarmissionen.se</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chandiga Godfrey Moggas</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211925 775 833</telephone>
   <email>godfrey.chandiga@ias-intl.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zaitun Rogota</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 927 629 664</telephone>
   <email>zaitun.rogota@ias-intl.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-24">145038.75</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-24">254117.47</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-19464">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-24">399156.22</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Aid Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305224502">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-08">159662.49</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Aid Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305540123">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-28">159662.49</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Aid Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
