<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-21/HSS10/SA1/N-P/INGO/19689</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Integrated Emergency Lifesaving Nutrition and Gender- Based Violence Response to conflict-affected population in Malakal PoC and Canal Pigi Counties South Sudan(Use This)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through this proposed project, International Medical Corps (IMC-UK) will provide emergency nutrition services to the conflict-affected, internally displaced people (IDPs) and the host populations in Malakal POC  and Canal Pigi (Jonglei State) county.  The proposed nutrition response will focus on treatment and prevention of acute malnutrition among children (boys and girls) aged 0-59 month, pregnant and lactating women with acute malnutrition through management of severe acute malnutrition (SAM) and moderate acute malnutrition (MAM), in nutrition facilities/sites and provision of support to a Maternal-Infant Young Child Nutrition (MIYCN) focusing more on the first 1000 days, of a child&apos;s life. The proposed SSHF funding will be for 12 months&#x2019; period. Hence, this project will enable to expand the response into Canal/Pigi County that has a very high level of global acute malnutrition (GAM) gt15%, already declared to be in Emergency (IPC Phase 4) acute food insecurity in May-August 2021, the situation can deteriorate further if humanitarian interventions are not continued timely. This project further will compliment and strengthen IMCs&#x2019; ongoing interventions, funded by UNICEF and WFP, in static nutrition sites as well as will support outreach nutrition services.

Through this project, IMC UK will reach 24,381 (6,289 children under five, 3,270 girls, 3,020 boys, 128 men and,17,963 Women) beneficiaries, specifically women and children in Malakal and Canal Pigi Counties.   The project will provide frontline lifesaving nutrition services which will focus on the most vulnerable, especially women and children under five. CMAM program will be implemented across 13 OTPs, 1 SC and 13 TSFP sites in 2 Counties. IMC  currently has an active Program Cooperation Agreement (PCA) with UNICEF and Field level agreement (FLA) with WFP through which consistent flow of nutrition supplies for SAM and MAM is ensured. The project is designed in a way that the nutrition activities will be integrated with the Protection/GBV, WASH, and health activities through close coordination and joint programming with other Partners for a more holistic approach and greater impact. In addition, IMC will continuously monitor the nutrition status of the population and the nutrition response through the routine collection and analysis of nutrition program data, mass Mid upper arm circumference (MUAC) screening and periodic SMART surveys funded by other donors.

In Canal Pigi County, in line with the three GBV Cluster Objectives (CO), IMC UK, will also provide integrated lifesaving GBV prevention and response services to supplement the already established BHA and FCDO projects in Malakal and Pigi/Canal . IMC  through this project will build capacity of IMC staff and local communities, enhance community engagement and sensitization,provide  survivor-centered case management and psychosocial support, establish/strengthen  Women and Girls Safe Spaces (WGSSs) programming, provide dignity kits and material support, integrate GBV risk mitigation and survivor support services across the project sites establish and / or strengthen GBV referral systems, provide legal aid  counselling through referrals pathways, , develop and deliver integrated nutrition and GBV messages, incorporate basic GBV messages into nutrition-related community outreach and awareness-raising activities. provide nutritional assistance to GBV survivors receiving medical support in the Clinics, IMC will roll out of safety audits in all project locations ,provide IYCF counseling sessions to GBV survivors, establish community-based complaints mechanisms (CBCM) at project sites. In addition, IMC will continuously assess the physical safety of and access to service delivery points to identify associated risks of GBV. An estimated 13,250 vulnerable women and girls across Malakal (7,000)  and Canal/Pigi (6,250) will benefit from this project over a period of 12 months.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD21-NUT-176523-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD21-PRO-176486-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anwar Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Country Director - Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211927000112</telephone>
   <email>anwarali@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dugsiye Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211927000124</telephone>
   <email>dugsiye@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joanna Chwastek</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants and Reporting Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211927000622</telephone>
   <email>jchwastek@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upper Nile</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.88942020 32.71813750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">389396.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">782010.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-19689">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">1171407</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
