<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-21/HSS10/RA1/P-WASH/INGO/20238</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated, flood response for equitable, safe and dignified access to Protection and WASH services, for flood affected population in Maiwut County, Upper Nile State, South Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International (RI), in partnership with local NGO, Community Action Organization (C.A.O), proposes a multi-sectoral, comprehensive response to address the needs of the most vulnerable populations in Maiwut county, Upper Nile State. The proposed project addresses Protection and WASH needs and proposes to reduce morbidity and mortality of 50,000 (12,500 men, 17500 women, 7500 boys and 12,500 girls) targeted beneficiaries by facilitating equitable, safe and dignified access to critical emergency services. Activities such as distribution of items and training will target specific selected groups who will also benefit from the awareness raising activities carried out in the following Payams Maiwut centre Payam, Wunkir Payam , Uleng Payam, Kigile Payam and Turu Payam. 

To address the protection needs of community in Maiwut county, RI amp CAO will implement protection activities including 
General Protection: Prevention of and response to risk and of violation of rights of floods affected population including returnees and IDPs through strengthening community legal/justice structures solving grievances including strengthening community based protection committees and paying specific consideration to vulnerable women, girls boys, and men as well as other potentially vulnerable populations subset including persons with disabilities, elderly persons as identified in IRNA report. Conduct regular post floods protection monitoring to assess the situation and support affected population in establishing linkage with available services and building the local capacity
Child Protection: RI and CAO will Prevent and respond to risks of violence, abuse and exploitation of vulnerable girls, boys and women in the area of displacement. Identifying and assisting separated and unaccompanied children
Training of the CAO and RI staff on Caring for child survivor to ensure that age appropriate services are offered to people in need
Protection GBV: Provision of multi-sectoral services for prevention and response to GBV including PSS and counseling, survivor center case management, health, reproductive health services, legal and linkage to livelihoods programs, shelter and WASH. Establish referral pathways and coordinate with other service providers.
Protection mainstreaming: RI will ensure protection mainstreaming across all sectors and partner, giving respects to human rights and in cooperating protection principles of meaningful access and DO No Harm  and accountability to the affected population as part of RI intervention. Multi sectoral GBV safety audits will be done and translating recommendations into actions as well as capacity building for frontline staff on GBV topics.

RI&#x2019;s emergency WASH component will contribute to improved health and hygiene status of beneficiaries through timely and equitable access to safe, potable and adequate water in targeted communities in Maiwut county. Since women and girls are the primary users of WASH services, the intervention is designed to be gender-sensitive and prevent GBV. The integrated approach will address the high levels of malnutrition by targeting the families of SAM and MAM children for WASH interventions and providing access to drinking water, thereby acknowledging that poor WASH services are a key driver of poor health and malnutrition. Activities will include the  rehabilitation of water points (boreholes) with secure location and access, household latrine construction, WASH NFI distribution, and the training of Water Users Committees (WUCs) and pump mechanics.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid Organization (CAO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-09" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beatrix Masime</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0922590600</telephone>
   <email>beatrix.masime@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daniel Nyabera</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0925895431</telephone>
   <email>daniel.nyabera@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deka Islan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0924683315</telephone>
   <email>deka.islan@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samuel Collis</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0922562172</telephone>
   <email>samuel.collis@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upper Nile</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.88942020 32.71813750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="34.8" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="65.2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-11-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-30">108508.26</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-30">340418.07</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-20238">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-30">448926.33</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
