<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-21/HSS10/SA1/P/INGO/19763</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of integrated protection services for vulnerable populations with and without disabilities in Pibor, Aweil South, Bentiu POC, Mangala and Juba IDP site.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will provide general protection and disability Inclusion mainstreaming interventions through targeted assistance to persons with and without disabilities. This will be through individual protection assistance (IPA) including assistive devices, safe referrals, capacity building on disability mainstreaming to protection actors, OPD engagement and awareness raising activities. The child protection component will in addition to the above include, Mental health and psycho-social support (MHPSS) for children and their care givers and establishment of referral pathways in Aweil South. Disability inclusion capacity building services for protection, will be conducted to ensure that persons with disability can access these much needed services.

The project target populations include, people displaced through conflict, floods and Covid-19 affected vulnerable groups with and without disabilities so they can safely and with dignity access their most fundamental rights and entitlements. This will be done through the provision of individual protection assistance, including, identification, assessments, referrals and provision of MHPSS and physical rehabilitation services to persons with heightened vulnerabilities, to ensure that they are able to access assistance and services. Crucially, the project will build capacity of protection emergency responders with the intent to influence policies, practices, attitudes and decisions aimed at creating an enabling environment to support for inclusion of persons with disabilities and elderly. Key activities will include, protection reporting, of the situation affecting the elderly and people with disabilities in IDPs, host community and return areas, as well as monitoring for violations of rights to contribute to preventing, reducing and mitigating serious protection threats for the vulnerable populations in Pibor, Aweil South, Bentiu, Mangala and Juba IDP sites. 

The project will also support the wider emergency responders in disability Mainstreaming capacity building that will contribute to the achievement of the Inter-Agency Standing Committee (IASC) guidelines on Inclusion of persons with disabilities in humanitarian action and in line with the IASC principal statement on the centrality of protection and the United Nations Disability Inclusion Strategy. HI will strengthen community based protection by working with communities to identify threats and risks in locations of operations, and &#x2013; in collaboration with the community &#x2013; shall devise strategies to address identified risks in a manner that is protective and Inclusive of all persons, including women and children. HI will also work with organizations of persons with disabilities and their associations to ensure they are able to assist and advocate for other persons with disabilities in their area of influence. Service delivery through both static and mobile protection (including MHPSS, physical rehabilitation) and disability inclusion teams. The mobile team will provide services to fixed locations including PHCUs/PHCCs hence the project will work closely with the humanitarian health partner(s) on the ground to ensure sustainability, complementarity, high coverage, avoid duplication of efforts and strengthen establishment of a clear referral pathway for identified cases and capacity building</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Armogast Mwasi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 916 084 984</telephone>
   <email>a.mwasi@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deborah Siango</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operations Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 912 101 341</telephone>
   <email>d.siango@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fidelis Musyoka</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 911 734 861</telephone>
   <email>f.musyoka@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.61440630 31.26263660</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Bahr el Ghazal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.53604490 26.79678490</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-31">249313.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-31">500686.89</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-19763">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-31">750000.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
