<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://clerdworld.org/2019/02/27/q-1-narrative-report/" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-54522-P-BUT-Q.4-REPORT</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-54522" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Legal Research and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q.4 PROGRESS REPORT</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CLERD continued the implementation of activities under the P-BUT project during this quarter. Two major activities were carried out: The monitoring visit and the evaluation workshop. The monitoring visit had a total 188 budget monitors while the Evaluation workshop had 116 participants who were drawn from the CSOs and MDAs that participated in the first training workshop on budget process, monitoring, tracking implementation, evaluation and advocacy. The first Monitoring visit, which took place in five of the six project locations, was part of the processes leading to accountability in budget implementation and results of the projects identified in various states, and the state of completion vis-a vis funds released for each project. The evaluation workshop carried out in three of the six project states, was to evaluate the findings from the monitoring visits, draw conclusion on the budget implementation and undertake advocacy visit to the policy makers on the outcome of the monitoring visits to project locations in the targeted sectors. We monitored a total of 70 projects across the project locations of different sectors of the economy like: Agriculture, Health, Education, Road and Housing, Women Affairs, Poverty and Rural Development etc. with potentials for positive impact in the lives of the people. Across the three states, advocacy visits were carried out to 17 policy makers of the aforementioned sectors on the outcome of the monitoring visits. The participating CSOs/representatives earlier trained on the budget process had their capacities built on the use of the monitoring tool for the exercise and understanding of indicators for evaluating budget performance. Many of the participants acknowledged that the monitoring exercise and evaluation workshop was a welcome development because it afforded them the opportunity to have a good understanding on the essence of having projects monitored and the need for citizens to engage the government more on the implementation of projects in their respective states.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000001767" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">State of Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The implementation of P-BUT continued this quarter starting from June 1, 2019 to September 30, 2019.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The State of Netherlands gave a grant to Centre for Legal Research and Development, an NGO registered in Nigeria.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15111" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2018-09-26">50494606</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="P-BUT-Q.4-REPORT">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-08-31">8048967.29</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The value amount was what was spent on project activities during quarter four.</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000001767" ref="State of Netherlands" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The State of Netherlands gave a grant to Centre for Legal Research and Development to implement the P-BUT project.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="P-BUT-Q.4-REPORT" ref="Centre for Legal Research and Development" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Legal Research and Development received a grant from State of Netherlands to implement the P-BUT project.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://clerdworld.org/2019/10/04/promoting-budget-transparency-in-nigeria-p-but/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The attached documents are Annual Narrative Progress Report for YR.1 and its Appendix.</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-09-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://clerdworld.org/2019/10/04/promoting-budget...-nigeria-p-but-2/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Appendix to the Annual Narrative Report -YR.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
