<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-18/3481/RA5/ESNFI/INGO/11280</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of cash for emergency shelter and cash for winterization to affected populations in FerozKoh</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The  need  for  shelter is highlighted  as  one  of  the  top  priorities  for  the  populations affected by drought such as IDPs, across  all  needs  assessments conducted by the partner in the western region. The affected population are in immediate need of emergency shelter assistance and winterization items before the end of 2018. These  families  will  continue  to  live  in  makeshift  shelters  and  are  exposed  to  protection  and health  risks  including  harsh  winter  conditions.

Afghanaid&#x2019;s recent verification assessment  of  approximately 780 IDPs households in Ghor, indicates  that  50% of the IDPs live in makeshift  shelter conditions that do not protect them  from  the external elements  nor  provide  privacy  and  dignity. The  shelter  need is extremely  high  amongst the people displaced by drought as  the  majority  live  in unprotected under-construction buildings and shops of  which 58% are  children. No local solutions could be found and the major challenge is that the majority of displaced population reside in private shops and buildings without permission. Based on the ground needs we propose the shelter needs to be compounded with the urgent need for winterization in Ghor. The laidback government response has increased the urgency for already stretched and burdened NGOs and INGOs to provide winterization items, food, shelter and health care to affected IDPs. 

In response to this impending crisis, Afghanaid proposes to provide assistance to 780 drought-affected IDPs (households) in FerozKoh. The assistance shall include the emergency winterization cash assistance of $100 to 780 IDP households. Therefore, for winterization all 780 IDP households will be targeted and the 390 most vulnerable of them will be selected after assessment who would be provided cash for rent as emergency shelter assistance, will also receive $75 per month for rent for three months. The transfers will be via local Saraf , also Afghanaid will establish distribution committees at the target sites for secure distribution. Both parties will cross-check the profiles of the IDPs and the amount prior to the transfer to the beneficiaries.

The emergency cash assistance will allow each beneficiaries to buy winterization items, and bear shelter costs. This vital assistance will help ward off discomfort and infirmity in the winter, giving protection and dignity. 

ANDMA and MoRR has assisted Afghanaid in identification of the beneficiaries in FerozKoh. Afghanaid is aware that the IDPs are not at single location and they move their destination time to time to search for cheaper and warmer places for living. Afghanaid will assist them without discrimination and have already verified their presence in the area.

Afghanaid has selected 780 IDP households based on vulnerability criteria such as households headed by women, widows, children, disabled, chronically ill and families with many children. These displacements are considered the most vulnerable as they did not receive the emergency shelter assistance from any agencies yet.

Afghanaid has extensive experience in cash programming, including previous projects using the M-PAISA and M-HAWALA systems to transfer emergency cash assistance to affected populations and returnees in Samangan and Nangarhar. We have also used smart card for transferring WFP food packages to beneficiaries in FerozKoh.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-25" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ayub Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Director of Finance</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093773333112</telephone>
   <email>akhan@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Najibullah Namiq</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Management and Partnership Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0799733944</telephone>
   <email>najeebullah@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.09957760 64.90595500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-12-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-07">28835.27</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-07">207253.49</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-11280">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-07">236088.76</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303741476">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-21">141653.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303895960">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-29">94435.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
