<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-18/3481/SA1/WASH-ESNFI-CPiE/INGO/7694</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of multi-sector assistance (WaSH, Shelter and Protection) to the vulnerable population of Kunduz Province.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kunduz province ranges among the hardest to reach areas in Afghanistan, with many districts remaining in the front line of the conflict opposing AOGs and governmental forces. The province saw another significant peak in AOGs&#x2019; activity beginning of May 2017, followed by a counter military action by governmental forces, leading to major population flows expected to continue in 2018. On the other hand, the overall assistance received in 2017 reveals a significant gap between the caseload and the number of people assisted.
According to a household survey conducted by SI in December 2017 in Emamsahib and Kunduz districts, major WaSH, Shelter and Protection needs and gaps remain: nearly half of the surveyed population (46%) is using water from unprotected sources with insufficient average daily water consumption, WaSH infrastructure in institutions often can&#x2019;t cope with new population influx, and the diarrhea incidence among children under five stands at 28%. Besides, 29% of HHs have reported their house to be destroyed during the conflict, and 89% of IDPs are residing in rented houses with an average monthly cost of 2,193 AFG. Moreover, 14% of HHs demonstrate more than two HEAT vulnerability criteria, putting them at higher risk of resorting to negative coping strategies and exposing them to protection concerns. 
SOLIDARITES INTERNATIONAL&#x2019;s present project has thus been designed as an integrated WaSH, ES/NFI and Protection assistance project, in Emamsahib and Kunduz districts (Kunduz province). Through cluster approved standard activities and in line with the 2018-2021 HRP&#x2019;s objectives, 17,560 individuals will be assisted, among which 57% of IDPs, 39% of host communities and 4% of returnees. Female, male, boys and girls will constitute respectively 17%, 17%, 33% and 33% of the beneficiaries. The targeting of beneficiaries has prioritized villages with a significant number of IDPs displaced during the last six months, also taking into consideration other partners&#x2019; coverage, to avoid overlaps. Secondly, a detailed household and technical survey has been carried out, using the cluster approved HEAT (Household Emergency Assessment Tool), to identify needs and prioritize the most vulnerable IDPs. 
WaSH activities will include the construction/rehabilitation of boreholes in villages, the construction of solar powered water systems in selected schools, the construction of gender sensitive latrines in villages, and targeted hygiene promotion activities designed to reach all segments of the targeted population. In-kind emergency shelter and upgrading of shelter through cash will also be provided, engaging community labor in the reconstruction work to foster dignity and involvement. Basic NFIs will also be distributed to vulnerable households. Protection concerns will be mainstreamed throughout the activities, to ensure an equal access to the assistance provided and to prevent any harm form being done. Specific protection needs of children, will also be addressed through awareness raising sessions at community level, set-up of community-ran Child-friendly spaces providing psychosocial support, and referral and follow-up mechanism, completed by a cash assistance when necessary, for the most vulnerable children requiring special assistance from dedicated actors. Finally, SI will participate to emergency preparedness among the humanitarian actors through pre-positioning of ESNFI stocks in Kunduz center.
The proposed action will thus ensure the timely assistance of affected community and contribute to life saving effort through an integrated multi-sector approach, while ensuring coordination among partners working in the area. Due consideration has been and will be given to gender, disability and environment during all phases of the project cycle, to ensure the needs of most vulnerable individuals are adequately taken into consideration, and no harm is inflicted through the intervention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarites International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarites International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jean-Philippe Barroy</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>079930363</telephone>
   <email>afg.cdm@solidarites-afghanistan.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cristina Thevenot</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Desk Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+33 17 62 18 640</telephone>
   <email>cthevenot@solidarites.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kunduz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.85993070 68.71549750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="44" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="9" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="47" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-02-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-08-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-21">611863.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-7694">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-21">611863.33</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarites International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303197703">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-26">367118</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarites International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303798071">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-28">102825.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarites International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
