<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=SDN/15/51/UND" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105682-7535-2016-SDN105</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RECOVERY OF LIVELIHOODS OF VULNERABLE FARMING AND PASTORAL COMMUNITIES IN DARFUR</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving crop and livestock production through enhancing availability and access to water and diversification of livelihoods has been prioritized by the Darfur Joint Assessment Mission in 2012. The key themes, outputs and activities proposed by the Agriculture, Livestock and Rural Livelihoods Thematic Working Group for Pillar III were based on a strategic framework for &#x201C;natural resources management for food and nutrition security in Darfur&#x201D; prepared by the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) in January 2012. In response to the urgent needs of the people in Darfur where agriculture and livestock based livelihood interventions receive the highest priority, FAO in collaboration with UNOPS and ILO, received funding to implement the joint project &#x201C;Recovery of Livelihoods of Vulnerable Farming and Pastoral Communities in Darfur&#x201D; . The main outcome of the project is to improve the food and nutrition security of 288,000 conflict affected farmers and nomads by supporting their agriculture and livestock based livelihoods through enhancing access to sustainable water, certified seeds, veterinary and livestock services and inputs, and agribusiness skills; and by promotion of community natural resources management systems. Four million nine hundred and thirty thousand US dollars (4,930,000) were allocated to the project from the Qatar Fund which was provided to the United Nations Darfur Fund (UNDF) to deliver the following results: &#x2022; Construction and rehabilitation of 55 water facilities including 15 hafirs, 20 shallow wells and 20 surface dams; &#x2022; Improvement of crop production by supporting production of 1,850 metric tonnes of certified sorghum, millet, sesame and ground nut seeds; enhancing vegetable and legume production; &#x2022; Improvement of livestock health and production by enhancing access to veterinary and livestock inputs and services and protecting 200,000 animals against epidemic diseases; &#x2022; Diversification of livelihoods involving 700 farmers through development of agribusiness skills. The project falls under Economic Recovery Pillar III of the Darfur Development Strategy which aims to contribute positively towards poverty alleviation and transitioning Darfur to development. This will be achieved by improving crop and livestock production and productivity through the sustainable management of natural resources including land, water, forest resources and promotion of energy alternative sources. The project interventions come under the Foundational and Short-term Activities (FaST) which will serve as essential precursors or prerequisites to a much larger and longer development programme. The FaST activities will enhance the speed of transition from relief to development. The project will contribute to objective 5 of FaST activities &#x2018;Improved crop and livestock production and productivity&#x2019; and to objective 7 &#x2018;Improved value chains in livestock, agriculture and livelihoods development&#x2019;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SD">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="SD" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="SD" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">149755</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="SDN/15/51/UND-2016-SDN105 - Employment for young men and women promoted through entrepreneurship, cooperatives and social enterprises. IGAs and BDS development programmes-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-16">149755</value>
   <provider-org ref="XI-IATI-UNPF">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi Partner Trust Fund Office, UNDP</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="SDN/15/51/UND-2016-SDN105 - Employment for young men and women promoted through entrepreneurship, cooperatives and social enterprises. IGAs and BDS development programmes">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-16">149755</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=SDN/15/51/UND">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: RECOVERY OF LIVELIHOODS OF VULNERABLE FARMING AND PASTORAL COMMUNITIES IN DARFUR</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
