<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/14/53/IRL" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-104528-1138-2016-GLO153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WED-GLOBAL: Irish Aid-ILO Partnership Programme, Phase II, 2014-15</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The WED-EE phase II project will build on the achievements of the WEDEE Phase I and use the infrastructure and delivery mechanism as well as the new partnerships that were forged. The development objective of the project is more women-led businesses contribute to job creation, economic growth and gender equality. Phase II of WEDEE aims to serve at least 2,100 women entrepreneurs with business development services that should result in the creation at least 150 new businesses by women in Kenya, Tanzania and Uganda. At least 30% of the enterprises reached will be located in rural areas, and at least 30% of the women entrepreneurs served will be young women. The three outcomes of the project are: (a) women-led businesses increase their business perfomance, (b) selected policies and programmes are reviewed by policy makers to mainstream women&#x2019;s entrepreneurship development, and (c) selected ILO-WED tools and approaches are made available beyond the project&#x2019;s lifespan 3).The project combines country components with a global product and links to Outcome 3: Sustainable enterprises create productive and decent jobs, with the expected impact of &#x2018;more women-led businesses contribute to job creation, economic growth and gender equality&#x2019;. To achieve the objectives, the following outputs will be delivered: &#x2022; Non-financial service providers capacity to provide business services to women entrepreneurs is strengthened and accredited &#x2022; Financial service providers&#x2019; outreach to women entrepreneurs is increased &#x2022; WED-EE partners&#x2019; capacity is strengthened to link women entrepreneurs to national and regional markets &#x2022; Action plan on WED developed with constituents and other stakeholders based on WED Assessments &#x2022; WED-EE advocacy partners&#x2019; capacity strengthened to advocate and lobby for priority WED assessment recommendations. 3.1 National sustainability action plans are developed for replication of select ILO-WED tools and approaches. &#x2022; WED tools enhanced with videos and audio to support trainers and their outreach. &#x2022; Policy briefs for advocacy, formalization and men&#x2019;s involvement in WED initiatives are developed and shared with WED-EE constituents, partners and stakeholders. The key performance indicators for the 2-year phase will be: &#x2022; 2100 women entrepreneurs are trained by or linked to non-financial and financial service providers (30% of these will be young women and 30% from rural areas) &#x2022; 150 new businesses are created &#x2022; A representative sample of the women entrepreneurs served state having increased sales by 10% &#x2022; 600 of the women entrepreneurs served apply for financial products &#x2022; 60 trainers are certified as ILO-WED trainers &#x2022; National action plans on Women&#x2019;s Entrepreneurship Development are developed and agreed upon by multi-stakeholder groups in the three countries &#x2022; At least 3 Women Entrepreneur Associations&#x2019; in each of the three countries advocacy capacity is strengthened through capacity building At implementation level, the project will collaborate with other relevant ILO programmes in the countries, particularly the Youth Entrepreneurship Facility, Joint Programme on Gender Equality and UN Joint Programme on Population.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-03" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="GLOBAL" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.ilo.org/dashboard"></recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-08-03"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">60177</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="GLO/14/53/IRL-2016-GLO153 - &#xA0;Sustainable enterprises: a global product for crisis recovery, income and employment creation-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">60177</value>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-21-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ireland, Irish Aid</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="GLO/14/53/IRL-2016-GLO153 - &#xA0;Sustainable enterprises: a global product for crisis recovery, income and employment creation">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">60177</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/14/53/IRL">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: WED-GLOBAL: Irish Aid-ILO Partnership Programme, Phase II, 2014-15</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
