<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/15/19/UNF" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105290-1300-2016-GLO903</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LFS pilot studies to implement the recommendations of the resolution concerning statistics of work, employment and labour underutilization (19th ICLS, 2013)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Labour Market Information across different regions of the world are heavily based on data collected through household surveys, in particular Labour Force Surveys (LFS). These surveys use international standards agreed at the 13th International Conference of Labour Statisticians (ICLS) as their measurement basis. Due to various shortcomings in the data delivered to users under these standards a new set of standards was agreed at the 19th ICLS. This document outlines the activities to be undertaken by the ILO to follow up the implementation of Resolution I concerning statistics of work, employment and labour underutilization adopted by the 19th ICLS in 2013 and approved by the ILO Governing Body as an international standard in March 2014. Collaboration between the ILO and UN Foundation is proposed to support this work. The new standards create a framework which will allow the development of a wider range of labour market and work indicators. The standards have a critical gender dimension in so far as the creation of definitions for different forms of work will lead to improved understanding of women&#x2019;s participation in in work. The ultimate aim of the current project is to support the development of better evidence to inform labour market policy development. The ultimate beneficiaries will be Government and other users of labour market information. This will be achieved by providing guidance to countries on implementation of the standards agreed at the 19th ICLS through LFSs. The project involves the implementation of a series of experimental pilot studies. The aim behind these studies is to test different question sequences to see which provide the best basis for measurement in line with the new standards. The ILO has commenced preparatory work for the pilots and it is proposed implementation will commence in mid-2015. Phase 1 will run for 1 year with further work to be planned once the results from phase 1 have been assessed. The project will both directly build the capacity of the participant countries, but also provide the evidence to develop guidance which can be of benefit to all countries wishing to implement the new standards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="GLOBAL" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.ilo.org/dashboard"></recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">153916</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="GLO/15/19/UNF-2016-GLO903 - (2012-13): Enhancing the quality of statistics and the measurement of decent work-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">153916</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Fund for International Partnership</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="GLO/15/19/UNF-2016-GLO903 - (2012-13): Enhancing the quality of statistics and the measurement of decent work">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">153916</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/15/19/UNF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: LFS pilot studies to implement the recommendations of the resolution concerning statistics of work, employment and labour underutilization (19th ICLS, 2013)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
