<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=BIH/15/01/EUR" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105567-611570-2016-BIH128</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Local Employment Partnerships in Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The EU and other donors have invested significant funds in building the capacities of local stakeholders so that they can effectively address a wide range of local labour market needs. Now these capacities need to be put to use in an intervention that adopts a local economic development approach through supporting Local Employment Partnerships (LEPs). Partnerships can be an effective mechanism through which the relevance of local active labour market measures can be enhanced. This requires establishing a permanent dialogue among regional and local employment offices, education institutions (formal and non-formal), employers, trade unions, chambers of commerce, regional development agencies, regional and local governments, and civil society organizations, and provide all stakeholders with the abilities needed to jointly devise and implement strategies and plans in line with the needs of the economy. The overall objective of the Action is to contribute to the strategic development of Bosnia and Herzegovina&#x2019;s labour market. The specific objective is to foster sustainable, partnership-driven active labour market frameworks at the local level for an increased access to formal employment, particularly in flood-affected areas. The Action will be implemented in order to: &#x2022; Assess and strengthen the capacity of LEPs &#x2022; Ensure ensure that LEPs are deeply involved in the implementation and creation of human resource/employment and integrated development strategies. The Action will both, support local employment development initiatives as well build the institutional development of the implementing LEPs, so that they can act as the main drivers of the shift from a traditional, partially successful, model for defining and implementing active labour market policies and measures towards a flexible, local needs-based partnership-driven model. Key target groups are LEPs members, including local labour market stakeholders from public, private and civil society sectors (existing LEPs, unemployed, employed, business owners, regional and local PES, employer organisations, trade unions, chambers of commerce, regional development agencies, non-governmental organisations, formal and non-formal education providers, regional and local governments) in selected municipalities/towns. Final beneficiaries will be the the unemployed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="BA">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="BA" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="BA" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">191201</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="BIH/15/01/EUR-2016-BIH128 - Employment policies with an emphasis on equal opportunities are developed and implemented-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-02-01">191201</value>
   <provider-org ref="tbc">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delegation of the European Union to Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="BIH/15/01/EUR-2016-BIH128 - Employment policies with an emphasis on equal opportunities are developed and implemented">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-02-01">191201</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=BIH/15/01/EUR">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Support to Local Employment Partnerships in Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
