<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=PER/14/04/CAN" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105239-1061-2016-PER144</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated system for the identification and registration of Child Labour in Peru</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peru has set a target of reducing child labour, particularly its worst forms by ten percent by 2021, through the implementation of the National Strategy for the Prevention and Eradication of Child Labour (2012- 021). The Strategy prioritizes the generation of information and knowledge (Goal 6). This project contributes to the implementation of the National Strategy and the development of public policy for the eradication of child labour in Peru through the design and implementation of a system that will collect information at the local level on child labour disaggregated by gender, as well as, characterizing and identifying areas of employment. The system will provide the necessary data to identify, record, track and monitor child labour at the municipal level which national statistics do not give. It will also provide access to public institutions to a database contain the information which will contribute to improve the efficiency of services provided to children and adolescents in child labour, their families and communities and accelerate the country&apos;s progress towards elimination of this problem. The project follows the logic of the information systems that have been developed in other Latin America (Colombia, Chile and Ecuador). It will document existing good practices in order to incorporate lessons learnt. The system integrates three key components. The first, focuses on the identification of children and adolescents in child labour or at risk of involvement. Instruments (surveys and formularies) for identification will be designed and methodologies (definitions and manuals) standardize and systematize processes for identification. A second component focuses on the registration information collected to organize, systematize and provide the data required by institutions, especially public ones, to order provide services to children and adolescents child labourers or at risk of involvement. The systematization is done through the digitization of information designed and arranged for this purpose in a computerized database. A third component will design and implement a system of care for children and adolescents identified in child labour or risk of involvement. At least 200 public officials be trained in the use of the system and services will be provided by public institutions, at least 2,000 children and adolescents in child labour or at risk and their families will be identified and referred to public institutions for the provision of services. This project has a frame of reference the Regional Initiative Latin America and the Caribbean Free of Child Labour, in which the countries themselves have prioritized the development of systems for the identification, tracking and monitoring as one of six key areas where progress is needed in order to advance in the eradication of child labour. Development objective: To contribute to the prevention and elimination of child labor, especially in its worst forms and the protection of adolescents in legal working age. Specific objectives: SO 1: Design and implement an information and registration system for identifying, monitoring and providing care to children and adolescents involved in child labour. SO. 2: Strengthen the capacity of public and private stakeholders to implement the information and registration system aimed at children and adolescents involved in child labour. SO 3: Implement a pilot project for the identification and restoration of the rights of children and adolescents involved in child labour.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-17" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PE">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="PE" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peru</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="PE" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">112442</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="PER/14/04/CAN-2016-PER144 - Se habr&#xE1; fortalecido la articulaci&#xF3;n y coordinaci&#xF3;n entre Gobierno y actores sociales para la implementaci&#xF3;n de las pol&#xED;ticas y programas de prevenci&#xF3;n y protecci&#xF3;n contra formas inaceptables de trabajo-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">112442</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Canada, Employment and Social Development Canada</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="PER/14/04/CAN-2016-PER144 - Se habr&#xE1; fortalecido la articulaci&#xF3;n y coordinaci&#xF3;n entre Gobierno y actores sociales para la implementaci&#xF3;n de las pol&#xED;ticas y programas de prevenci&#xF3;n y protecci&#xF3;n contra formas inaceptables de trabajo">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">112442</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=PER/14/04/CAN">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Integrated system for the identification and registration of Child Labour in Peru</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
