<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/15/03/FIN" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105191-1105-2016-GLO303</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to the joint UN Social Protection Floor Initiative and Social Protection Interagency Cooperation Board (SPIAC-B)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive summary 1.1 This project provides an opportunity for the ILO to respond to the rapidly growing demand by countries and UN-partners for coordination and technical services in support of countries&apos; efforts to build their national social protection floors in line with the joint One-UN Social Protection Floors Initiative. 1.2 Following the financial crisis of 2007-2009 the UN Chief Executives Board (CEB) requested ILO to provide support to the joint UN Social Protection Floor (SPF) Initiative. The Government of Finland has supported this One-UN initiative through the ILO since 2010. The initiative has led to a UN-wide endorsement of the ILO Social Protection Floors Recommendation, 2012 (No. 202) (hereafter referred as R.202). The human right to social protection for all is now recognized as one of the core Post-2015 SDG-targets (OWG Target 1.3.). 1.3. The ILO and other UN-Agencies and international partners are under growing pressure as a rapidly increasing number of member State governments are demanding support and guidance in the creation and implementation of their national SPFs, in line with Recommendation.202. Member States are requesting technical advisory support to design and implement minimum guarantees that constitute their SPF as part of their national development strategies and social protection systems. Several governments are developing their national social protection extension strategies with a view to delivering reliable income security and access to health and social services for all people throughout their life cycles, context-tailored combinations of contributory and non-contributory social protection schemes. The present project builds upon previous collaboration between the Government of Finland and the ILO since 2010 through which the ILO has successfully facilitated the increasingly fruitful coordination and cooperation between UN-agencies, development banks, active bilateral development partners and key CSOs working in the field of social protection and essential services. Through the Finnish support substantial technical assistance has been provided to member States&apos; efforts in social protection assessments and national dialogues towards the realization of R.202, and inter-agency cooperation and coordination has been promoted. This led to the establishment of the context of the Social Protection Inter-Agency Cooperation Board (SPIAC-B), at the request of the G20 in 2012. This project promotes the concrete realization of the joint call of the UNDG Chair and ILO Director-Generals - Helen Clark and Guy Ryder - of 24 March 2014 wherein they called on all UN Country Teams to work together towards national floors of social protection. The present project provides for the setting-up of an ILO SPF Helpdesk of One UN and Inter-Agency for technical advisory and capacity building services to support UN country teams (UNCT) and their national and international partners in countries, namely in response to requests from national governments and from inter-agency initiatives as part of the coordinated efforts of &#x201C;Technical and Financial Partners&#x201D;, non-governmental agencies and donors, with the aim to strengthen the technical foundations of their endeavours to achieve policy coherence and a rational use of resources toward the national extension of social protection coverage. The project will strengthen the inter-agency collaboration in the context of the Social Protection Interagency Cooperation Board (SPIAC-B) at the global level, in the context of regional partnerships with UNDG regional chairs and in the context of national UNCT partnerships on social protection floors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="GLOBAL" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.ilo.org/dashboard"></recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">467134</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="GLO/15/03/FIN-2016-GLO303 - (2012-12): Strengthening the tripartite governance and performance monitoring of national social security systems-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">467134</value>
   <provider-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finland, Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="25010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="GLO/15/03/FIN-2016-GLO303 - (2012-12): Strengthening the tripartite governance and performance monitoring of national social security systems">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">467134</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="25010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/15/03/FIN">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Support to the joint UN Social Protection Floor Initiative and Social Protection Interagency Cooperation Board (SPIAC-B)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
