<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/16/06/HCR" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105635-1295-2016-GLO153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Building for UNHCR livelihood officers on value chain analyses for refugees</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the assignment is to reinforce capacities of UNHCR livelihoods officers (staff and affiliated workforce) to conduct market assessments and value chain analyses to enhance livelihoods interventions for refugees. The direct beneficiaries will therefore be UNHCR livelihoods officers, while the final beneficiaries will be refugees and asylum seekers in the selected countries as well as men and women working in the sector(s) identified as having the greatest potential to absorb and create decent work for refugees. To reinforce capacities in terms ILO will design and implement a training programme for UNHCR livelihoods officers, which entails a specifically designed theoretical training course as well as on-the-job training. More specifically, the capacity building for UNHCR livelihoods officers will consist of the following components: 1. Training needs assessment for livelihoods officers: ILO will conduct an assessment of trainings needs of UNHCR livelihoods officers that will help to determine the specific focus and content of subsequent theoretical and practical training on value chain development. 2. Development and delivery of a specifically designed training course on market assessments and value chain analyses for livelihoods officers: ILO will design and deliver a one-week training course on market assessments and value chain analyses to enhance livelihoods interventions for refugees. The training course will focus on providing guidance and practical skills for the design and implementation of value chain initiatives for refugees through theoretical inputs as well as practical examples. It will furthermore provide insights and tips on the use of related job-creation and labour market tools (skills development and entrepreneurship) and their practical application in the selected sectors. It will also touch upon the role of cooperatives in refugee employment and as they relate to value chain development. 3. Value Chain Analysis in one selected country with on-the-job training for livelihoods officers: a Value Chain Analysis will be conducted with the help of consultants in one strategically selected country (TBD). UNHCR livelihoods officers will support this value chain analysis and receive on-the-job training during the analysis. Livelihoods officers will support ILO and consultants in the preparation of the analysis including through drafting concept notes and terms of references, engaging in background research and drafting a detailed research plan for the analysis. On-the-job training during the preparation phase will be provided through an online platform. During the actual analysis, livelihoods officers will actively take part in interviews, focus group discussion and the final validation workshop so as to learn on the job how to conduct a value chain analysis. 4. Guidance on how to enhance livelihoods interventions for refugees through market assessments and value chain analyses: UNHCR livelihoods officers will receive a manual that gives a step-by-step overview of how to conduct a value chain analysis to enhance livelihoods interventions for refugees. Furthermore, model templates for terms of references, concept notes and research plans will be provided to guide and support livelihood officers who want to conduct value chain analyses. 5. C-BED pilot trainings in Egypt: Based on experiences during the first C-BED test training in Egypt in 2015, ILO will further adapt and translate all necessary material and organize 3-4 pilot trainings for Syrian refugees to test different modules and material. This should result in a strategy for subsequent roll-out of C-BED in Egypt.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="GLOBAL" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.ilo.org/dashboard"></recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-03-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">131405</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="GLO/16/06/HCR-2016-GLO153 - &#xA0;Sustainable enterprises: a global product for crisis recovery, income and employment creation-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-30">131405</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="GLO/16/06/HCR-2016-GLO153 - &#xA0;Sustainable enterprises: a global product for crisis recovery, income and employment creation">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-30">131405</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/16/06/HCR">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Capacity Building for UNHCR livelihood officers on value chain analyses for refugees</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
