<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=RLA/15/50/EEC" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105376-2970-2016-SSJ127</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustaining GSP-Plus Status by strengthened national capacities to improve ILS compliance and reporting &#x2013; Guatemala &amp; El Salvador</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives The present Action aims at improving the application of the 8 fundamental ILO conventions in the following ILO beneficiaries of the EU preferential GSP+ scheme: El Salvador, Guatemala, Mongolia and Pakistan. The selected countries will be assisted to take action to apply the 8 fundamental ILO Conventions and better meet their standards-related obligations, in particular on the critical issues raised by the ILO supervisory bodies and reflected under EU GSP+ monitoring. They will also be assisted to fulfil their ILO Constitutional reporting obligations on these conventions. Organisation/ implementation: The strategy will be to act on several fronts, as to improve implementation of ILS and compliance with reporting obligations and/or ratified fundamental Conventions. In each country, selected key actors capable to improve implementation of ILS will be given technical assistance, training and will be made aware of the critical issues. These actors will be members of the national administration, representatives of employers&#x2019; and workers&#x2019; organizations, judges and parliamentarians. The intervention to build administrative capacity on implementing the ILS will use a mix of approaches, focussing mainly on institutional development. Activities could include: &#xBF; Awareness-raising and training on the content of selected fundamental ILS. &#xBF; Research to generate information on the status of implementation of ILS, including legislative gap analyses, advice on elements that will enable tripartite constituents to take the relevant decisions aiming at full implementation. &#xBF; Legal advice on the revision or drafting of legislation and regulations in the light of the supervisory bodies&#x2019; comments. &#xBF; Strengthening of data collection and reporting capacity of tripartite constituents including the capacity of using the systemic approach to managing ILS constitutional obligations. &#xBF; Publication/adaptation of thematic materials on the implementation of the concerned ILS. The programme management strategy is designed to ensure coordination and coherence, while also ensuring cost-efficiency and national ownership aligned with the priorities identified by the supervisory bodies. The programme management will ensure complementarity with other EU-ILO projects horizontally or in the countries concerned and avoid overlap. The management structure is comprised of the following components:</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="389" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">113195</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="RLA/15/50/EEC-2016-SSJ127 - Base de conocimiento y formaci&#xF3;n de los constituyentes sobre discriminaci&#xF3;n mejorada.-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">113195</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Commission, DG Trade</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="11330" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="RLA/15/50/EEC-2016-SSJ127 - Base de conocimiento y formaci&#xF3;n de los constituyentes sobre discriminaci&#xF3;n mejorada.">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">113195</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="11330" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=RLA/15/50/EEC">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Sustaining GSP-Plus Status by strengthened national capacities to improve ILS compliance and reporting &#x2013; Guatemala &amp; El Salvador</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
