<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Dal campo al mercato (C2M): sostegno integrato alle associazioni  agricole e ai giovani produttori dei distretti di Magude, Moamba e  Manhi&#xE7;a per la s</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">L&#x2019;iniziativa si svolge nei distretti rurali di Magude, Moamba e Manhi&#xE7;a, nella Provincia di Maputo (Mozambico), 
in un contesto che negli ultimi anni &#xE8; stato colpito da una molteplicit&#xE0; di crisi (climatiche, economiche, agricole, 
sanitarie) che hanno limitato il potenziale di sviluppo agricolo e influito negativamente sul benessere e sulla 
sicurezza alimentare delle famiglie, prevalentemente dedite ad attivit&#xE0; di tipo agricolo, e sulla capacit&#xE0; dei 
giovani uomini e donne di trovare un&#x2019;occupazione o di avviare attivit&#xE0; generatrici di reddito. Il progetto C2M 
mira a contribuire al miglioramento della qualit&#xE0; di vita delle famiglie rurali in termini di sicurezza alimentare e 
di stabilit&#xE0; socio-economica proveniente da attivit&#xE0; agricole resilienti e sostenibili grazie al rafforzamento del 
settore agricolo in un&#x2019;ottica di adattamento al cambiamento climatico e, nello specifico, ad aumentare le 
opportunit&#xE0; di accesso al mercato per i piccoli produttori membri di associazioni agricole, con particolare 
attenzione per giovani donne e uomini, attraverso l&#x2019;aumento della produttivit&#xE0; agricola, la diminuzione delle 
perdite di produzione e l&#x2019;aumento delle competenze tecniche.
A questo fine, costruendo sull&#x2019;esperienza consolidata del proponente nel contesto di intervento con progetti 
di emergenza post-siccit&#xE0; e di costruzione di resilienza a livello rurale, utilizza un approccio multidimensionale 
e integrato, che si riflette nei tre risultati di progetto: migliora la capacit&#xE0; produttiva di 26 associazioni di piccoli 
produttori e produttrici grazie ad una maggiore disponibilit&#xE0; di infrastrutture e servizi per l&#x2019;agricoltura a livello 
distrettuale, con particolare attenzione alla promozione dell&#x2019;agricoltura irrigata; riduce la perdita di produzione 
agricola grazie a installazione di infrastrutture e formazioni su conservazione, trasformazione e 
commercializzazione; e incentiva la capacit&#xE0; di auto-impresa di 90 giovani anche attraverso l&#x2019;aumento delle 
competenze tecniche grazie a corsi e tirocini professionalizzanti.
C2M viene realizzato da una rete di partner che comprende una ONG iscritta all&#x2019;elenco con due decenni di 
esperienza nei distretti target (Helpcode), una societ&#xE0; cooperativa specializzata in sviluppo, gestione formazione su software per analisi e monitoraggio dei dati in contesti vulnerabili (Gnucoop), un&#x2019;impresa S.p.A
che sviluppa e brevetta materiali e prodotti da fonti rinnovabili per l&#x2019;agricoltura (Novamont), un&#x2019;istituzione del 
Governo mozambicano responsabile per lo sviluppo del settore agricolo a livello Provinciale (DPAP, Direzione 
Provinciale per Agricoltura e Pesca) e da un partner della societ&#xE0; civile mozambicana che &#xE8; un attore 
riconosciuto nella formazione, mentoring e advocacy in favore dell&#x2019;imprenditoria giovanile (ANJE). La DPAP &#xE8; 
coinvolta direttamente nel progetto come partner, supervisionando il processo di digitalizzazione del formato 
di raccolta dati agricoli realizzato, validato e adottato formalmente per tutta la Provincia di Maputo nell&#x2019;ambito 
del progetto affidato AID10862, e la formazione dei tecnici preposti alla raccolta. Le altre controparti 
istituzionali &#x2013; Governo dei distretti di intervento, con i Servizi Distrettuali per le Attivit&#xE0; Economiche (SDAE), 
Servizi distrettuali per Pianificazione e Infrastrutture (SDPI), Servizi Distrettuali per Istruzione, Giovani e 
Tecnologia (SDEJT) sono pienamente coinvolti nella definizione, esecuzione, visibilit&#xE0; e monitoraggio 
dell&#x2019;iniziativa, attraverso Memorandum di collaborazione. Questa attivit&#xE0; sottende alla logica di progetto 
secondo la quale disponibilit&#xE0; di dati agricoli di alta qualit&#xE0; e tempestivi &#xE8; fondamentale per le istituzioni a tutti 
i livelli, e per i partner, al fine di prendere decisioni valide per orientare le strategie di sviluppo agricolo e rurale, 
e contribuire alla riduzione della povert&#xE0; e dell&#x2019;insicurezza alimentare.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The initiative takes place in the rural districts of Magude, Moamba and Manhi&#xE7;a, in Maputo Province 
(Mozambique), in a context that in recent years has been affected by multiple, diversified crises (climatic, 
economic, agricultural, health-related) that have limited the potential for agricultural development and 
negatively affected the well-being and food security of rural households, mainly engaged in agricultural 
activities, and the ability of young men and women to find employment or start income-generating activities. 
The C2M project aims to contribute to the improvement of the quality of life of rural households in terms of 
food security and socio-economic stability resulting from resilient and sustainable agricultural activities through 
the strengthening of the agricultural sector in a perspective of adaptation to climate change. It specifically aims 
to increase opportunities for accessing local markets for small producers members of agricultural associations, 
with particular attention to young women and men, through the increase of agricultural productivity, the 
decrease of production and post-harvest losses and the increase of technical skills. 
To this end, building on the proponent&apos;s consolidated experience in the context of intervention with post?drought emergency and rural resilience projects, C2M adopts a multidimensional and integrated approach, 
which is reflected in the three project outputs: improving the productive capacity of 26 smallholder associations 
through increased availability of infrastructure and services for agriculture at the district level, with a focus on 
irrigated agriculture; reducing production and post-harvest losses through installation of infrastructure and 
training on conservation, processing and marketing; and boosting the self-enterprise capacity of 90 young 
people including through increased technical skills with vocational courses and internships. 
C2M is implemented by a network of partners that includes a registered NGO with two decades of experience 
in the target districts (Helpcode), a cooperative specialised in the development, management and training on 
software for data analysis and monitoring in vulnerable contexts (Gnucoop), a corporation that develops and 
patents materials and products from renewable sources for agriculture (Novamont), an institution of the 
Mozambican Government (Provincial Directorate of Agriculture and Fisheries, DPAP) and a Mozambican 
partner (NGO) that is a recognised actor in training, entrepreneurship (ANJE). The DPAP is also directly involved in the project as a partner, supervising the process 
of digitalization of the agricultural data collection form implemented, validated and formally adopted for the 
whole Maputo Province under the project AID10862, and the training of technicians in charge of field data 
collection. The institutional counterparts - Governments of the intervention districts, with the District Services 
for Economic Activities (SDAE), District Services for Planning and Infrastructure (SDPI), District Services for 
Education, Youth and Technology (SDEJT) are fully involved in the definition, implementation, visibility and 
monitoring of the initiative, through Memorandum of Collaboration. This activity underpins the project logic 
that the availability of high quality and timely agricultural data is essential for institutions at all levels, and for 
cooperation partners, in order to make sound decisions to guide agricultural and rural development strategies
and activities, and contribute to the reduction of poverty and food insecurity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HELP CODE ITALIA ONLUS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/02/4" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31194" percentage="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural co-operatives</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31150" percentage="14" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural inputs</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31140" percentage="40" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural water resources</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31161" percentage="27" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food crop production</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="12" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-15">1789165.03</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HELP CODE ITALIA ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-20">1073499.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HELP CODE ITALIA ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
