<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ETHAKA - A sustainable agricultural production and consumption model for  climate resilience and food and nutrition security</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto ETHAKA, di 36 mesi, che si realizzer&#xE0; in 4 distretti delle Province di Zambezia e Nampula, nasce 
dall&#x2019;esperienza che ICEI, Istituto Oikos e Associazione Mani Tese e i partner di progetto in Italia (Comune 
di Milano) e in loco (2 autorit&#xE0; pubbliche e 2 enti accademici, ONG Helvetas) hanno maturato in 
Mozambico e nel settore, nell&#x2019;ambito di iniziative di promozione di modelli agricoli resilienti al clima 
e di nutrizione. L&#x2019;intervento, che coinvolge come partner i autorit&#xE0; pubbliche delle due provincie a garanzia della sua 
sostenibilit&#xE0; istituzionale, intende offrire una risposta alla limitata disponibilit&#xE0; e diversificazione 
agricola e alimentare causata da: i) sistemi agricoli a bassa produttivit&#xE0;, ii) un quadro normativo e 
istituzionale non favorevole e servizi di assistenza tecnica inadeguati per la pianificazione di modelli agricoli 
resilienti e sostenibili iii) abitudini alimentari e igienico sanitarie inadeguate a soddisfare le esigenze
nutrizionali.
La strategia di intervento &#xE8; finalizzata a contribuire a raggiungere la sicurezza alimentare, migliorare la 
nutrizione e aumentare il reddito della popolazione del Mozambico (OG) &#x2013; sia in ambito rurale che urbano 
&#x2013; e si basa sull&#x2019;adozione a livello istituzionale e comunitario (famiglie) di un modello agricolo di produzione 
e consumo sostenibile, resiliente e che soddisfi le esigenze nutrizionali della popolazione (OS). Per 
raggiungere tale obiettivo, il progetto intende:
1. Aumentare la sicurezza alimentare delle famiglie di produttori su piccola scala - in particolare donne e 
giovani - in 16 comunit&#xE0;, aumentando e diversificando la produzione primaria da un lato, rafforzando le 
principali filiere alimentari dall&#x2019;altro. A tale scopo saranno promosse tecniche di produzione agricola 
sostenibile secondo un approccio circolare e resiliente ai cambiamenti climatici (Sistemi AgroForestali e 
agroecologia), saranno diversificate le attivit&#xE0; produttive introducendo allevamento su piccola scala, 
piscicoltura e apicoltura e si rafforzeranno le capacit&#xE0; e le strutture per le fasi di post-raccolta (stoccaggio 
e trasformazione), sia per la sicurezza alimentare che per l&#x2019;accesso al mercato. Parallelamente si 
realizzeranno azioni di conservazione e ripristino degli ecosistemi costieri degradati presenti (mangrovieti, 
ecosistemi dunali), secondo il modello agricolo in equilibrio con l&#x2019;ambiente proposto dall&#x2019;iniziativa.
2) Rafforzare il quadro normativo per un adeguato trade-off tra agricoltura e ambiente, attraverso un 
profondo lavoro di advocacy con le istituzioni a livello municipale (Quelimane, Nampula), provinciale 
(Zambezia, Nampula) e nazionale affinch&#xE9; siano promosse politiche pubbliche settoriali di agricoltura 
sostenibile e sistemi alimentari sostenibili in linea con il modello. Un corposo programma di 
rafforzamento di capacit&#xE0; rivolto ai principali stakeholder del settore, in particolare funzionari e tecnici 
delle autorit&#xE0; pubbliche di riferimento, sar&#xE0; il volano per la creazione di una Task-force interprovinciale, a 
cui si inviteranno rappresentanti del livello nazionale, per la formulazione di raccomandazioni di politiche 
e successive azioni di advocacy con decisori a livello municipale, provinciale e nazionale. A livello 
municipale si promuover&#xE0; l&#x2019;adozione del Milan Urban Food Policy Pact (MUFPP) da parte delle due capitali 
provinciali; agli altri livelli l&#x2019;adozione di documenti di pianificazione strategica secondo le raccomandazioni 
della Task-force. 
Cuore pulsante di questa componente sar&#xE0; la creazione di un &#x201C;Centro di Innovazione, divulgazione e 
formazione permanente in Sistemi Agro-Forestali - CISAF&#x201D;, che sperimenter&#xE0; e promuover&#xE0; tecniche 
basate sui sistemi agroforestali, supporter&#xE0; l&apos;innovazione e incentiver&#xE0; opportunit&#xE0; di collaborazione 
interdisciplinare nell&apos;area accademica, tra policy makers e con il settore privato, costituendosi come una 
piattaforma di confronto a livello nazionale e internazionale.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ETHAKA project, of 36 months, which will be implemented in 4 districts of the Provinces of Zambezia 
and Nampula, arises from the experience that ICEI, Istituto Oikos and Associazione Mani Tese and the 
project partners in Italy (Municipality of Milan) and in the field (2 public authorities and 2 academic 
institutions, NGO Helvetas) have gained in Mozambique and in the sector, in the context of initiatives for 
the promotion of climate resilient agricultural models and nutrition. 
The intervention, which involves as partners public authorities of the two provinces to ensure its 
institutional sustainability, aims to offer a response to the limited availability and diversification of 
agricultural products and food caused by: i) low productivity farming systems, ii) an unfavourable
environment in terms of regulatory and institutional framework and inadequate technical assistance 
services for the planning of resilient and sustainable agricultural models iii) inadequate food and sanitation 
habits to meet nutritional needs. 
The intervention strategy aims to help achieve food security, improve nutrition, and increase the income 
of the population of Mozambique (Impact) - both rural and urban - and is based on the adoption at 
institutional and community (household) levels of an agricultural model of production and consumption 
that is sustainable, resilient, and meets the nutritional needs of the population (Outcome). To achieve this 
goal, the project will: 
1. Increase the food security of small-scale producer households - particularly women and youth - in 16 
communities, by increasing and diversifying primary production on the one hand, and strengthening key 
food value-chains on the other. To this end, sustainable agricultural production techniques will be 
promoted according to a circular approach and resilient to climate change (AgroForestry Systems and 
agroecology), production activities will be diversified by introducing small-scale livestock farming, fish 
farming and beekeeping, and capacities and facilities for the post-harvest stages (storage and processing) 
will be strengthened, both for food security and for market access. In parallel, actions will be carried out 
to conserve and restore the degraded coastal ecosystems present (mangroves, dune ecosystems), 
according to the agricultural model in balance with the environment proposed by the initiative. 
2) Strengthen the regulatory framework for an adequate trade-off between agriculture and 
environment, through a deep advocacy work with institutions at municipal (Quelimane, Nampula), 
provincial (Zambezia, Nampula) and national level, in order to promote public sector policies of 
sustainable agriculture and sustainable food systems in line with the model. A substantial capacity-building program aimed at key stakeholders in the sector, in particular officials and technicians of the 
relevant public authorities, will be the driving force behind the creation of an inter-provincial Task-force, 
to which representatives from the national level will be invited, for the formulation of policy 
recommendations and subsequent advocacy actions with decision-makers at municipal, provincial and 
national level. At the municipal level the adoption of the Milan Urban Food Policy Pact (MUFPP) by the 
two provincial capitals will be promoted; at other levels, the adoption of strategic planning documents 
according to the recommendations of the Task Force. 
The heart of this component will be the creation of a &quot;Center for Innovation, Dissemination and training
in Agro-Forestry Systems - CISAF&quot;, which will test and promote techniques based on agro-forestry systems, 
support innovation and encourage opportunities for interdisciplinary collaboration in the academic area, 
among policy makers and with the private sector, constituting a platform for comparison at national and 
international level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICEI - ISTITUTO COOPERAZIONE ECONOMICA INTERNAZIONALE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/02/5" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="38" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43071" percentage="36" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food security policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43072" percentage="26" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Household food security programmes</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end all forms of malnutrition, including achieving, by 2025, the internationally agreed targets on stunting and wasting in children under 5&#xA0;years of age, and address the nutritional needs of adolescent girls, pregnant and lactating women and older persons</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase investment, including through enhanced international cooperation, in rural infrastructure, agricultural research and extension services, technology development and plant and livestock gene banks in order to enhance agricultural productive capacity in developing countries, in particular least developed countries</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-15">3597313</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICEI - ISTITUTO COOPERAZIONE ECONOMICA INTERNAZIONALE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-20">2158387.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICEI - ISTITUTO COOPERAZIONE ECONOMICA INTERNAZIONALE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
