<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41155305-GLA-JET</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41155305" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tropenbos International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLA - Just Energy Transition, the greater Virunga landscape and the Ituri landscape in DRC</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Landscapes rich in valuable natural resources, such as oil, forested and associated water-based ecosystems (lakes, mangroves) are at risk of degradation and pollution by exploration and exploitation of oil, through deforestation for installations/ pipelines, oil spills, and gas flaring. Of particular concern is potential damage to national reserves/parks, and spawning grounds of fish in the Delta and along the shores of Lake Albert and Lake Edward. Also, governance of oil resources is characterized by high degrees of inequality. Especially communities/ordinary citizens lack voice in decision-making about oil exploration and exploitation plans and benefit sharing. On the other end of the spectrum, geo-political interests also influence oil resource governance in the focus countries. Furthermore, violations of local, national and international best practices on human and environmental rights are widespread and corporate accountability is generally weak. In some cases regulations are absent, conflicting or lack harmonization, but mostly a lack of will (influenced by corruption), weak enforcement capacities on behalf of relevant state agencies, and a lack of accountability mechanisms in the home countries of multinationals are noted. Of specific concern are the transboundary challenges related to the management of DR Congo-Uganda oil reserves because it increases the risk of conflict in the region. In spite of (prospected) oil production and export, millions of people in the focus countries have no access to energy and mostly rely on fuel wood and charcoal for cooking. This constitutes a massive threat to deforestation and underlines the urgency for a transition towards renewable sources of energy, in particular on community level. But as governments in the focus countries predominantly appreciate the economic benefits of oil exploitation, a discussion around long-term costs and benefits of oil is weakly embedded in broader reflection and agenda setting on renewable energy sources, inclusive and just energy transition, and other values (ex. cultural values, livelihoods, biodiversity, water, tourism) the oil-rich landscapes offer. This links on global level with reflections on unsustainable nature of fossil fuels in meeting worldwide demand for energy within the limited carbon budget defined by the worldwide ambition to keep climate change under two degrees global warming.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TBI-DRC will focus its 2017 JET efforts on reducing wood energy consumption by using good practice I.e. by raising awareness of local communities and opinion leaders of Ituri landscape about good practices in energy use and natural resource management. We will organize the sellers of charcoal and firewood in association so that they are able to pay taxes while at the same time reducing their number so that they become controllable. Finally, we intend advocacy and lobbying of provincial and national deputies of the province of Ituri, so that the issue of energy transition will increasingly be discussed in the provincial and national assemblies. The advocacy capacity of (local) CSOs partners (FLEVICA, COCOLPE, APAJI and CVAP) will be strengthened, and their vision will be unified during the workshops that we will organize for this purpose; We will sensitize local communities, including marginalized groups (women, youth and indigenous groups), on best practice of sustainable wood energy management (using improved woodstoves). A panel discussion will be organized at the University of Bunia in Ituri, targeting professors, teachers, students and the heads of the 3 big Universities of Bunia: University Shaloom, university of Bunia and ISP/Bunia. Topic will be best practice of natural resource management and issues of oil exploitation in Lake Albert. This will allow these influential people of the province to understand the major challenges and risks of oil exploitation. Finally, advocacy missions and individual contacts will be made with both provincial and national deputies to advocate for a just energetic transition and change of laws in favour of a just energy transitions in the near future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The thematic programme, in the long-term, wants to contribute to a pro-people, inclusive and just energy transition process (moving away from oil/fossil fuels towards renewable energy) that specifically considers gender and vulnerable groups. Four pathways of intermediary change within the sphere of influence of the programme contribute to the overall goal: R1: CSOs are unified around a common ideology on inclusive and just energy transition: broadening the knowledge and experience of the CSO coalition on energy transition and strengthening capacities on research, lobby and advocacy. Also exchange with CSOs from other African countries and, where relevant, northern countries will be stimulated. R2: Relevant national government agencies in the African focus countries progressively encourage/ promote an inclusive and just energy transition: lobby and advocacy that is based on well-researched analyses on the economic potential of renewable options for development, coupled with legislative lobby on specific (inter) national policy development will increase government engagement and eventually budgeting for just energy transition. R3: Best practices of inclusive and just energy transition exist in communities in the selected landscapes: The programme aims to raise awareness on community level and stimulate engagement/ participation in energy transition agenda setting processes. R4: New or existing oil exploration/extraction projects are halted or delayed: The programme will also look at oil exploration and exploitation that is already taking place (Nigeria) or at provisions made by government and private actors to launch operations in time to come (DR Congo, Uganda). Violations by companies and governments of international best practice around human and environment rights standards will be addressed by the programme through campaigning and litigation. This will further motivate support for the need for energy transition and reduce demand for oil. Litigation and campaign work may also delay (and potentially halt) oil projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41155305-GLA-JET" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TBI-DRC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41155305-GLA-JET" ref="NL-KVK-41155305" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tropenbos International (TBI)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41155305-GLA-JET" ref="NL-KVK-41155305" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tropenbos International (TBI)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41155305-GLA-JET" ref="NL-KVK-41155305" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tropenbos International (TBI)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trudi van Ingen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PMEL Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>trudi.vaningen@tropenbos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="32210" percentage="33" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="33" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="34" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">34957</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">32500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">41000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">31000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">24800</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">38375</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">42693</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Expenses 2018">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">50957</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Expenditure 2019">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">38945</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Expenditure 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">40183</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/170404-Civil-Actor-Participation-(CAP)-tool-20170515010512.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil Actor Participation (CAP) tool</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Engagement,-Commitment-and-Action-(ECA)-Tool-20170515010507.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Engagement, Commitment and Action (ECA) tool</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41155305-GLA" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
