<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41155305-GLA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41155305" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tropenbos International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Livelihood Alliance</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society; Governments; International institutions; Private sector actors, Knowledge Institutions</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forested landscapes form the cornerstone of the livelihoods of about 1.2 billion people almost 20% of the world&#x2019;s population. A large proportion of these people are among the poorest in the world. They are often particularly disadvantaged because their rights over land and natural resources are frequently ill-defined and far from assured. Forested landscapes in developing countries are also crucially linked to the rest of the world. The natural services they provide are regarded as International Public Goods (IPGs). The services climate resilience, biodiversity, and food and water security are critical for growing agro-commodities that are consumed globally. Despite the tremendous services forested landscapes provide, almost a third of the world&#x2019;s forests have disappeared and another 20% of global forest cover is seriously degraded. Unsustainable cultivation of food, animal feed and energy crops is one of the root causes of deforestation as the expansion of plantations leads to further deforestation and land degradation. Incentivized by agricultural and trade policies, international actors such as multinational corporations and investors are major drivers of forest loss. Still, also local communities and small, local companies can contribute heavily to loss and degradation of forests. Another important driver of deforestation and land degradation is the lack of political and private will in many low- and lower-middle-income countries to safeguard the critical functions that forests provide. Scientific and empirical research shows that informed local communities with ownership of or access to land play a crucial role in safeguarding productive forested landscapes. Inclusive and sustainable governance of forested landscapes is founded on informed joint decision-making and collaboration by all stakeholders &#x2013; government agencies, the private sector and local communities. This type of governance ensures equal access to natural resources and their benefits, ensuring thriving green livelihoods of local communities. The Green Livelihoods Alliance will act to support &#x2013; and simultaneously learn from &#x2013; local communities in forested landscapes. With our mutually reinforcing networks, tools, knowledge and experience, Alliance members Milieudefensie, IUCN NL and Tropenbos International work with civil society organisations (CSOs) who share our goals to represent and empower local communities in lobby &amp; advocacy to bring about inclusive and sustainable governance of forested landscapes. Where possible, through collaboration the Green Livelihoods Alliance will facilitate multi-stakeholder dialogues with a wider group of CSOs, local and international companies and governments to improve policies and practices. Where necessary, we will empower CSO partners to press public and private stakeholders for change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the Green Livelihoods Alliance is to strengthen the abilities and effectiveness of Southern CSOs to influence policies and practices to achieve the inclusive and sustainable governance of forested landscapes. In these landscapes local communities can enjoy secure access to ecosystem services on the basis of three core elements: 1. Equitable access to and better control over land, natural resources and rights; 2. Inclusive landscape governance; and 3. Nature-based approaches to conservation, sustainable management and forest restoration, including for enhanced climate resilience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-40530467-GLA" ref="NL-KVK-40530467" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Milieudefensie</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41155305-GLA" ref="NL-KVK-41155305" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tropenbos International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41155305-GLA" ref="NL-KVK-41155305" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tropenbos International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tropenbos International is an international non -governmental non-profit organization based in the Netherlands which aims to improve forest management and protection for the benefit of local inhabitants and sustainable development in the tropics. By making knowledge work for forests and people, Tropenbos International contributes to well-informed decision making for improved management and governance of tropical forests. Its longstanding local presence and ability to bring together local, national and international partners make Tropenbos International a trusted partner in sustainable development.</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Roderick Zagt</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+31 317 702028</telephone>
   <email>roderick.zagt@tropenbos.org</email>
   <website>http://www.tropenbos.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O.Box 232 6700 AE Wageningen The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="312" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="920" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">930844</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">2992750</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">2987250</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">3540000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">3185000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">875935</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">2404149</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Expenditure 2018">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">2824903</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Expenditure 2019">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">3506421</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Expenditure 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">3087783</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://multimedia.milieudefensie.nl/GLA_AnnualPlan_2017/GLA_Jaarplan_2017.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLA Annual Plan 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/GLA_voortgangsrapportage_2016-20171004111004.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLA overall progress report 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.tropenbos.org/file.php/2133/tropenbos-international-iati-exclusion-policy.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tropenbos International Exclusion Policy</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-40530467-GLA" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
