<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-22/UKR_CBPF/RA3/FSL/NGO/21925</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing emergency humanitarian assistance to improve food security and build the capacity of small farms.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The security situation in Ukraine deteriorated sharply after the escalation of the military conflict on February 24, 2022 and continues to deteriorate. Intense fighting and continuous shelling have resulted in a humanitarian catastrophe, including death and injury, massive displacement of civilians throughout the country, and severe damage and destruction of critical civilian infrastructure and private housing 
As stated in Flash Appeal Ukraine. March-August 2022, more than 12 million people remain locked down in affected areas or unable to leave due to heightened danger, destruction of bridges and roads, and a lack of resources or information on where to find safe housing. The ongoing hostilities have led to severe shortages of food and water. Due to the escalation of the conflict, the sowing campaign is difficult, most of the land is not accessible and needs to be cleared
This project is divided into two components
As part of the first activity, HADC plans to improve the well-being of 300 small family farms both in the territory of the NGCA (territory ownership until 24.02.2022) and in territories with an undetermined status, to which the NGCA has access. The main selection criterion for family farms is the production and processing of agricultural products. This activity will increase the productivity of small family and individual farms, support more people with food (including members of their own household). This type of assistance will include seeds for the second rotation of vegetable crops (radishes, onions, lettuce, cucumbers, early potatoes), as well as:
- fertilizers and plant protection products
- fertilizers and green manure seeds (mustard, phacelia, clover, vetch, alfalfa, etc.) to prepare the soil for the next season
- fertilizers for the current crop and plant protection products (herbicides, pesticides)
The average cost of support for one small farm is $200
The second component is designed to provide alternative one-time food assistance to 4,000 people who are in dire need of this type of assistance. The planned activity is to provide immediate access to food for 4,000 people living in the territories with undetermined status, to which the NGCA has access. As a quick response, we suggest using an alternative food package recommended by the cluster
CF &quot;HADC&quot; is the first organization at the NGCA that provided food assistance to residents of Mariupol in extremely difficult access conditions, while other humanitarian actors carried out trips at a later and quieter time. The organization has the opportunity to provide humanitarian assistance in extremely difficult to reach locations. Thus, in April alone, we provided food, candles, matches, water and warm clothes for 3,000 beneficiaries (the total weight of the humanitarian cargo was over 30 tons). As part of this project, HADC plans to provide food assistance to residents of the most hard-to-reach locations, where there is the most urgent need and food supply chains are disrupted.
The project complies with SO1 &#xAB;Provide principled and timely life-saving multisectoral assistance to people affected by the war Implement principled humanitarian action&#x2014;that is neutral, impartial and independent&#x2014;to ensure that humanitarian actors can reach all people in need, wherever they are, in Ukraine. Save lives by providing essential and gender- and ageresponsive protection, shelter, health, critical household items, food security and livelihoods, water, sanitation, hygiene, and education to people affected by the war. Scale-up multisectoral response through the use of multipurpose cash to address the different humanitarian needs of affected people in a holistic manner with due consideration to gender, age, and disability needs. Scale up logistics and telecommunications to allow for an efficient and effective response and communication with affected communities to ensure accountability to crisis-affected people (AAP)&#xBB;, - &#xAB;Flash Appeal Ukraine. March-August 2022&#xBB;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHARITABLE FOUNDATION &quot;HUMANITARIAN AID AND DEVELOPMENT CENTRE&quot;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHARITABLE FOUNDATION &quot;HUMANITARIAN AID AND DEVELOPMENT CENTRE&quot;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ninel Gasparyan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Head</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+38066 227 35 38</telephone>
   <email>centrgumpom@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UA14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donetska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.04731497 37.67411990</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-24">385655.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-21925">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-24">385655.62</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHARITABLE FOUNDATION &quot;HUMANITARIAN AID AND DEVELOPMENT CENTRE&quot;</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305597860">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-02">192827.81</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHARITABLE FOUNDATION &quot;HUMANITARIAN AID AND DEVELOPMENT CENTRE&quot;</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
