<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-22/UKR_CBPF/RA3/S-NFI-WASH/NGO/21900</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency support to the population of vulnerable categories of Donetsk NGCA and of Donetsk GCA affected by military actions.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ongoing military actions lead to numerous damages to social, engineering and medical infrastructure, thousands of homes are completely or partially destroyed. Due to the ongoing shelling and the inability to return to the destroyed housing, hundreds of thousands of civilians are still in temporary accommodation centers, the other part is forced to survive in basements and bomb shelters. As a result of the escalation of the military conflict in the territories where active hostilities are being conducted, there is a complete lack of water supply, heat supply, gas pipelines and power lines are damaged. Civilians: the elderly, the disabled, families with children are doomed to survive in extremely difficult conditions of hunger, cold and unsanitary conditions. Many people continue to live in dilapidated houses, unwilling to leave their only home in the hope of restoring it (at least partially) and establishing minimal living and sanitary conditions with the help and participation of humanitarian missions and local administrations.
Social and medical institutions faced great difficulties in the conditions of insufficient funding and ongoing hostilities, there is an urgent need to provide sanitation and hygiene facilities for the prevention and control of infectious diseases.
Based on this, CO &quot;ICF &quot;MIRA&quot; plans to take a number of necessary measures within 3 months to ensure adequate living conditions, including sanitary and hygienic conditions for 1000 vulnerable households by providing: 1000 hygiene kits, 500 households with sets of NFI STANDARD SHELTER EMERGENCY KIT for urgent repair of damaged housing, the cost of one set will be $176, 250 sets of NFI STANDARD NFI EMERGENCY KIT for households with basic household items, the cost of the set will be $153.94 and 250 sets of NFI STANDARD TC/CC NFI EMERGENCY KIT, the cost of which is $204.82. The provision of NFI kits will help ensure proper living conditions, carry out urgent repairs and return to homes, which will reduce the number of IDPs. 
Measures are also planned to provide 5 social and 5 medical institutions of Donetsk NGCA and Donetsk GCA with appropriate sanitary and hygienic kits for the prevention of infectious diseases. The assistance will be focused on people of vulnerable categories, of which: those in a difficult life situation as a result of the destruction of housing and in need of NFI Kits and sanitation and hygiene products to reduce the risks of the spread of infectious diseases, will be 60% elderly people -10% single parents -5% large families -5% people with disabilities - 6% people with chronic diseases - 10%. The identification of beneficiaries will take place on the basis of information provided by local administrations at the request of the CO &quot;ICF &quot;MIRA&quot;  in accordance with the selection critThe organization has sufficient successful experience in implementing projects with WASH and SHELTER components, taking into account all possible risks. Wherever possible, the organization will call for gender equality and seek to inform about the lessons learned from gender and integration issues in order to raise awareness of stakeholders about them.
The CO &quot;ICF&quot; MIRA&quot; will ensure that all proposed measures contribute appropriately and without discrimination to the integration, safety, protection and dignity of people of different genders and ages, especially people with disabilities and the elderly.  All program activities will be aimed at preventing gender, will be transformative, benefit individuals, allow them to enjoy family life, communities and
society as a whole, which will accelerate the achievement of Sustainable Development Goals. First of all, all activities will contribute to ensuring gender equality, empowering women and girls, and will also be crucial
for improving the well-being of people with disabilities, with chronic diseases, the elderly, women and children, for the well-being of families, which, in turn, will reduce gender inequa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Children&#x2019;s Fund &#x2018;Mira&#x2019;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Children&#x2019;s Fund &#x2018;Mira&#x2019;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karolina Nosatova</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of board</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380 50 477 13 31</telephone>
   <email>mdfmira@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UA14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donetska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.04731497 37.67411990</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="70" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-10">274562.21</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-21900">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-10">274562.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Children&#x2019;s Fund &#x2018;Mira&#x2019;</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
