<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-22/UKR_CBPF/RA2/NUT-P/INGO/21717</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Protection, PSS and Nutrition response for conflict-affected girls, boys and families  in Vinnitsa and Chernivtsy.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children (SC) is proposing an integrated Child Protection (CP)and nutrition response for children and their caregivers in the targeted locations  of Vinnitsa and Chernivtsy through the provision of gender-sensitive PSS, IYCF support and individual assistance, prioritizing children most at risk, including children with disabilities and UASC. Children with disabilities and children in institutional care are particularly vulnerable due to their weakened protective environment and are at higher risk of psychosocial distress, violence, GBV, abuse, abandonment, and exploitation.Activities will include rapid family tracing and support to families to prevent separation. CP focal points will be mobilized and service mapping conducted ensuring accurate information on protection services is accessible. Frontline workers and partner staff will be trained on PFA  and remote and in-person MHPSS activities will be scaled up. Psychosocial support activities will be provided for children, caregivers and humanitarian workers along with the distribution of recreational kits. SC will provide individual case management and strengthen the capacity of case workers and service providers in line with international standards. SC will support the functionality of referral mechanisms though the Child Protection Sub-cluster. Strict confidentiality and other ethical standards will be followed in managing the hotline cases. SC will support Collective Centers to ensure that a protective environment is available for children and their families, including Children with Disabilities (CwD). SC will support the establishment and operation of Child Friendly Spaces (CFSs) and conduct activities to reduce caregivers&#x2019; distress, strengthen their coping strategies and improve their ability to strengthen their children&#x2019;s resilience. The Minimum Standards for CP in Humanitarian Action with particular focus on the Pillar Four Standard 21 to 28 and SGBV minimum standards will guide the CP activities. SC will further strengthen the capacity of facilitators and case workers to support CwDs and their families. 
To contribute to reduce the risk of excessive mortality amongst infants and children aged 0-23 months, SC will promote and support safe and appropriate feeding practices for both breastfed and non-breastfed infants and young children aged 0-23 months during emergencies, in Chernivtsy. SC will establish Mother Baby Areas(MBA/MBC) at key points in collective centres and transit points. MBAs will provide safe nurturing environment for early child development.They will also function as a referral pathway to CP services and other services and programmes. SC will promote IYCFE among caregivers. Volunteers will be trained on IYCFE in emergencies as well as in CSG and PSEA. Nutrition services provided in MBA will serve to support the delivery of nurturing care activities that address the physical, mental and socio-emotional needs of caregivers and children. These include relaxation and recreational activities for mothers, caregivers and children, support groups, as well as individual nutrition counselling. SC will provide specialized support for mothers who wish to reactivate breastfeeding. SC will comply with all agreed standards for the safe and appropriate provision of SLM,such as the programming guide for procurement and use of breastmilk substitutes in humanitarian settings. SC will work hand in hand with the wash team to ensure that water used is safe and with the health team to monitor growth and development of children who attend the spaces.SC has worked in Ukraine since 2007 and responded to the conflict since 2014. SC is now scaling up its operation and is establishing offices in Liviv, Uzhorod, and Chernivtsi as well as field offices in Vinnytsia and Dnipro.SC is mobilizing emergency financing to facilitate an effective, wide-scale humanitarian response. A humanitarian surge team has been deployed to the response in Ukraine, to support the permanent staf</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kateryna Slobodianik</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Finance</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380953066758</telephone>
   <email>Ekaterina.Slobodyanik@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Denis Puzhalin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Quality and Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380666062435</telephone>
   <email>denis.puzhalin@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UA73">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chernivetska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.26819792 25.97702081</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="UA05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vinnytska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.92044212 28.68553580</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="26" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="74" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-03">1000000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-21717">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-03">1000000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305563853">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-12">800000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
