<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-22/UKR_CBPF/RA1/FSL/UN/21363</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural livelihood support provision and resilience building of conflict affected people in hard to reach communities of Eastern Ukraine (GCA)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The conflict in East Ukraine is exacerbating an already economically troubled region in further socio-economic decline. Out of the 1.1 million people in need of livelihoods assistance, 400,000 people are estimated to be severely or moderately food insecure and chronically affected by conflict resulting in lack of income and livelihoods opportunities, which in turn negatively impacts their physical and mental wellbeing. 

This project will target conflict affected vulnerable HHs and displaced farmers (2 224 HHs/5 115 persons) in the rural areas of Donetsk oblast, in particular residing in the hard-to-reach villages located within 0-10 km from the contact line in the Government Controlled Areas (GCA) where agricultural production is one of the main income sources. The socio-economic status of these rural HHs is acutely impacted by the ongoing conflict where people are more vulnerable because of higher unemployment rates, and where population lost access to many sources of livelihoods that were available before the conflict.

Furthermore, over 30% of the population in the target area is aged over 60, with the majority being women whose access to food and livelihoods have been limited by ongoing insecurity. With prohibitive distances to the main urban centers to access food markets, these rural HHs have become vulnerable and have been relying on their own backyard agricultural and livestock production to cover their basic food security and nutrition needs.

In light of these identified challenges, the main objective of this project is to contribute to improved food security and livelihoods conditions of these conflict affected vulnerable people, and to strengthen their resilience through provision of Agricultural-Livelihoods assistance and capacity building trainings. The project will target the most vulnerable HHs within the communities including the women headed households, displaced farmers, elderly individuals, persons with disabilities, and unemployed persons.

The proposed project activities are strongly aligned with UHF 2022 Reserve Allocation Strategy and Priorities and contribute to the intervention area 2 &#x2018;Agricultural and non-agricultural livelihood support to population affected by the conflict.&#x2019; The proposed project is also aligned with the Food Security and Livelihoods Cluster (FSLC) priorities and will contribute to the FSLC objective 2: &#x2018;Strengthen vulnerable conflict-affected households&#x2019; self-reliance and contribute to the economic capacity by protecting and restoring agricultural and non-agricultural livelihoods&#x2019;. 

Contribution will be made through provision of vegetable seeds to the most vulnerable households along with trainings responding to their most pressing food needs, and by the provision of trainings to farmers who have been severely affected by conflict or internally displaced, in overall contributing to build up on the resilience and recovery of the most affected rural communities near the contact line. 

Furthermore, the project is aligned with the UN Humanitarian Development Peace Nexus (HDP Nexus), aiming at promoting and maximizing synergies across humanitarian response and development programmes and contributing to the HDP Nexus priority on the equitable and sustainable access to livelihoods and economic opportunities of the conflict affected population. 

FAO will partner with local NGOs to provide quality response to humanitarian and development needs, building local capacity to enable the sustainable provision of quality services upon the completion of the project in support of the phasing out of International actors from the area.

The project will be implemented through a close coordination with FSLC and partners, local authorities and community members. Protection will be mainstreamed and FAO&#x2019;s framework on Accountability to Affected Populations will be applied through the design, implementation and monitoring phases of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Advisory Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charitable Foundation Center For Social Development &quot;Bridge&quot;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mara Lopes</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Office</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380506092230</telephone>
   <email>mara.lopes@fao.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UA14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donetska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.04731497 37.67411990</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-19">625007.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-19">70712.51</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-21363">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-19">695719.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305540128">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-27">695719.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
