<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-22/UKR_CBPF/RA3/WASH-CSS-H-FSL/NGO/21903</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency multi-sectoral assistance to the conflict-affected population living in areas under threat, particularly Bakhmutskyi, Kramatorskyi and Pokrovskyi rayons of Donetska oblast, GCA.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The security situation, related to the armed conflict has rapidly deteriorated since the start of the military escalation. A large number of people became IDPs or moved abroad. The population remaining, even those currently not directly affected by security incidents and fighting, are facing reduced or disrupted services. Local authorities&#x2019; capacities to provide social protection services are overstretched. There is an increased need for WASH support in conflict-affected areas at both the community and household levels, as well as a need for maintaining the functioning of health infrastructure by procuring and providing supplies such as water tanks, generators, etc.
The objective of the proposed project is to address the acute immediate lifesaving and life-sustaining needs of the most vulnerable men, women, boys, and girls living in areas under threat, particularly Bakhmutskyi, Kramatorskyi and Pokrovskyi rayons of Donetska oblast, GCA.
Within the framework of the project it is planned to implement the following activities: 
- Distribution of generators to ensure backup electricity supply and sustained operation of boreholes and pumping stations
- Distribution of generators to ensure backup electricity supply of medical institutions
- Distribution of materials to local water supply companies, such as pipes, pumps, valves, etc., necessary for emergency repairs of water supply systems in case of damages, including as a result of hostilities
- Provision of equipment necessary for pipeline repair
- Distribution of Family and PSN hygiene kits for the most vulnerable population, the composition of which is according to recommendations of the WASH Cluster
- Distribution of food parcels in addition to hygiene kits
- Distribution of bottled water and water trucking in settlements suffering from lack of water
- Distribution of tanks and jerry cans for emergency supply of water to social institutions and installation at different points in settlements to provide the population with water in case of a lack of water supply, as well as an emergency stock of water to HHs or small premises, e.g. bomb shelters.
It is planned to reach 52,741 people with assistance, including 7,120 people with disabilities.
During the project implementation, there might be some challenges related to increased escalation of hostilities, security, access to project locations, procurement and legal obstacles. In this regard, special attention will be paid to risks management. For that purpose, a detailed analysis of potential risks, indicating proposed mitigation measures have been elaborated. 
NEW WAY (NW) is planning to implement the project on its own. NW is a local NGO that continues activities started in 2016 by German NGO arche noVa. Over the years, NW has become a noticeable actor in the WASH sector, supporting the conflict-affected population through the implementation of relief projects in eastern Ukraine. Furthermore, NW has expertise in the implementation of social infrastructure rehabilitation projects, including the health sector. In particular, similar projects have been implemented with about 5000 individual and institutional hygiene kits distributed, 36 generators provision to educational and healthcare institutions with power from 5 kW to 100 kW, and water and sewage infrastructure rehabilitation in more than 50 settlements of Donetska and Luhanska oblasts.
There is a well-established structure as well as necessary technical and support staff in place to oversee the implementation of the project activities. There is a clear awareness of the local context as well as principles of the humanitarian response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Foundation &#x201C;NEW WAY&#x201D;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Foundation &#x201C;NEW WAY&#x201D;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Andriy Kryvchenkov</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Foundation</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380664606448</telephone>
   <email>akryvchenkov.newway@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lina Potaeva</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance  Administration Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380953919791</telephone>
   <email>lpotaeva.newway@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UA14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donetska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.04731497 37.67411990</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="12" percentage="5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coordination and Support Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="11" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="7" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="77" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-02"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-06"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-06">871339.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-21903">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-06">871339.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Foundation &#x201C;NEW WAY&#x201D;</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
