<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-22/UKR_CBPF/RA2/H-P-FSL/INGO/21718</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency multi-sectoral response to the urgent needs of vulnerable populations affected by the Ukraine Crisis</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 24 February 2022, Russia launched a full-scale military operation in Ukraine, with aerial, ground and sea incursions leading to multiple fronts of conflict throughout the country. With 2.9 million people already in need of humanitarian and protection assistance in eastern Ukraine prior to the offensive, the humanitarian situation has since drastically deteriorated. The intensity of the fighting, and notably the indiscriminate airstrikes hitting civilians and civilian infrastructures, continue to trigger fear and large-scale displacement inside Ukraine and to neighbouring countries, while simultaneously exacerbating the humanitarian needs of those who are internally displaced or remain in heavily affected areas &#x2013; noting increasing reports of the most vulnerable people, including people with disabilities and older persons, being left behind. A month after the launch of Russian military operations, more than 10.2 million people have already been displaced by the conflict, amongst whom 4.3 million children, including 3.7 million refugees and 6.5 million IDPs. Between 24 February and 23 March, the OHCHR recorded 2,685 civilian casualties, including 1,035 people killed -figures likely much higher, as civilian deaths and injuries continue to be verified. In besieged Mariupol alone, the death toll is estimated at more than 2,350 people and potentially &#x201C;twice higher&#x201D;. Most of these casualties were caused by the use of explosive weapons with a wide impact area, including shelling from heavy artillery and multiple launch rocket systems as well as airstrike. The country&apos;s health minister said that Russian forces have shelled 135 hospitals and damaged 43 ambulances, WHO having verified 64 attacks on health care since 24 February. Some areas have suffered critical shortages of medical supplies. WHO warns that attacks on medical facilities are becoming strategies of war. In Mariupol, where 100,000 people would reportedly still trapped, the UN warns of a critical and potentially fatal shortage of food, water, and medicine. Since the beginning of March, several attempts have been made to evacuate people and set up &quot;humanitarian corridors&quot;, but few have been successful. It is estimated that 13 million persons are stranded or trapped in areas of Ukraine where they cannot reach safety.
In light of the rapid and continued deterioration of the crisis, severe humanitarian impact and limited capacities in country to respond to the exponential crisis at hand, emergency surge capacities have been called upon to support the response. 
Building upon our close monitoring of the situation in Ukraine since January 2022, our solid historical presence in the Balkans as well as our strong experience in conflict settings and volatile security contexts across various parts of the world, Handicap International - Humanity amp Inclusion (HI) is currently re-establishing a Programme in Ukraine and surrounding countries, with teams deployed on the Ukraine Crisis since 1 March 2022. HI teams are currently focusing on launching activities in Chernivtsi, Vinnytsia, Oujhorod and Dnipro, whilst furthering assessments in the East of the country and along the Slovakia and Hungary borders inside Ukraine. Through this project, HI aims to reduce the suffering of vulnerable conflict-affected populations through the delivery of an inclusive, immediate and multi-sectoral humanitarian response addressing the Health, Basic Needs and Protection of conflict-affected populations, with specific focus on IDPs, refugees, persons with disabilities/injuries and/or with signs of psychological distress, while reducing the risks caused by Explosive Ordnance (EO) contamination and supporting the wider humanitarian response to be more inclusive. HI will work on both sides of the shifting &apos;contact line&apos;, adapting its modalities as the context evolves in eastern and western Ukraine.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fanny Mraz</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+33 761007567</telephone>
   <email>f.mraz@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UA73">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chernivetska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.26819792 25.97702081</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="UA12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dnipropetrovska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.41701338 34.73173409</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="UA05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vinnytska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.92044212 28.68553580</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="UA21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zakarpatska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.40361980 23.27591388</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="39" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="39" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="22" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-25">1500000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-21718">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-25">1500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
