<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-22/HSD20/RA1/WASH/NGO/21587</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency WASH services to dry-spell affected people in South Darfur</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to FAO, low rainfall in terms of distribution and frequency have affected parts of North Kordofan, Central Darfur and South Darfur states.  These dry spells are likely to exacerbate the food security, nutrition and livelihood situation further. There is a risk of social tension and conflicts due to increased competition for resources. The suspension of over 2.7 billion USD in economic support from the international community, low foreign exchange reserves, limited economic activity, and continued political instability likely resulted in the depreciation of the SDG in the parallel market from 450 SDG/USD in December 2021 to 490 SDG/USD by the third week of January 2022. The persistent lack of access to sustainable hard currency streams is likely to result in the SDG further depreciating. The increases in food and transportation prices (50-100 percent greater than last year), and the cost of the local food basket (over 120 percent greater than last year), are negatively impacting the purchasing power of poor households. 
By mid-January 2022, staple food prices continued increasing typically in most markets while remaining stable or slightly decreasing in other markets. Stable food prices are approximately 100-200 percent higher than last year and three to four times greater than the five-year average. 
The limited economic activity has also led to deteriorating WASH situation in these areas coupled with non-functional and aging WASH infrastructure and poor budget allocation. 
Displaced people in Darfur have revealed signs of famine and a great shortage of food and water, warning of catastrophic effects in the absence of appropriate aid . These areas also have poor water infrastructure. 
In South Darfur, Nitega, Kass and Edel fursan localities witnessed unpredictable stability situation in the last 2 two years compare to East Jebel Mara which was hit by the Darfur crisis and part of it is controlled by Sudan liberation Army Abdel-Wahid (SLA/AW) difficult to access but possible after primary contact with the Humanitarian responsible of SLA. Previous inter tribal conflict occurred in 2020 in EJM resulted to a big number of population displacements in several settlements in and around Jebel Mara and some of them started return back to their home villages.
The 3 localities are accessible with no grater insecurity challenges. The average of rainfall of last year 2021 was reduced to less than 35% from the natural average of last 10 years in the region and this caused an important shortage of food due to the poor harvest.   A total of 659,087 of IDPs, returnees and host communities  in the 4 localities named: Nitega,Kass, Edel Fursan and East Jabel Marrah have difficulties to get sufficient water for their families and animals consumption. A number of 380 existing hand pumps in the 4 localities are now out of use. The project will intend to immediately maintain the hand pumps and the mini water yard to provide enough and clean water for the vulnerable population in the areas.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       - 50,000 nomads with their animals are getting water and hygiene services.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    - 20,000 travelers passing the water points are having WASH services including water for themselves and their animals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Great Family Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Great Family Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Eltahir Asil</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249911363097</telephone>
   <email>gfamily.organization@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jamal Hamad El Nieel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249123883084</telephone>
   <email>jhamad57@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.64886390 24.90422080</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-25"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-03">496788.47</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-21587">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-03">496788.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Great Family Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305668283">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-05">397430.78</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Great Family Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
