<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-16/3884/S/E/INGO/3971</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of  immediate access to inclusive safe and protected learning environments that promote psychosocial well being of afffected boys and girls  fleeing from Mosul in Ninewa Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project will provide support to newly displaced IDP children and adolescents boys and girls (aged 6 -18 years) fleeing conflict affected areas with Education in Emergencies (EiE) intervention in line with Education Cluster&apos;s minimum assistance first and second-line education response package outlined in the 2016 HRP. Through its education services, War Child UK (WCUK) will provide an age appropriate and gender sensitive non-formal education program for 6000 displaced boys and girls. The project will primarily target newly-arriving IDPs fleeing from Mosul in camps and in locations where informal settlements are established. Though the exact locations will be determined once the camps are established and IDPs arrive, the two locations currently identified are Tilkaif District, and Sheikhan District in the Ninewa Governorate. WCUK prioritised the Ninewa governorate as planning documents predict that the governorate is likely to receive a considerable portion of IDP&#x2019;s fleeing Mosul and its surrounding areas. However, as the context is fluid and subject to a number of external variables, the exact location selection is flexible within these two locations. The services provided will increase the access of boys and girls affected by conflict to quality, safe and protective learning environments, mainstreaming gender sensitive and child protection approaches, ensuring that the intervention is specific to their needs. WCUK will establish 8 Temporary Learning Spaces (TLS) to provide education services to children. WCUK will work closely with national and local education authorities to explore using existing school structures and bridge, where possible, the transition into the formal education system to ensure sustainability, strengthen the capacity and resilience. 40 education personnel will be recruited from the local community through a participatory and transparent process , based on selection criteria reflecting diversity and equity. All education personnel will be trained EiE , psychosocial support (PSS) and Psychological First Aid (PFA ) to promote the psychosocial wellbeing of affected boys and girls. Community outreach campaigns and community education committees will be established to promote learning, ensure community participation, transparency, accountability and equitable delivery of education. WCUK&#x2019;s TLS &#x2019;s will serve as an entry point for children and adolescents to be identified and WCUK will engage with CP partners to establish effective referral pathways for at risk boys and girls. WCUK will routinely conduct monitoring and evaluation in its areas of intervention to ensure its services are relevant to the needs of the population. 
As WCUK is one of the key agencies responding to Education and CP needs in Iraq, WCUK&#x2019;s first and second line response has been developed in close consultation with the respective clusters and has framed this intervention in line with the Education Cluster Strategy. With over 12 years implementation experience in Iraq WCUK is familiar with the context and is accustomed to implementing projects in challenging environments, including the Syria response. WCUK recently implemented a similar project in Anbar which provided services for IDPs from Ramadi and Falluja. WCUK will draw upon lessons learned in the Anbar intervention to guide its Mosul response as well as sector specific best practice and minimum standards. WCUK has allocated a modest fund to initiate the first line response and has already begun preparing and procuring for the response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sameena Gul</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964 751 5210991</telephone>
   <email>sameeng@warchild.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-07">81848.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-08-29"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-07">318151.88</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-3971">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-07">400000.08</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302289721">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-15">240000.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303211803">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-07">159999.66</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
