<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-16/3884/R/CCCM/UN/3158</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building local capacity to create safe and livable environment and responding to the most urgent IDP Camp care and maintenance needs through CCCM mobile teams in Central Iraq</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM will conduct a variety of CCCM trainings and joint Camp maintenance activities for a minimum of 4 formal IDP camps in Anbar governorate. As a note, specific camp names are not available at this time, as the cluster has not developed an updated map.

Building upon ongoing CCCM projects in Anbar, where IOM already provides CCCM response in 8 formal and 20 informal Camps, IOM, in the 4 additional camps under this project, will train government officials engaged in Camp Management and IDP camp representatives, in the foundations of CCCM response. IOM will also carry out minimal Camp maintenance, in coordination with IDPs, through on the job training on care and maintenance activities. IDPs will also receive toolkits, to carry out ongoing maintenance after the finalization of the project. All activities, for the 4 proposed camps, will be implemented by 1 CCCM Mobile Team, made up of 3 staff members. 

Throughout all interventions, IOM will ensure that the needs of the most vulnerable, including Female-Headed Households (FHH), Youth-Headed Households (YHH), Pregnant and Lactating Women (PLW), and IDPs living with a physical disability and/or chronic disease are prioritized. CCCM activities will include: 

a) Selection of IDP Camp Representatives in each camp. Through community consultations, the CCCM Mobile Team will select 5 IDPs per camp, to form 2 teams: a Camp Management Team (2 people) responsible for community engagement and governance, and a Camp Maintenance Team (3 people) responsible for camp care and maintenance.   Both teams, as well as government officials and other community group leaders will receive one formal training in CCCM response.  

b) Camp Management Teams and Camp Maintenance Teams (20 IDPs total) provided with On-the-Job Training (OJT) in Camp governance, care and maintenance. 

c) Implementation of joint Camp maintenance actions (by CCCM Mobile Team and Camp Maintenance Team), responding to risks and hazards identified inside the Camp. This can include repairing of tents and caravans, fire mitigation activities, replacement of WASH infrastructure, etc. This activity aims both to improve camp conditions, and build the capacity of the Camp Maintenance Team.
 
d) A least 4 IDP community groups established in each camp. This includes the aforementioned Camp Management Teams (CMgT) and Camp Maintenance Teams (CMnT), as well as Women&#x2019;s Empowerment Groups (WEG), and Youth Empowerment Groups (YEG). Additionally, a Camp Safety Committee (CSC) may be established, where necessary, to support the activities of the Camp Maintenance Team through monitoring risks and hazards inside the camp. The establishment of these groups will ensure IDPs in selected camps have a voice and can participate in management and camp maintenance alongside government camp management staff. 

e) Awareness campaigns conducted on camp care and maintenance, with a focus on health and safety. Campaigns can include fire safety, camp clean-up and safe electricity use. 

f) Routine monitoring of informal and formal camps conducted to identify potential threat and needs and ensure referrals, where necessary.  

Furthermore, IOM will incorporate gender mainstreaming into all activities, assessing the specific needs of men, women, boys, and girls, and designing tailored interventions to meet the specific needs of all populations. Camps will be selected in coordination with the CCCM cluster and government authorities using the Iraq CCCM prioritization tool developed jointly with the Protection, WASH, and Shelter/NFI clusters to choose priority camps, specifically targeting where the government has urgent capacity building needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daihei Mochizuki</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter  Settlements/CCCM Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964-0750-021-1730</telephone>
   <email>dmochizuki@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Anbar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.90000000 41.60000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-11">251168.85</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-11">148718.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-3158">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-11">399887.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302043529">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-16">399887.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
