<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-16/3884/ST/P/INGO/2610</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Facilitating the provision of lifesaving, specialized Child Protection services to extremely vulnerable children in hard to reach and underserved locations in Anbar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will provide lifesaving, specialised Child Protection (CP) services to extremely vulnerably girls and boys in hard to reach and underserved areas of Anbar. The project will mainly target existing and newly arriving IDPs and 5% host community in non-camp, camp and informal tented settlements in and around Habaniya, Amirat al-Fallujah and Khaldia, since these areas are both hard to reach and critically underserved in terms of CP specialised service provision and will also reach out to other areas where newly displaced IDPs may be settled, if and when they are accessible. The services provided will be lifesaving, whilst also being tailored to the varying needs of the boys and girls, so that they are gender sensitive, age appropriate and specific to their needs. War Child will be the overall lead for this project and will work in partnership with the local NGO Afkar, who have been working in the area for over 10 years and so have good knowledge of the area and rapport at community level. War Child will undertake the capacity building of the partner NGO through intensive training and on the job mentoring in specialised CP service provision in order to support field based implementation, which will be undertaken by the national NGO. While the project will provide specialized CP services to the affected target group, it also aims to build the capacity of local organisations for continuity of these critical services that are currently not available or not to the extent needed in Anbar. Project planning, beneficiary selection, developing criteria for beneficiary selection, MampE planning and clarity on roles and responsibilities of the War Child and Afkar will all be done jointly at the outset of the project. The services provided by Afkar consist of first and second line response: the provision of lifesaving information, education and communication (IEC) about CP, available services and referral pathways for 7,500 boys and girls supporting the implementation of Rapid Protection Assessments (RPAs) through CP Focal Points screening for grave violations against children through the UN&apos;s Monitoring and Reporting Mechanism (MRM) providing Psychological First Aid (PFA) and emergency referral to external services to 150 newly displaced children and adolescents providing targeted Psychosocial Support (PSS) through emotional support groups to 2,250 children and adolescents identifying and documenting Unaccompanied and Separated Children (UASC), providing emergency alternative care arrangements and linking with UNHCR and ICRC for family retracing, reunification and Best Interest Determinations (BIDs) providing case management and emergency referrals to external services to 180 children and implementing 3 safety audits to promote child safeguarding and CP within the community. WCUK will build the capacity of 100 NGO staff, service providers and duty-bearers in the provision of specialised CP services, as well as in security management in conflict settings. The latter is important since Anbar is a relatively insecure operating environment and the project is working through mobile, as well as static teams, so as to access hard to reach areas and newly displaced IDPs. This project will be implemented through PSS Workers, CP Outreach Workers, Case Workers and Case Managers, CP Technical Advisor, MEAL Officer and Security Officer, plus other project management and support staff, to ensure the smooth implementation of the project and compliance with donor policies and procedures. Donor reporting/ coordination with humanitarian agencies will be War Child&apos;s responsibility. MampE will be from War Child&apos;s office in Baghdad, which will also be complemented by weekly and monthly visits to the field for on-going mentoring support to Afkar&apos;s field staff in Anbar, oversee implementation and resolve challenges together at field level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afkar Society for Relief and Human Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Khamis Salih</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afkar Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+9647512279610</telephone>
   <email>eng.cmcv@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Anbar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.90000000 41.60000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-12">284333.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-12">165655.31</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-2610">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-12">449989.04</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301831804">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-24">269993.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303213786">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-08">179995.61</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
