<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-16/3884/ST/H/INGO/2569</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved Access to Essential and Basic Lifesaving Health Care Services with Provision of Essential medical supplies and Strengthened Surveillance Systems targeting displaced and vulnerable people in Anbar Governorate, Iraq.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RI&apos;s proposed intervention builds upon RI&#x2019;s existing health interventions in Anbar, Baghdad and Salahaldin Governorates with funding from HPF and ECHO. This intervention will provide continuation of ongoing life-saving assistance while ensuring access to essential and quality health care services for displaced and vulnerable individuals in a manner that is accountable, conflict-sensitive and supports the government&apos;s responsibility as the first responder. RI coordinates with the Health Cluster, WHO and UNFPA in responding to the HRP  minimum essential health service package, prioritizing the first-line response with front-line service delivery. This will always ensure access to essential, life-saving medicines, consumables, and equipment, including for reproductive health, for vulnerable populations.  RI will give priority to newly displaced persons or where displacement is expected imminently in Anbar governorate. The mobile health response proposed will maintain flexibility to reach areas west of Ramadi such as Kilo 18 and other new locations with concentrations of newly displaced IDPs. The selection of locations remains flexible and responds to immediate health needs.

This critical and life-saving response will be carried out through support to Four mobile medical teams (MMT) in hard-to-reach or/and front-line areas where there are no other operational health facilities . In addition, RI will also support one primary health centers (PHC) currently supported by RI near the Bzeibez bridge in Al Asfar Camp in Amriyat Falluja (AF) with many newly displaced population from the recent Ramadi crisis making up the catchment population and having gap in medical staffs and supplies, Being the only health actor in that area RI considers support to this facility fits the first line response in line with the strategic objectives of the health cluster. RI will provide equipment and supplies to the supported MMTs, as well as training and incentives to the health facility (HF) staff, in order to ensure that qualified staff are able to provide quality health care service. RI supported MMTs are designed to have a link with PHC in order to ease referrals and facilitate the necessary support to the field team. The proposed project will be the continuation of the RI&apos;s ongoing emergency and basic health care services and services provided includes treatment of common illnesses, management of injuries, reproductive health care services, maternal and child health care, health education, provision of essential medicines, control of communicable diseases within the community, and strengthening of the existing referral system. RI will also continue providing technical capacity and support as necessary to the medical teams in order to provide high-quality care. RI Mobile Medical Team will maintain a level of flexibility that allows changes in location based on needs within Anbar governorate and in close coordination with the DOH and other health actors.
RI seeks to provide urgent medical assistance to 28,800 internal displaced persons (IDPs) located in Anbar governorate of Iraq. The project will cover AF, Rahaliya and recently liberated and hard to reach areas in Ramadi, and Khalidiya which has high number of IDPs and gaps in provision of health care services while also identifying remote and isolated locations where there are high concentrations of vulnerable IDPs especially areas where conflicts continues to escalate. The project will look at expanding coverage and deepening humanitarian response in the areas RI already has programming presence and community acceptance in order to meet the existing and rapidly growing needs in target areas. 
RI will ensure that this intervention is not only responsive to the unique health needs of women and girls, but also takes into account the concerns and priorities of boys and men, which may vary, and will work to ensure that clinics and MMTs are accessible and welcoming to persons with disabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-25" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Harriet Calis</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Manager - Middle East</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 962 77 84 00 761</telephone>
   <email>harriet.calis@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Randhir Singh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0751 014 8987</telephone>
   <email>randhir@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Steven Pertric</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+9647512448514</telephone>
   <email>steven.petric@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Anbar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.90000000 41.60000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-05-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-11-25"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-26">500000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-2569">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-26">500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301843417">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-31">400000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302645291">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-08">91136.69</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
