<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-16/3884/S/WASH/INGO/3735</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SP Mosul Emergency WASH Preparedness</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thousands of families that are expected to flee to the Ninewah Zone during the Mosul operation will have no camp to settle in should the crisis happen in the near-term. SP proposes a 90 day preparedness project providing emergency WASH supplies and facilities for 1000 IDP families in temporary living sites or emergency camps for a 30 day time period. (Phase 1 in the Contingency Plan). 60 days of funding for preparation and pre-positioning will allow SP to immediately begin building teams, renting warehouse space, and pre-positioning supplies.  These teams and supplies will be used for provision of water and emergency water facilities, construction of emergency and long-term latrines, desludging/excreta disposal, hygiene kit distribution, hygiene promotion, solid waste management, and surface water management for 1,000 families over a 30 day time period.

In the case that IDPs are already on-site when SP arrives, the response phase will have a 3-day emergency phase followed by a 27 day construction phase.  The first 3-days will include an initial assessment, construction of emergency pit latrines, water trucking, and hygiene kit distribution.  The initial assessment will target key information for constructing WASH facilities like the number of families in each location and the availability of water and sanitary facilities.  One emergency pit latrine will be constructed for every 50 individuals already on-site, up to 6,000 individuals.  These pit latrines will be pre-fabricated steel tubing structures that can be assembled on-site, which suspend Samaritan&apos;s Purse provided latrine slabs over a 0.5 meter, 0.5 meter deep trench.  The steel structures will be wrapped in Samaritan&apos;s Purse provided tarp for walls.  Water trucking will provide a minimum of 5 liters per person per day for all of the individuals already on-site, up to 6,000 individuals.  One family hygiene kit containing basic items like soap and laundry detergent as well as some feminine hygiene supplies will be distributed to every family already on-site, up to 1,000 families.  The field engineers and contracted backhoe operators will grade the site and spread gravel as needed to prevent standing water from accumulating.

Higher quality facilities and more specialized care will be provided following the first 3-day response.  One sandwich-panel type latrine and shower will be installed for every 50 individuals over the next 27 days.  These latrines will be flushed and the showers will be used with buckets to ensure a quick response and to help regulate appropriate water use during the emergency phase.  Families can use the buckets they receive from the UNICEF rapid response mechanism to flush the toilets and take baths using water from the tap stands.  The 24 water storage tanks and 48 tap stands will be installed, and a minimum of 15 liters of water per person per day will be trucked to the site and used to fill the tanks.  One baby hygiene kit will be distributed to every family every 14 days.   Hygiene Promotion teams will distribute and post hygiene messaging materials, conduct hygiene promotion sessions, distribute garbage bags, and survey displaced families on gaps in services and their specialized needs.  Fenced-off garbage disposal areas will be constructed a safe distance away from family dwellings and a contractor will be hired to collect and appropriately dispose of solid waste as needed.  Special care will be given to ensure the protection of women, young children, and those with handicaps.

One Monitoring and Evaluation officer designated to the project will record the completed activities at the end of each day from the team leaders, and collect and compile the surveys from the hygiene team.  A final report will be compiled and submitted 5 days after the end of the 30 day response phase, including the data from the initial assessment and surveys, the completed number of each activity, and the corresponding status of each indicator and outcome.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samaritan&apos;s Purse International Relief /SPIR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samaritan&apos;s Purse International Relief /SPIR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Matthew nowery</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+96407707768625</telephone>
   <email>MNowery@samaritan.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-27">88186.18</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-11-01"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-27">401444.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-3735">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-27">489630.75</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samaritan&apos;s Purse International Relief /SPIR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302270216">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-07">244815.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samaritan&apos;s Purse International Relief /SPIR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303241075">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-26">234166.82</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samaritan&apos;s Purse International Relief /SPIR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
