<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-16/3884/S/WASH/INGO/3694</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing life-saving WASH assistance to internally displaced and critically affected vulnerable families (women, men, girls  boys) in Mosul corridor, Iraq.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first line emergency WASH response will target 9,600 beneficiaries (1600HH) newly displaced and critically at risk women, men, boys and girls along the Mosul corridor in Potential Emergency Camps in Qayyarah sub district (Oxfam is flexible in terms of location based on need and gaps identified by WASH cluster and other actors). The project will support 100% emergency preparedness and response once the displacement happen and Oxfam will follow WASH cluster response guidelines against settlement typology during the response. Oxfam WASH response will be led by a highly flexible, mobile rapid response team in place to meet immediate water, sanitation amp hygiene needs in a timely manner to save lives of newly displaced people.

To respond to the immediate WASH needs of the newly displaced people and as a part of emergency preparedness for the expected large scale emergency in Mosul, Oxfam will focus on the pre-positioning of WASH supplies and first line response (Full WASH package). To provide access to safe drinking water of appropriate quality, Oxfam will do water trucking for 30 days to ensure access to at least 15 lppd of water. To ensure supplied water is potable/ fit for human consumption Oxfam will conduct water quality analysis/monitoring and will do chlorination at source level where necessary. To reduce contamination of water and improve safe storage of water at community and HH level, Oxfam will install 30 communal water tanks and will distribute jerry cans with a 20 liter capacity. To prevent open defecation and to reduce public health risks to newly displaced people, Oxfam will install 202 emergency latrines. Separate latrines for women and men will be designated and the doors of latrines will be lockable from inside to ensure protection and safety of women and children. Latrines for people with disabilities (PWD) will also be installed. Gender segregated 192 emergency bathing facilities will also be installed to ensure availability of bathing space for women and children near to their dwellings. To increase hygiene awareness in the targeted communities and to reduce risks to water amp vector borne diseases during emergency, Oxfam will conduct 200 hygiene promotion sessions along with water supply amp sanitation activities. Hygiene sessions will be carried out through hygiene volunteers. 10 volunteers will be identified from the targeted communities, who will be trained on basic hygiene promotion in emergencies amp community mobilization. Male volunteers will conduct session with men amp children, female volunteers with women amp children to ensure gender specific hygiene concerns are discussed during the sessions. Oxfam will follow WASH cluster guidelines for distribution of WASH NFIs. To mitigate risks to vector borne diseases in emergencies, Oxfam will ensure proper disposal amp management of the solid waste in the targeted area. Oxfam&apos;s hygiene promotion and engineering staff will work with volunteers, local elders and municipality to raise awareness about proper waste management procedures and mechanisms. Oxfam will distribute 10 cleaning kits and in order to promote additional environmental protection, 30 clean up campaigns will be organized through participatory approaches, involving WASH committees, local municipalities, the local community and community elders. For cleaning campaigns labor will be recruited from targeted communities using cash for work approach to provide livelihood opportunities to most affected people.

WASH activities will be integrated with proposed Oxfam food security amp livelihood (FSL), protection and MPCA activities in the targeted locations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-25" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Bilal</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country WASH Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>009647733489094</telephone>
   <email>Mbilal@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sarah Deed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Funding Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00964 7502463420</telephone>
   <email>SDeed1@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-31">243024.35</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-31">304687.25</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-3694">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-31">547711.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302289720">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-15">438169.28</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303001208">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-15">109518.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-27">0</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
