<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-16/3884/S/E/INGO/3746</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing access to emergency education and child protection services for school-aged IDP children in Northern Iraq.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is to provide immediate access to inclusive, safe and protective learning environments to 3,000 IDP girls and boys displaced due to the military operations to retake Mosul City. Displaced children and youth will benefit from quality and life-sustaining learning through non-formal education, psychosocial support and child protection services provided by trained educators. 
The proposed project aims to enhance the capacity of the education actors to provide assistance to the newly displaced children, addressing their education needs with a harmonized approach based on the adapted Education in Emergencies modules and INEE Standards, as well as of PIN Emergency team to effectively collect and analyze data.

The key project activities aiming to enhance preparedness to provide emergency education to IDP school-aged children will include: procurement of equipment to set-up 15 mobile child friendly/temporary learning spaces (TLS) incl. winterization measures needed in the TLSs to secure and better accommodate the 3,000 targeted children, recreational kits, school-in-a-box kits and other scholastic materials, etc. In terms of capacity development, the project will target 50 women and men selected from national and international NGOs and governmental departments such as DoE (Department of Education) and DoLSA (Department of Labour and Social Affairs) who will attend a five-day Training for Trainers (ToT) on Education in Emergencies (EiE) methodologies and tools. The ToT will include modules on contextualized INEE Standards, Psychosocial Support (PSS), Psychological First Aid (PFA), life skills, positive discipline, Mine Risk Education (MRE), Child Protection and Child Protection referral pathways. The training will be held twice during the project implementation period, targeting 25 people with each session, to better include the new education actors who will arrive in KR-I when the Mosul operation starts. Additional 10 members of PIN Emergency response team will also be trained on how to conduct emergency needs assessment, post distribution monitoring, evaluation surveys, on data collection and evaluation, and on how and when to use KoBo toolkit for a more efficient monitoring and evaluation of the project activities.

As overall activity within this project, considering the role of PIN as a co-chair of the Education Dohuk sub-cluster, will be promotion of a coordinated and harmonized response to the educational needs of the newly displaced and accessible (considering the security situation) communities, thus the project includes contextualization, printing and dissemination of Education in Emergencies training modules and promotion of contextualized INEE Minimum Standards for Education in Emergencies modules among education stakeholders (national and international NGOs, UN agencies and governmental departments), which will be than delivered through a workshop to directly 20 education and child protection workers and indirectly to all their colleagues.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-10" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maciej Perczynski</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964 (0)751 524 6855</telephone>
   <email>hom.iraq@peopleinneed.cz</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G09">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dahuk</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.86739100 42.99885800</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-19">128698.59</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-19">73286.7</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-3746">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-19">201985.29</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302242341">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-24">201985.29</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
