<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-16/3884/ST/NFIs/INGO/2661</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency Shelter and NFI Support to Vulnerable IDPs in Anbar and Ninewa Governorates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through this six month initiative, ACTED will provide together with its local partner UIMS, a first-line response of Shelter and NFIs in Anbar and Ninewa in order to ensure that vulnerable IDP families have 1) access to shelter conditions meeting minimum standards, and 2) access to essential seasonal appropriate NFIs. These activities will take place in both camp and non-camp locations in Anbar and Ninewa via three mobile teams pre-positioned in the area, with items stocked respectively in Baghdad and Dohuk. The proposed project will be implemented by ACTED staff in Ninewa governorate and by UIMS, ACTED&#x2019;s local partner in Anbar. 

ACTED will target 2000 beneficiaries in Anbar, including 540 women, 520 men, 480 girls and 460 boys. In Ninewa, 1000 beneficiaries will be targeted, including 270 women, 260 men, 240 girls and 230 boys, in order to ensure they have access to shelter and essential NFIs. Activities will include distribution of Single Room Sealing Off Kits (SRSoKs) out-of camps, which will include 2 pieces of exterior grade plywood, galvanised steel nails, 4 pieces of square cut timbers, construction adhesive for wood/concrete/metal, binding wire and tools (a hammer, a saw, a plier and a caulking gun) as well as distributions of NFIs in and out-of-camps. ACTED will ensure flexibility of the SRSoKs as materials will distributed depending on the structure of the households assessed, thus on a case by case basis to ensure meeting needs of the targeted beneficiaries. The NFI Mobile kit will be distributed, where applicable, in combination with RRM kits in Ninewa&#x2019;s districts where ACTED is either the main or backup RRM partner. The kit has been designed to improve living conditions of critical shelters where beneficiaries are expected to reside for a period of up to two weeks.

The NFI kit proposed has been standardised across Shelter-NFIs cluster partners and will be piloted during this intervention, thus allowing agencies a certain flexibility over the times to be distributed in order to adapt them as much as possible to the needs of beneficiaries as these are further identified. The kit was agreed on among partners by identifying current needs of IDPs, lesson learnt and past experiences in the areas of interventions. It will include 3 thermal roll mats, 2 pieces of tarpaulin, bed sheets in summer and blankets during the winter season, a kitchen set composed of a cooking pot, a picnic blanket, a can opener, a wooden spoon, scissors, bowls, spoons, forks and cups for a family of 6 and a gas stove, a first aid kit, 2 solar lanterns, 2 collapsible jerry cans, a washing bowl, duct tape and a 40mt long rope. The kit has been designed to provide an effective first line response that would cover essential NFIs needs of the beneficiaries for a period up to two weeks. Additionally, the kit is mobile in nature, as it is composed of easy-to-transport items that in case of further displacement will be able to be carried around.

Lastly, the proposed activities are part of a mobile intervention, which includes a comprehensive approach that will respond not only to Shelter and Non-Food Items (NFIs) needs but also to WASH, Protection and Camp Coordination and Camp Management (CCCM). This multi-sectoral approach aims to respond to the current crisis in Anbar and to prepare for the eventual influx of IDPs in Ninewa following the liberation of Mosul city as well as the current needs of IDPs in the area. ACTED will also monitor all its distribution activities and carry out a Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM) in order to assess the impact these activities have on beneficiaries. This will be shared with the Shelter and NFI Cluster to share information and lesson learnt with all the partners.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The United Iraqi Medical Society for Relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-03" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lorene Tamain</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+33 14 265 3333</telephone>
   <email>lorene.tamain@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Raphael Capony</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964 (0)7 51 501 873</telephone>
   <email>raphael.capony@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Anbar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.90000000 41.60000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-01">186733.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-01">63264.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-2661">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-01">249998.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301855442">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-07">249998.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
