<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-HVA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transition to High Value Agriculture Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rehabilitation of up to 11 irrigation systems servicing up to 15,500 hectares to facilitate transition to high value agriculture. Technical assistance to support the establishment of water user associations that will be legally responsible for O&amp;M of the systems. Financing for post harvest infrastructure and technical assistance for farmers and agribusiness.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Moldova</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/evalbrief-092019-moldova-agr-int">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Removing Barriers to High-Value Agriculture in Moldova</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://data.mcc.gov/evaluations/index.php/catalog/166">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transition to High Value Agriculture</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-HVA-0329" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-HVA-0330" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-HVA-0331" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-HVA-0332" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-ROAD REHAB" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">13. Prior to signing the detailed design studies contract for the Centralized Irrigation System Rehabilitation Activity, unless MCC agrees otherwise in writing, the Government will have delivered documentation acceptable to MCC evidencing publication in the ?Monitorul Oficial? of a WUA Law in form and substance acceptable to MCC and in compliance with international best practices, which law will be in full force and effect no later than three (3) months after the date of publication. (PIA Schedule 2, 2(a))</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Prior to the release of invitations for bids for any construction works contract for the Centralized Irrigation System Rehabilitation Activity, unless MCC agrees otherwise in writing, (i) at least five (5) centralized irrigation systems will have WUAs registered under the WUA Law, (ii) the Government will have delivered documentation acceptable to MCC that all systems included in any construction contract will have WUAs registered under the WUA Law (which documentation may include a copy of the state registration certificate that evidences legal registration of each WUA, and a copy of the WUA registration package including appropriate WUA foundation documentation and charter), and (iii) the construction package(s) will be acceptable to MCC. (PIA Schedule 2, 2(b))</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">15. Prior to the release of invitations for bids for any construction works contract for the Centralized Irrigation System Rehabilitation Activity, unless MCC agrees otherwise in writing, the Government will have delivered documentation acceptable to MCC evidencing publication in the ?Monitorul Oficial? of a Water Law in form and substance acceptable to MCC and in compliance with international best practices, including the provision of water rights for a minimum of twelve (12) years. (PIA Schedule 2, 2(c))</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">16. Prior to the Disbursement of MCC Funding for the release of monitoring equipment specified under the River Basin Management Sub-Activity, the Government will have completed the in-kind contribution of operational and secure structures, subject to MCC assessment and approval, for housing the new equipment specified under the River Basin Management Sub-Activity. (PIA Schedule 2, 2(d))</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">17. The aggregate amount of MCC Funding to be disbursed for the Access to Agricultural Finance Activity will not exceed: (i) three and one-half million United States Dollars (US$3,500,000), during the first twenty-four (24) months after commencement of such Activity; and (ii) four and one-half million United States Dollars (US$4,500,000) during the first thirty-four (34) months after commencement of such Activity; provided that, if, after the midterm review of the Activity has been conducted, MCC determines that the Activity will have an economic rate of return of at least twelve percent, or such other rate as may be acceptable to MCC in its sole discretion, additional Disbursements may be made during such time periods for the Activity, as agreed by MCC. (PIA Schedule 2, 2(e))</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">18. Prior to the Disbursement of MCC Funding for the High Value Agriculture Post-Harvest Credit Facility in connection with the Access to Agricultural Finance Activity, the Government will develop and approve a policy and procedures manual governing all aspects of such fund including its establishment and operations, which policies and procedures manual will be in form and substance satisfactory to MCC and will have been approved by MCC. (PIA Schedule 2, 2(f))</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transition to High Value Agriculture Project Results</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hectares under improved practices as a result of training?</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Outcome of Indicator for Transition to High Value Agriculture Project</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for Transition to High Value Agriculture Project Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-01"></period-end>
     <target value="8400">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for Transition to High Value Agriculture Project Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7279">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for Transition to High Value Agriculture Project Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
