<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Administration and Control</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova - Program Administration and Control project: The Accountable Entity&apos;s, the Millennium Challenge Account (MCA) Moldova, administrative costs, which include staff salaries, financial audits, and fiscal and procurement agent fees.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Moldova</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-HVA" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN-0017" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN-0021" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN-0031" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN-0059" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MDA-2750BXCOMD-ROAD REHAB" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(a) Prior to any CIF Disbursement into any Permitted Account in accordance with an approved Disbursement Request, MCA-Moldova will have delivered to MCC a complete, correct, and fully executed Disbursement Request for the relevant Disbursement Period, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC and submitted in accordance with the Reporting Guidelines.  Each Disbursement Request will include the following reference number: GR08MDA10010.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(b) (i) Each Activity being funded by such CIF Disbursement is consistent with the goal of facilitating the implementation of the Compact (ii) there has been no violation of, and the use of the requested funds for the purposes requested will not violate, the limitations on the use or treatment of (1) MCC Funding, as set forth in this Compact, including under Section 2.7, or (2) Compact Implementation Funding; and (iii) no material breach of any covenant, obligation, or responsibility of the Government or MCA-Moldova under this Compact, the Program Implementation Agreement, any supplemental agreement, or any Program Guidelines has occurred or is continuing.  MCA-Moldova will have delivered to MCC (x) evidence of the adoption and publication of the Establishment Decree, and (y) an up-to-date extract from the state registry verifying that MCA-Moldova is a fully-formed and registered public institution under the laws of Moldova.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(c) MCA-Moldova will be sufficiently mobilized in order for MCA-Moldova to be able to fully perform its obligations and to act on behalf of the Government.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(d) MCA-Moldova will have adopted a Procurement Plan, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, with respect to the Compact Implementation Funding, and such Procurement Plan remains in full force and effect.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(e) MCA-Moldova will have adopted a Fiscal Accountability Plan, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, and such Fiscal Accountability Plan remains in full force and effect.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(f) The Government will have adopted and published a decree, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, administratively implementing the tax exemption mechanism as set forth in the Compact, and such decree will remain in full force and effect.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(g) The Fiscal Agent will have been duly appointed, and MCA-Moldova will have duly executed the Fiscal Agent Agreement, and such agreement will be in full force and effect without modification, alteration, rescission, or suspension of any kind, unless otherwise agreed by MCC, and no material breach has occurred or is continuing thereunder.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(h) The Procurement Agent will have been duly appointed, and MCA-Moldova will have duly executed an agreement with the Procurement Agent, and such agreement will be in full force and effect without modification, alteration, rescission, or suspension of any kind, unless otherwise agreed by MCC, and no material breach has occurred or is continuing thereunder.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(i) The Bank will have been duly appointed, and MCA-Moldova and the Fiscal Agent will have duly executed the Bank Agreement, and such agreement will be in full force and effect without modification, alteration, rescission, or suspension of any kind, unless otherwise agreed by MCC, and no material breach has occurred or is continuing thereunder.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(j) The Permitted Account will be established.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
