<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-21/DDA-3474/PAK/H/NGO/19966</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To contribute to the government led Covid-19 response by filling up the most critical gaps in prevention, management and diagnosis in District Kohat.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In proposed project, government led COVID-19 response will be supported by filling up most critical gaps in prevention, treatment and diagnosis in district Kohat.For this, a model is proposed after the in-depth consultation with health department, WHO provincial sector leads and need and gap analysis of the ongoing COVID-19 response.The BHUs will be made &#x201C;One Stop COVID 19 PHC Centers for Prevention, Treatment and Diagnosis&#x201D; and  having multiple facilities for COVID services (Triage for early detection of suspects, basic care, testing, referrals and improving vaccination coverage at static centres, strengthening capacity of Mobile Vaccination Teams and strengthening Static Vaccination Centres by demand generation and using services of Union Councils Polio Eradication Committees/Lady Health Workers/Community Peer Groups with special focus on Afghan Refugees.Capacities of existing work &#x2018;ll be enhanced in prevention, treatment and diagnosis of COVID patients and if required steams will be strengthened by recruitment of more health workforce. This one-stop COVID PHC Centre will also share burden of populous BHUs.COVID Prevention SOPs will be instituted at BHUs and concerned BHU official will brief patients about following up SOPs and treatment including medication and isolation and if need be, referral to DHQ Hospital.Capacity of targeted health facilities will be enhanced both at primary and secondary levels by institutionalizing IPC and taking curative measures on prevailing health conditions such as communicable diseases, diarrhea, dysentery, respiratory infections (air-borne and water borne diseases).In each selected health facility, PPE kits for health staff protection along with disinfection material will be provided.
General, MNCH and reproductive health medicines will be provided to support safe deliveries.Hand-washing units will be installed in targeted BHUs and in Afghan Refugee Camps.Special focus will be given to strengthening of proper Waste Disposal Management especially of used PPEs amp other infectious material.
Trainings and capacity building activities will target 500 medical health workers from both public and private health sectors including doctors, paramedics, LHWs, LHVs, disease surveillance officers, vaccinators amp psychologists to prevent, identify and refer COVID patients to designated specialized COVID treatment centres.Training material will be provided on practicing IPC measures during antenatal amp postnatal care, safe delivery, immunization, use of modern methods of contraceptives and efficient referral mechanism.
To support women amp girls of target population, a helpline will be established for psychosocial support to post COVID Psychological Trauma. GBV cases will also be addressed through helpline for giving psychological support as well as establishing strong referral mechanism by ensuring dedicated ambulance service in targeted communities especially for emergency maternal patients.
In culturally appropriate manner, trained Social Mobilizers will conduct awareness sessions on COVID-19 prevention amp benefits of vaccination to the general public with the support of Union Council Polio Eradication Committees (UPECs)/LHWs and influentials like religious support persons, elderly and persons with disabilities and CBO&apos;s amp LSOs. Mass awareness campaign on COVID-19 will be initiated in targeted communities through dissemination of IEC materials, radio messages and cable TV adverts for acceptance and coverage of Vaccination at community level.Messages will also emphasize on prevention and control of COVID-19 i.e reduction of virus transmission, improve healthcare seeking for fever and respiratory symptoms and importance of social distancing, etc.
COVID-19 ICU at DHQ Kohat will be equipped with necessary equipment (Beds, Pulse Oximeters, O2 concentrators and Suction machines). The BHUs providing BEmONCs will be further strengthened through provision of equipment and MNCH related medicines and supplies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fakhar-ud-din</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring and Reporting Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0333 519 1048</telephone>
   <email>fakharpak@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sohail Ayaz Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief Executive Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0303 888 6666</telephone>
   <email>sohail@chef.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tahir Naseem</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0300 859 1277</telephone>
   <email>tahir.naseem@chef.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK2">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khyber Pakhtunkhwa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.48100000 72.09020000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-24">185189.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-24">108607.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-19966">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-24">293796.91</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305165888/6715">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-02">204641.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305315831">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-10">51160.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
