<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="3" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41197577-EJR2223</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41197577" secondary-reporter="0" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOS Children&apos;s Villages The Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">22/23 Ethiopia Joint Response - Implementation SOS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Across Ethiopia, 23,8 Million people are projected to be in need in 2021. Ongoing violent conflict, desert locust invasion and recurrent climatic shocks such as floods and droughts, as well as the socioeconomic impact of Covid 19 are the key drivers of humanitarian needs. Food Security and Livelihoods (including Agriculture), WASH, and Health are the sectors with the most people in need. Due to the projected increase in the number of IDPs, as a result of the ongoing conflict, unemployment, and the impact of climate change, needs are expected to increase in the coming months. The IPC Acute Food Insecurity Analysis of June 2021 concludes that in Northern Ethiopia (Tigray, Amhara and Afar), over 350,000 people were in Catastrophe (IPC 5) between May and June 2021, which is the highest number of people in IPC 5 since the 2011 Somalia Famine. 5,5 Million people (61% of the population analysed) were facing high levels of food insecurity (IPC 3 or over) and this level is predicted to be worse at the end of 2021.1
The outbreak of the Tigray conflict in Ethiopia in November 2020 had dramatic effects in the region. Telecommunications, roads, air travel, internet, electricity, banks, potable water, and other public institutions and services are not functioning, inaccessible, and/or are shut down, endangering the lives of the Tigray people. Despite the agreement between the Government of Ethiopia and the United Nations allowing humanitarian access into Tigray, humanitarian actors in practice are often denied access to the region. This severely hinders or even prevents the provision of humanitarian life-saving assistance to affected communities and IDPs, where the situation is quickly deteriorating. According to the latest UN Situation report of November 4th 2021, no humanitarian supplies have arrived in Tigray since the 18th of October. Also, the movement of humanitarian workers in and out of Tigray has been fully denied since 28th October, and movement within the surrounding regions (Amhara &amp; Afar) has been severely restricted.

SOS CV and its local partner Tesfa Birham will implement one part of the Ethiopia Joint Response, focused in the sectors FSL, Health and MPC within the following locations: Fedis woreda (Oromia region) and Efratana uidim woreda (Amhara region).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="EJR2223" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOS Children&apos;s Villages Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="EJR2223" ref="NL-KVK-41197577" role="2" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOS Children&apos;s Villages The Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="EJR2223-L" ref="NL-KVK-41197577" role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOS Children&apos;s Villages The Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">702488</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-12-31">821513</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">883482</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">884915</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Commitment SOS Ethiopia 2023">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">713481</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41197577-EJR2223" ref="NL-KVK-41197577" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SOS-Ethiopia" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Commitment SOS Ethiopia 2022">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">769482</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41197577-EJR2223" ref="NL-KVK-41197577" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SOS-Ethiopia" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1st Payment SOS Netherlands">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">239700</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41197577-EJR2223" ref="NL-KVK-41197577" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SOS-Ethiopia" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Commitment SOS NL 2023">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">821515</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41197577-EJR2223-L" ref="NL-KVK-41197577" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41197577-EJR2223" ref="NL-KVK-41197577" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Commitment SOS NL 2022">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">883480</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41197577-EJR2223-L" ref="NL-KVK-41197577" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41197577-EJR2223" ref="NL-KVK-41197577" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Primary health</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities within Oromia region:   1: Provide trainings and education to 300 community members on preventive health care
 2: Provide 150 malnourished children and lactating caregivers with need based supplementary food for 6 months
3: Provide trainings and education to 200 caregivers on the importance of nutritious food preparation
4:Support two health institutions with routine drugs
5:Identify existing gaps in health services delivery of health extension workers, and provide the HEWs with need based capacity support. 
6: Support 1800HH with two years health insurance/medication cost coverage (9,000 people)
7: Provide dignity/sanitary kits to 400 in need women and school going girls.
8: Facilitate MHPSS capacity building training to 100 local government frontline  health workers                                                                                         Activities within Amhara Region: 1:Establish and support two Mobile Health and Nutrition Teams (MHNTs)
2:Rehabilitate Anti Retro VIral Treatment (ART) centers in three health centers
3: Support six health centers with medical equipment, Construct six delivery rooms. PRovide MHPSS services to conflict affected communities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of primary health care consultations</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="41950"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of primary health care consultations</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="41950"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shortterm livelihood support</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities within Oromia region: Distribute drought resistant and locally adaptable small ruminants to restore critical livelihoods assets of 120 households (5 shoats per HH),Provide selected drought resiting seed to 200 hh, Provide capacity building trainings for 28 Rural SACCOs (RuSACCO) executive committes on fund management, Support 4 RuSACCOs with different office supplies. Provide different need based farm tools to 500HHs; Provide seed money to 75 youth and 50 caregivers to engage on feasible IGA                                                                                                     Activities within Amhara region:  Rehabilitate 100 damaged shops and shades run by young IGA promotors.    Support 100 IGA propotors through business developemnt training, advocacy with financial institutions that have given them micro credits for extened payment periods. Support the rehabilitation of 100 residential houses burnt during conflict. provision of improved seeds, agrcicultural tools and fertilizers to 800 HHS. Provision of small ruminants to 150 HHs. Support the establishment of 600 VSLAs ( Village saving and lending associations)and 10 SHGs   (Self Help groups).    Six rounds of conditional cash transfer for OVC and persons with disability   Cash for work program for 300 HHs  for three months</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people provided with resources to protect and start rebuilding livelihood assets</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10895"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National and local actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Building training for local staff and key government officials on Humanitatian Emergency Management (Safety and security; CHS)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of budget that went to national and local actors</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="49"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Building (localisation)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Building training for local staff and key government officials on Humanitatian Emergency Management (Safety and security; CHS)

Capacity building training will be given to the local implementing partner, government offices and community based organizations on Core Humanitarian standards, Cash/Voucher Assistance and resource mobilization</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of budget spent on capacity building of national an local actors</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3.14"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Building (reach)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Building training for local staff and key government officials on Humanitatian Emergency Management (Safety and security; CHS)

One local partner organization, four local government offices and and three community based organizations will be given trainings on how to mobilize responces for local emergency response interventions, CHS and CASH/Voucher assistance.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of national and local actors supported with capacity-building</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project beneficiaries and key stakeholders will play a critical role in project decision making, delivery, M&amp;E.
Gender balanced project advisory committee composed of community elders, religious leaders, representatives of local women groups, youth groups, and local health, nutrition and WASH partners, will meet on a quarterly basis. The committees will provide feedback from different community groups, discuss challenges, evolving humanitarian needs and make recommendations to the project management team on project implementation. 
Consulltation events will be organized to stimulate involvement of representatives of target communities in further program planning. Community committees will be formed in project locations, and these committees will be involved in monitoring the implementation of activities, provding feedback and in the final evaluation of the project.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of crisis-affected people who are also involved in the design, implementation, monitoring and/or evaluation of the programme</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="877"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Availability of access to and consumption of food</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of food support for 250 HHs for four months</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people enabled to meet their basic food needs</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1250"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health infrastructure rehabilitation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rehabilitation of 3 damaged health facilities including WASH and medical disposal facilities (Lechi Health center; Semien Health center and Mekelle health center); Purchase and provide routine drugs to three health facilities; Support three health centers with motor cycles and furniture</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of health facilities rehabilitated</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adaptations to JR</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will take into account feedback form beneficiaries through the hotline, suggestions boxes, community focal points and project committees. There feedack will inform the implementation and if needed adaptations will be made to the project. 

Continuous discussions will be conducted with the target community during the project life span. Based on feedback from the target community, needed adjustments and adaptations will be made on the project design and implementation modalities. We will also put in place easy accesible accountability systems and complaints mechanisms.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of adaptations in the design and/or implementation of the JR, as a result of the input from beneficiaries.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unconditional and unrestricted cash</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people benefitting from unconditional and unrestricted cash</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1150"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
