<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="376" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/5003" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-LWR-NI-14-5003</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Response to the Impact of Rust and the Coffee Crisis among  Families of Small Coffee Producers</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Rehabilitate their coffee plantations by replanting as needed with roya resistant varieties that also have high quality attributes, applying biomineral and organic fertilizers which strengthen the plants capacity to respond to Roya, and improving overall management practices in their coffee plantations.
2) Access temporary employment through 3000 person days of work generated in the supported communities by project activities in tree and coffee nurseries, production of organic and biomineral fertilizers, and other project activities.
3) Improve the resilience of their farms to future coffee crises through diversification of their production with food crops, incorporating new marketable tree species into their coffee plantations, as well as improving their information about climate change mitigation and adaptation strategies.              
1. LWR and partner CAFENICA will have the opportunity to pilot the use of SMS messaging in project implementation to share information with beneficiaries and to coordinate project activities using the services provided by local cellphone companies.  If this is successful it will be easily transferred to all CAFENICA associated cooperatives.  
 2. LWR and CAFENICA will also pilot an approach to project implementation that attempts to maximize generation of employment in the targeted communities through project activities as sort of a cash for work program though on a very small scale.  We will be able to explore challenges and strategies of employment generation, mechanisms of supervision and payment as well as targeting of beneficiaries for these opportunities.   
 3. LWR and CAFENICA will round out data on the validation of biominerals by adding a third year of data as well as an expanded trial in a particular region under intense coffee leaf rust stress.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will support 500 households with over 3000 members in communities San Juan del Rio Coco, in Las Segovias, one of the most affected coffee producing areas of the country.  The project is also prioritizing solutions for organic coffee producers for whom options are more limited. 
 
In addition to benefits to targeted farming households, this project provides three opportunities for learning and innovation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFENICA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-13-2574963" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lutheran World Relief</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="LWR-NI-14-5003" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="LA-NIC-3-002-14" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-2574963">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lutheran World Relief</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lutheran World Relief</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Melissa Esmero</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Associate</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>mesmero@lwr.org</email>
   <website>http://programs.lwr.org/latinamerica</website>
   <website>http://www.lwr.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_3616727">
   <location-id code="3616727" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">San Juan del Rio Coco</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">San Juan del Rio Coco, Nicaragua (admin level 2)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="3616727" level="2" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.53333 -86.16667</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM2"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://programs.lwr.org/latinamerica">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
