<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-19/DDA-3482/SA2/SNFI/INGO/13963</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian response to improve access to adequate, functional and safe shelter spaces and facilities for the most vulnerable families and marginalized groups in Area C and Hebron H2 restricted neighborhoods.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project was approved by the 2019 Shelter HRP (HPSE19-SHL-150500-1). In partnership with the Rural Centre for Sustainable Development (RCSD), the proposed activities will target the most vulnerable households located in Hebron H2 and Area C of the West Bank, identified as priority areas in the 2019 HPF 2nd Standard Allocation Strategy. Specifically, the proposed activities will be implemented in the most marginalized communities in Hebron H2 and Area C, including  Abu Nuwar, Al Hathroura, Khirbet al Kharaba, Om Al Amad, Umm Fagarah, Ar Rakeez, and Susiya, targeting households living in inadequate shelters and exposed to harsh weather, protection concerns and being at risk of forcible transfer. The response will ensure equal access to housing by taking into consideration
specific needs based on gender, age and disability.

AAH designed this proposed response based on the specific needs of the targeted families. AAH aims to upgrade the residential shelters of the targeted Bedouin and herding families in E1 and South Hebron Hills suffering from harsh weather conditions and man-made disasters resulting in protection risks such as forcible transfer, while also aiming to decrease the vulnerability of households including one or more family member(s) with a disability in H2 area. The vulnerability of these families is twofold, including protection and social concerns. On top, they suffer from limited access to basic services, while also suffering from socio-economic problems such as stigmatization and limited livelihood opportunities associated with the disability one or more family member(s) have. The housing itself can also be considered substandard as people are exposed to violent threats such as clashed and tear gas fires as the houses are not prepared for this since doors are small and there are stairs between rooms. 

The main proposed activities include a) The upgrading/rehabilitation of 63 shelters for vulnerable and marginalized families living in communities in Area C, through improving shelter structure, insulation, doors, windows, etc, and b) The adaptation/rehabilitation of 10 prioritized shelters in Hebron H2 area, targeting families who have one or more  family member(s) with a disability, through adapting shelter spaces, entrances and structure to be functional to accommodate the need of the person with the disability pe.  

AAH and RCSD have extensive prior experience and a strong understanding of the current protection and legal situation for construction in Area C and how to access to restricted areas in H2. Both organizations will ensure protection mainstreaming and risk mitigation by employing a low-profile in rehabilitating structures from the inside and will select adequate working time to avoid exposure and prevent harm to the beneficiaries and communities. Moreover, the partners will ensure active engagement of the people during different phases of the project to ensure a community-based approach, participation, ownership and awareness of rights. Female headed households are prioritized based on vulnerability whom will play an integral part in the selection and design, the selected households are well informed about their rights, obligations and potential risks involved regarding housing, land and property issues and provide their consent to all proposed project activities.

The proposed intervention is time sensitive for the targeted households, as these families may not be able to maintain and/or afford another winter within their existing shelter conditions. The unsafe, insalubrious and uncomfortable situations these families experience daily create a destructive environment, affecting their resilience and eroding their capacities. This emergency response will provide much needed support to the targeted families to have healthy and sturdy shelters to be less exposed and vulnerable and withstand the upcoming winter and following hot summer season.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Accion Contra El Hambre (Action Against Hunger )</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Accion Contra El Hambre (Action Against Hunger )</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Centre for Sustainable Development (RCSD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HPSE19-6-150500-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lucas Honauer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+972 (0)546 87 43 49</telephone>
   <email>lhonauer@pt.acfspain.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HPSE19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">occupied Palestinian territory 2019  (part of 2018-2020 HRP)</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-17">74943.37</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-17">304977.86</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-13963">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-17">379921.23</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Accion Contra El Hambre (Action Against Hunger )</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304269634">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-18">227952.74</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Accion Contra El Hambre (Action Against Hunger )</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304911812">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-09">151968.49</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Accion Contra El Hambre (Action Against Hunger )</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
