<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-33557</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delonex Energy</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Compared to the West and North Africa regions, the East and Central Africa region remains underexplored for hydrocarbons and, despite recent major discoveries in Mozambique and Uganda, the region&apos;&apos;s hydrocarbon potential remains largely untapped.  The work and success of Delonex will help further promote the development of the hydrocarbon sector and encourage further investments in the region.  Smaller companies, such as Delonex, tend to outperform the major oil companies on exploration success and new value creation.  It is expected that independents will continue to lead the way in opening new basins, as governments open up more acreage onshore.  Analysis shows that it is the companies that  are well capitalized, with the right management team, and the correct understanding of the political and social landscape that are best placed to make transformational discoveries.  By opening up new hydrocarbon discoveries in the region, Delonex will pave the way for the entry and broad participation of the large oil companies that bring with them the expertise and resources necessary to develop such new plays, thereby triggering economic activity for the region.  This will eventually bring about substantial revenues to host governments through royalties and profit taxes generated from oil production, direct and indirect local employment and skills development in the host economy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the past decade, Sub Sahara Africa has been the focus of global exploration activity as it offers huge yet-to-be-found resources and it is believed some of the most prospective frontier basins in the world are in this continent, as exemplified by the recent large discoveries in Mozambique, Uganda and Tanzania.   Delonex Energy Limited (Delonex or the Company) seeks to build a portfolio of East and Central African assets with proven, undeveloped reserves and contingent and prospective resources which it will bring to the development stage.  The Company will target exploration-led opportunities in known petroleum systems, focusing mainly on two to three onshore/shallow water basins with common attributes and scalable to a material size.  The portfolio will be built up through acquisitions, farm-ins and direct awards from host governments.  The management team of Delonex is well advanced into pre-screening their first investments.  Material equity stakes and operatorship will be targeted and partnerships will be built to access markets and mitigate risks. The Project will also seek to set a team on the ground, based in Kenya, in order to establish local presence, identify contractors, local content partners and create relationships with all stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DELONEX ENERGY UK LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-33557" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-21" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Gary Pidcock Director  Engineering &amp; Operations Delonex Energy Advisors UK Limited Almack House, 28, King Street St. James, London SW1Y 6QW United Kingdom Telephone:  +44(0) 207 306 3081 Fax:  F: +44(0) 207 321 0881</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">To be determined.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Africa Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delonex is in the process of building a portfolio of oil and gas assets in the East and Central African region through acquisitions, farm-ins and direct awards from host governments.  The projects location will depend on which assets Delonex decides to acquire.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.0000000000 21.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="2131" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">B-AA - Oil and Gas Exploration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $60.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-11-21"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-11-21">60000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-11-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-11-21">60000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DELONEX ENERGY UK LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/33557/delonex-energy">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/33557/delonex-energy">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
