<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-30136</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emerging Markets Communications, Inc.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emerging Markets Communications (EMC or the Company) provides mission-critical, end-to-end communications solutions to governments, non-governmental organizations (NGOs) and multinational corporations operating in remote regions of the globe. Specifically, the Companys services include voice, data, email, video and broadband internet access and applications.  The project consists of (i) the scaling up and expansion, and (ii) the balance sheet strengthening, of EMCs VSAT telecoms network serving isolated areas of emerging markets.  EMC provides global satellite communication using a high quality, fully managed network.  The Company began its activities in 2002.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve productivity through connectivity:  The impact of increased and affordable access to communications and data services is widely acknowledged, with far reaching benefits in terms of private and public sector productivity, including market information, education, tele-medicine and extending financial services to the frontier.      Increased coverage: EMC has the capacity to deliver fully managed, end-to-end solutions in difficult countries and regions where satellite technology is the best or only alternative.     Broader range of services:  Further to basic data and voice, EMC can support more sophisticated applications, processes and corporate software solutions such as SAP and Oracle.    Enhance competition:  Often, EMC is the only viable alternative to the incumbent telecomsoperator.  Supporting EMC helps increase competition and provides comfort to many f its customers that sensitive communications will be handled with privacy.     Reduction in travel/carbon footprint:   EMCs Video-on-Demand solution to be deployed in 2011 will allow customers to collaborate with their colleagues, clients and suppliers without the need to physically travel in and out of remote locations.    Vulnerable ultimate beneficiaries:  Clients in main vertical (development agencies / NGOs, accounting for 54% of revenues), directly target the base of pyramid, especially in Africa.  These institutions reach would be limited without the services of specialized niche providers such as EMC.     Quick deployments:  EMC has a custom-designed solution allowing fast, tactical implementation of communications links following natural catastrophes (i.e., most recently in the Haiti and Chile earthquakes). EMC&apos;&apos;s personnel, a team of highly trained and experienced professionals, is available and ready to deploy and implement satellite services within 48 hours thanks to a stock of pre-staged equipment at regional offices across all continents.     Business continuity:  Strategically located infrastructure ensures business continuity / disaster recovery through redundant links and ample data center capacity. Remaining operational during a disaster makes the difference between financial sustainability and extensive losses for any public or private corporation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EMERGING MARKETS COMMUNICATIONS, LLC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-30136" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-07-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-07-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Santiago Rossi, VP Finance EMC Argentina Tte. Gral. J. D. Per&#xF3;n 949, 14th Floor B1640GNX  Capital Federal, Argentina  Guillermo Mulville (Team Leader) Senior Investment Officer Bouchard 557, 11th Floor Capital Federal, Argentina Tel: +54.11.4114.7206 Fax: +54.11.4312.7184  Jerry MaCauley (Transaction Leader) Investment Officer 2121 Pennsylvania Ave, NW Washington , DC 20433 USA Tel: + 1 202 473 7338 Fax: + 1 202 974 4403</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Africa Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EMC has a network of strategically located, wholly-owned support centers (mainly in Argentina and Kenya) and approximately 700 customer sites scattered throughout the World. It operates 3 teleport facilities (located in Germany, UK and Hawaii), as well as 120,000 sq feet of secure disaster recovery/business continuity data center infrastructure.  EMC has ample C-band spectrum (approximately 1,100 MHz) at below current market cost. Satellite capacity is a scarce resource for the medium term, thus acting as a barrier to entry.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.0000000000 21.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AD - Other (Including Satellite Telecommunications, Radio and Television Broadcasting, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $22.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2011-07-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-07-18">10000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2011-07-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-07-18">12000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-07-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-07-18">12000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EMERGING MARKETS COMMUNICATIONS, LLC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-07-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-07-18">10000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EMERGING MARKETS COMMUNICATIONS, LLC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/30136/emerging-markets-communications-inc">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
