<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-45453</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBI WCS Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholder effects: Increased access to working capital and trade finance for BBI&apos;s customers (FIs and traders) in IDA PSW/FCS countries in Africa. This Project is expected to sustain BBI&apos;s ability to maintain liquidity and access to working capital to these customers in IDA/FCS countries. Given the short term nature of the trade transactions financed by BBI, IFC anticipates that BBI will maintain/provide access to finance to customers across IDA PSW countries for a total volume of up to US 300 million over the life of the Project.

Market Creation: Integration: By supporting BBI&apos;s liquidity needs and its ability to provide trade finance services despite COVID 19 IFC&apos;s facility is intended to promote the integration of trade finance markets in the Africa region. This will be achieved by maintaining and expanding trade finance corridors and trade linkages through bolstering correspondent banking network that serves as an enabling platform. This Project will help to protect the essential platform of myriad cross border trade finance linkages, which supports trade in these countries. In addition, it will contribute to the maintenance of financial stability by providing comfort to other market participants, beyond the Project, that are under pressure to retrench from African markets during this economic crisis. To measure the progress against this outcome, IFC will track the number of additional IDA PSW markets where the Bank is currently not actively supporting trade finance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed investment is a Working Capital Solutions (WCS) facility to BMCE Bank International Plc (BBI or the Bank) of up to US$50 million to be provided by IFC (the Project). The proposed loan will have a tenor of 2 years, renewable for one additional year at IFCs sole discretion, for a maximum aggregate tenor of up to 3 years.   &#xA0;  The Project will provide BBI with funding to support its trade lending activities to import and export of essential goods throughout IDA/FCS countries in Africa. BBIs trade finance portfolio is highly diversified. Currently, BBI has exposure to 18 IDA PSW countries in Africa, accounting for 55% of total exposure.   &#xA0;  This follow-on Project complements an up to US$75 million risk sharing facility under the Global Trade Liquidity Program. The Project is expected to be supported by the IDA Private Sector Window Blended Finance Facility (PSW BFF) as described in the Blended Finance Section.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BMCE BANK INTERNATIONAL PLC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-45453" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="6"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BMCE Bank International Plc  Mounira Smihi  Director, Deputy Head of Representative Office  +41(0)792701800  msmihi@bmce-intl.ch  Fraum&#xFC;nsterstrasse 15, Z&#xFC;rich 8001  https://www.bmce-intl.co.uk/</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Africa Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project will support trade lending activities throughout the 18 IDA/PSW countries in Africa in BBIs portfolio, which account for 55% of total exposure.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.0000000000 21.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="522110" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">O-AK - Commercial Banking - Trade and Supply Chain</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $25.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/45453/bbi-wcs-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/45453/bbi-wcs-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
