<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-521198</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GEF SE Lighting the Bottom of the Pyramid (formerly LED Off-Grid Lighting Initiative)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project Lighting the Bottom of the Pyramid will engage local and international lighting-related companies to offer the non-electrified population in Kenya and Ghana greater access to modern and affordable off-grid lighting products that can commercially displace fuel-based lighting products (e.g. kerosene lamps, candles). The project is an innovative and large-scale initiative to engage the private sector in the effort to increase access to modern energy services and reduce poverty.     The focus on fuel-based lighting is due to its very harmful, yet often underrated, impact on development by reducing households disposable income and living standards, and hurting small business operational costs and productivity. IFCs research found that fuel-based lighting can account for up to 50% of all energy expenses and up to 33% of total household income. In the case of small business, fuel-based light costs from $50/year per lantern (e.g. street vendors) to $1,000/year (e.g. fishermen). Yet, the low quality of the lighting provided by fuel-based devices impairs any productive activity or social development. Greater access to modern off-grid lighting products can reverse this scenario and contribute to poverty reduction.   The projects insight is the realization that current consumption of fuel-based lighting represents a large, global market mostly untapped by lighting companies. Independent estimates indicate that worldwide spending on fuel-based lighting in developing countries is $38 billion/year. In Kenya and Ghana alone, IFC estimates the total spending on fuel-based, off-grid lighting to be $1.4 billion/year. This large market to date has been served by fuel-related companies and has been untapped by lighting companies. Hence, IFC believes there is an opportunity to attract lighting companies to enter and compete in the fuel-based, off-grid lighting market, transforming the private sector profit-seeking motivation and ability to innovate into a force to increase access to modern and affordable lighting services and reduce poverty.  The seize this opportunity, the project will facilitate the market entry of African and foreign companies in this market by helping firms:  - understand the market, including consumer behavior and preferences concerning lighting, acceptable pricing points and distribution channels, and  - mitigate the perceive risks of entering into a new market in a region that for most private companies is very challenging.   The entry of several companies in this market and their competition for market share will bring to non-electrified citizens a variety of modern off-grid lighting products that are designed, and priced to be better and more affordable than fuel-based lighting. IFC will not pick winners choosing companies or products, but merely facilitate the market entry of as many companies as possible and foster a competitive environment amongst them.   To that end, this 4-year project has 5 core sub-actions or phases, namely:  - forming the private sector consortium,  - performing market research on consumer behavior, including product field testing,  - mapping and engaging with the distribution channels reaching the targeted population,  - after sharing market findings from previous sub-actions ii and iii with participating firms, IFC will support individual companies in entering this market (e.g. IFC may provide funding to a local assembly plant, trade-finance product to facilitate import of components or products, mobilize micro-financing, etc), and  - support the development of institutions to support the market, such as consumer awareness campaign, or establishing systems for product quality controls of modern off-grid lighting products being offered to the unelectrified population in Kenya and Ghana.    The project to date has attracted the interest of over 350 organizations from over 40 countries, and will also be the pilot for a larger World Bank Group lighting initiative called Lighting Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project core development impact will be to increase, in a commercially and environmentally sustainable way, access to modern and affordable off-grid lighting services to the population in Kenya and Ghana that, today, can only access fuels for lighting. Access to modern lighting will positively impact these populations in several ways. Fuel-based lighting is an expensive solution that provides a low quality service of light, and hinders development. For instance, concerning households living standards, fuel-based lighting can account for as much as 15% of a household income. In addition, it is a safety hazard and common source of fires. Furthermore, it contributes to indoor air pollution and related health problems. Concerning social development, poor lighting directly impacts educational performance. Concerning small businesses, such as night street vendors, the high cost of fuel-based lighting limits evening operating hours, and the low quality of the light limits customer traffic and sales, hence the overall productivity of small businesses.   Access to modern and affordable off-grid lighting services can revert these conditions and significantly improve the living standards of households, and the productivity of very small businesses. The project targets for the pilot in Kenya and Ghana a market penetration of as much as 10% in 10 years, which translates into 1,500,000 end-users with modern, off-grid lighting products by 2015 in the two countries. The project has support from both governments, and extensive support from the private sector and stakeholders at large. To date, over 350 organizations have expressed interest in the projects approach, and in taking part or being involved in its implementation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNKNOWN</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-521198" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-10-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Due to the advisory nature of this project, a client is not applicable.    Please contact:   Mr. Fabio Nehme  Sustainability Innovation Group, IFC + 1 202 458 5858 fnehme@ifc.org 2121 Pennsylvania Avenue NW Washington DC 20433 USA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Africa Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will be implemented in Kenya and Ghana, covering all regions in these two countries, and urban, peri-urban and rural areas.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.0000000000 21.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="2211" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BF - Solar - Renewable Energy Generation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/521198/gef-se-lighting-the-bottom-of-the-pyramid-formerly-led-offgrid-lighting-initiative">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
