<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-40530953-SCC-KEN</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-40530953" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amnesty International, The Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening Civil Courage &#x2013; Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme activities intend to support civil society organisations, (women) human rights defenders and other activists to claim the necessary civic space that enables them to operate freely and express their legitimate demands. Interventions include strengthening of protection mechanisms and solidarity networks, and enhancing skills in assembling evidence-based reports to influence the policies at regional, national and international levels. The second line of work ultimately aspires that Kenyan authorities acknowledge the violation of rights of Muslim people and their communities, and take adequate measures for redress of victims and non-repetition of such violations. To that end, civil society organisations and rights holders will be supported in documenting and reporting on human rights violations, and to use that evidence in advocacy and dialogue with relevant duty bearers at local or national level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance will work in particular with and for (Women) Human Rights Defenders, including journalists, Muslim communities in Kenya&#x2019;s Coastal and North-eastern region and victims of human rights violations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity is part of a larger programme implemented by the Strengthening Civil Courage Alliance, consisting of ABAAD &#x2013; Resource Center for Gender Equality, Amnesty International The Netherlands, DefendDefenders, PAX and their partner networks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme focuses on Kenya&#x2019;s restricted civic space as well as human rights violations in the context of State security sector operations (counter-terrorism operations). At national level, crackdowns on demonstrations violated the freedoms of expression and assembly. Journalists and human rights defenders, youth and targeted populations have been subject to harassment, intimidation, sexual and gender-based violence (SGBV), negative profiling and extrajudicial killings when investigating and speaking out on corruption and extrajudicial executions as well as on issues like reproductive health and gender-based violence. Kenya&#x2019;s military involvement in Somalia in 2011, as well as its geographic location has made the country vulnerable to acts of (international) terrorism. To counter this vulnerability, Kenya developed and implements counter terrorism measures. In practice, security operations have been negatively impacting the enjoyment of basic human rights of Muslim communities in the Coast and North-eastern regions. These communities have faced widespread discrimination, lack of economic opportunities, marginalization and ethnic or religious profiling by security forces.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-40530953-SCC-KEN" ref="NL-KVK-40530953" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amnesty International, The Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-40530953-SCC-KEN" ref="NL-KVK-40530953" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amnesty International, The Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="UG-NGB-5541-UG-NGB-5541-KEN" ref="UG-NGB-5541" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DefendDefenders</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="80" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">63030</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">120193</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">123762</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">103668</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">29481</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">81793</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-40530953-SCC1" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development programme partners</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs with increased L&amp;A capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SCS053" indicator-uri="https://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2022">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 partner (other, not youth or women-led) analysed L &amp; A capacities in 7 capacity areas A. Produce evidence, B Inspiring trust among power holders, C. Represent constituency interests, D. Analyse the political arena,  E. Produce tailored messages,  F. Work collectively, G. Build rapport with power holders,  determining the need  to prioritize strengthening capacities in areas C and G.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of 2022,&#xA0; 1 partner  (other, not youth or women-led) will have strengthened  L &amp; A capacities in  C. Represent constituency interests, and  G. Build rapport with power holders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 2.3 Kenyan Gvt (Office of the President) publicly acknowledges and condemns the scope and gravity of abuses during counterterrorism operations in Kenya and takes effective measures to address the problem.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of laws and policies for sustainable and inclusive development that are better implemented as a result of CSO engagement (SCS1)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SCS012" indicator-uri="https://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">KDF should follow the mandate as stipulated in Art. 241 (3) of the Constitution of Kenya (2010) but this is currently not happening</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenyan Parliament takes the decision to end illegal deployment of KDF (with a verifiable contribution from partner CSOs)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1.3 (W)HRDs and the national coalitions engage in strategic and effective lobbying of the Kenyan authorities and of UN and AU human rights mechanisms on HRDs protection and to lift restrictions on civic space &#x2013; including e.g. the Computer Misuse and Cybercrime Act</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># advocacy initiatives carried out by the national coalition of HRDs for, by or with their membership (regarding restrictions on civic space) (SCS 4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SCS041" indicator-uri="https://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The local partner positions herself as a thought and collaborative leader towards (re)formulation and or enforcement of appropriate policies, laws, institutions and cultural norms that touch on the safety, security and well-being of HRDs. Submissions on the Data Protection Bill 2018 were made and review of laws related to the exercise of the Power of mercy under Article 133 of the Constitution. The partner engaged in advocacy at the national and in some instances at the local level.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">4 by 2025 (cumulative) - 1 in Yr5. Advocacy at the UNHRC ahead of the upcoming elections, development of statements and letters to be submitted at the diplomatic missions and NHRI (= National Human Rights Institute) on the situation of HRDs in Kenya</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
