<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-21-DO-DR-345</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening networks to prevent and address family, gender-based, and sexual violence. Strengthening networks to prevent and address family, gender- based, and sexual violence. Strengthenin g networks to prevent and address family, gender- based, and sexual violence</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assist special populations which may be vulnerable or at-risk on a temporary or chronic basis whose needs are not addressed under emergency humanitarian assistance or other programs. These include groups such as the disabled; orphans, children and at-risk youth; victims of trafficking; victims of gender-based violence; refugees, returnees, ethnic minorities, internally displaced or other socially excluded groups; the elderly; and female heads of household. Depending on circumstances, services may intend to protect groups; mitigate adverse conditions they face, or to remove barriers to help integrate them into society. Components may include measures to increase the capacity of local service and advocacy NGOs and/or professional social workers; to establish public/private service delivery partnerships as well as family and community focused service models; to establish effective referral networks; to develop appropriate service protocols and methods for screening prospective recipients; or to improve public understanding and sensitivity to the needs of the vulnerable.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evaluation is the systematic collection and analysis of information about the characteristics and outcomes of programs and projects as a basis for judgments, to improve effectiveness and inform decisions about current and future programming. Evaluations are distinct from (a) needs assessments, which are designed to examine country or sector context to inform project design, (b) internal informal reviews of projects and (c) audits (conducted either internally or by an external audience). This program area should include all evaluations designed and funded with foreign assistance funding, including the components of contracts with task orders for evaluations (regardless of the mechanism). It should also include all independent contractors hired solely to produce an evaluation(s).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rule of law is a principle under which all persons, institutions and entities, public and private, including the State itself, are accountable to laws that are publicly promulgated, independently adjudicated, equally applied and enforced, and consistent with international treaties and customary law. Rule of law is demonstrated by: adherence to the principles of publicly accepted legitimacy of the law, institutions and process; checks and balances on structures of power; supremacy of law; equality before the law; accountability to the law; fairness; effective application of the law; equitable access to justice; participation in decision-making; legal certainty; avoidance of arbitrariness; and, procedural and legal transparency. Activities include support for strengthening of judicial systems including court administration, management, and operations, judicial proceedings, constitutional and legal reform efforts, judicial independence, access to justice, and legal education and associations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supports the following illustrative program-funded costs: salaries of US, FSN, and TCN and other staff such as PSCs, RSSAs, PASAs, CASUs working for the US Government managing, administering, and supporting programs and their program-funded benefits such as housing, travel, transportation, education allowances etc; institutional contractors that provide such staff, rent, IT services, the program-funded share of utilities, staff training costs and the cost of developing and administering training programs, equipment and supplies, ICASS, vehicle fuel and maintenance, maintenance contracts, janitorial services, operational unit web page development and maintenance, outreach such as publications and the cost of their preparation (including staff costs), and technical assistance to ensure USG compliance with regulations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award focuses on evaluation which is the systematic collection and analysis of information about the characteristics and outcomes of programs and projects as a basis for judgments, to improve effectiveness and inform decisions about current and future programming. More specifically, this award includes N&#xFA;cleo de Apoyo a la Mujer (NAM), $283,290 over three years NAM will expand services offered to victims of family, gender and sexual violence, and strengthen institutional networks dedicated to preventing such violence in Santiago and Moca. The project is expected to benefit 1,385 victims, members of grassroots and nongovernmental organizations, and local public-sector employees. (DR-345). N&#xFA;cleo de Apoyo a la Mujer (NAM). NAM will expand services offered to victims of family, gender and sexual violence, and strengthen institutional networks dedicated to preventing such violence in Santiago and Moca. The project is expected to benefit 1,385 victims, members of grassroots and nongovernmental organizations, and local public-sector employees.. N&#xFA;cleo de Apoyo a la Mujer (NAM), $283,290 over three years NAM will expand services offered to victims of family, gender and sexual violence, and strengthen institutional networks dedicated to preventing such violence in Santiago and Moca. The project is expected to benefit 1,385 victims, members of grassroots and nongovernmental organizations, and local public-sector employees. (DR-345) 1. N&#xFA;cleo de Apoyo a la Mujer (NAM) will improve quality of services offered to victims of family, gender and sexual violence, and strengthen institutional networks dedicated to preventing these problems in Santiago and Puerto Plata. It will also train doctors, nurses, primary health care units on issues related to gender-based violence and will prepare a manual to facilitate implementation of protocols and norms. The project is expected to benefit approximately 650 victims, members of grassroots and nongovernmental organizations, and local public-sector employees.. N&#xFA;cleo de Apoyo a la Mujer (NAM), $15,685 NAM will expand services offered to victims of family, gender and sexual violence, and strengthen institutional networks dedicated to preventing such violence in Santiago and Moca. The project is expected to benefit 1,385 victims, members of grassroots and nongovernmental organizations, and local public-sector employees.. N&#xFA;cleo De Apoyo A La Mujer (Nam) Will Expand Services Offered To Victims Of Family, Gender And Sexual Violence, And Strengthen Institutional Networks Dedicated To Preventing Such Violence In Santiago And Moca. The Project Is Expected To Benefit 1,385 Vict.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To help nations achieve sustainable improvements in the well-being and productivity of their populations through effective and accountable investments in education and other social services. Promote equitable, effective, accountable, and sustainable formal and non-formal education systems.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-21" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-21" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N&#xFA;cleo de Apoyo a la Mujer</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-08-23" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-08-23" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-23" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-23" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lesley Duncan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+1 202-360-4530</telephone>
   <email>lduncan@iaf.gov</email>
   <website>http://www.iaf.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1331 Pennsylvania Ave. NW, Suite 1200 North&#xC2;&#xA0;Washington, DC 20004</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="DO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="DO">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dominican Republic</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. assistance supports the foreign policy priority of building the Dominican Republic&apos;s effectiveness as a regional partner, and is aligned with the priorities established in the Dominican National Development Strategy. A challenging security environment, climate change, weak institutions, corruption, inadequate public health services, poor education, and a lack of job opportunities are major development challenges facing the Dominican Republic. The U.S. government collaborates with Dominican authorities to address these challenges, while working with local and international partners to strengthen institutional and technical capacity. A secure and stable Dominican Republic is important to the advancement of U.S. interests in the Caribbean. The FY 2017 foreign assistance request aims to build resilience to the effects of climate change, improve the quality of basic education, and increase access to quality prevention, care, and treatment services for HIV/AIDS. To address the needs of marginalized populations, including women, the lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender and intersex (LGBTI) community, people of Haitian descent, and people with disabilities, U.S. assistance will fund activities to support their inclusion in all aspects of Dominican society. Bilateral programs will complement and enhance security and citizen safety assistance being provided through the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-26">60288</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement of funds to the Award Implementing Organization to carry out the activities set forth in Annex A of the grant agreement.</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="11230" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic life skills for youth and adults</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="4000" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education and Social Services - General</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-03-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-03-19">56500</value>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative costs (non-sector allocable)</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="8001" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct Administrative Costs</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2012" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-08-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-08-23">283290</value>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative costs (non-sector allocable)</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="8002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring and Evaluation</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2012" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-09-19">79924</value>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative costs (non-sector allocable)</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="8002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring and Evaluation</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2012" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-11-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-11-13">67869</value>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative costs (non-sector allocable)</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="8002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring and Evaluation</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2013" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-14">103966</value>
   <sector code="11230" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic life skills for youth and adults</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="4000" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education and Social Services - General</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-02-21">15685</value>
   <sector code="15130" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal and judicial development</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="2001" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rule of Law and Human Rights</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2014" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-30">44878</value>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Protection</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="4004" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Services</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2014" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-11-12">3000</value>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Protection</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="4004" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Services</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2014" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
