<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-9-ID-F13AP00831</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">An innovative partnership program for human-elephant coexistence and forest conservation in Aceh, Sumatra, Indonesia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;This project will be carried out in phases. Phase I has the following objectives and activities: Objective 1. Ensure effective planning, implementation, monitoring, evaluation and documentation of the project using a transdisciplinary approach as a model for replication within and outside Aceh. Activities under this objective include the following: Establish a transdisciplinary team with skills necessary for building an innovative model for addressing HEC. Seven positions with different skill sets will be identified to build a core team including expert consultants. A ToR will be developed for each core team member and members will be recruited. Key stakeholder roles and responsibilities will be outlined. The team will conduct baseline assessment of human-elephant conflict (HEC) threats in target districts. The core team will meet identified key stakeholders to revisit threat assessment. The model project will be based on the results from threat assessments with key stakeholder consultation. Project activities regularly monitored and results evaluated. A project monitoring protocol and schedule will be established. Regular evaluation meetings will be conducted with project stakeholders. Lessons learned and guidance for replication for successful and sustainable human-elephant co-existence in an agricultural landscape. Compile bi-annual lessons learned into a comprehensive document. Transform comprehensive lessons learned document into communication material to be published and presented to relevant stakeholders for potential replication in other areas. Objective 2. To increase the effectiveness of laws for the protection of biodiversity and natural resources of Aceh, promoting the creation of a cross-party, committed, knowledgeable and constantly expanding legislator network called Aceh Conservation Caucus. The activities under this objective include the following: Identify key members of the Aceh Congress with influence on conservation and management of natural resources and biodiversity. These key players will be those in the Aceh Congress who have influence on priority environmental issues, operating dynamics within the structure and processes of the Legislature, including national, provincial, and district governments and their interactions. Develop a relationship plan and detect specific needs and motivations of the key players identified to be part of the network of legislators interested in the environment. Establish the administrative and operational structure of the Aceh Conservation Caucus. Develop ToRs for Aceh Conservation Caucus advisors and for legislative and policy consultants. Establish and run awareness mechanisms using the Aceh Conservation Caucus with legislators and other decision makers as targeted audiences. Design, trial and conduct baseline/project end awareness survey with community stakeholders. The Aceh Conservation Caucus will conduct periodic presentations at the Aceh House of Representatives and related government agencies. Design and develop a web portal with a thematic structure that meets the needs and motivations of specific information from lawmakers, while linking them with relevant environmental issues and priorities. The portal will provide information on environmental issues, decision-making processes, statistics, include constantly updated databases, as well as being a forum for participation and dissemination of the work of the network of environmental legislators. Train volunteer groups to conduct community outreach events, and deploy core team for regular visit to specific target audience within project focal area. Record outreach process and verifiable indicators and produce activity report. Provide study tour to selected field sites for legislators and decision makers. In situ study visits will be held to expose legislators directly and intensely to the natural environment. This will also provide legislators an experiential relationship with local stakeholders, and raise their awareness of environmental issues in general, and specifically to the issue of conservation and wildlife conflicts. Field study trips will be planned to enable legislators to be immersed in a successful conservation site, i.e., the CRU in Tangkahan, so they may experience a positive and sustainable program that benefits human-elephant coexistence, and promotes a better understanding of environmental issues. This program is a positive example of human-elephant coexistence. Submit environmental problems and possible solutions directly to the group of legislators. Establish effective and efficient mechanisms to provide adequate and timely information so Aceh legislators can make better decisions when developing and implementing laws. Promote the network of environmental and conservation legislators, as an Aceh Conservation Caucus, consisting of decision makers and their recommendations. Phase II, which will be carried after the Phase I is completed by grantee and report is accepted by USFWS, has the following objective, Objective 3: To develop a strategic land use and agricultural mapping plan for HEC areas, compatible with human and elephant needs. The activities within this objective are as follows: Initiate a study to identify agricultural commodity options for individual and industrial farmers within Aceh&#x2018;s elephant range by working with consultants to develop research methodology to identify the level of preference, damage, and economic impact of different agricultural commodities. Produce potential elephant-compatible commodity list to be tested, and conduct elephant preference research from produced potential commodity list through, field examples, controlled trials, and secondary data. Produce thematic map showing model of potential commodity placement and distribution within project focal areas. Work with agriculture experts to assess the economic value of identified compatible agricultural commodities. Develop ToR for agriculture expert on economic values assessment of the nominated elephant-compatible commodities. Produce viability study using economic and agricultural point of view in order to publish options for various identified elephant-compatible commodities. Develop a sustainable agricultural landscape plan for two districts. Gather data on the locations, causes, and impacts of HEC in the two target districts. Prepare communication materials based on all data and research for presentation to the community. Conduct presentations in two districts and record meeting minutes to feed into lessons learned document and commodity map. Develop agricultural map based on all research and stakeholder input. Submit the sustainable agricultural landscape mapping plan to the district government and the Aceh Conservation Caucus to be adopted into district policy. Prepare necessary documents (ex. policy guideline) to be officially submitted. Prepare legislative endorsement as part of official submission of the strategic agricultural mapping plan to district governments. Submit policy paper. Encourage community and decision makers to adopt the sustainable agricultural landscape plan to ensure that agricultural plantations are compatible with human and elephant needs. Develop participatory process for community to adopt agricultural options using policy guideline produced. Conduct meetings presenting clear linkage between the conservation and economic livelihood points of view to address HEC and promote human-elephant coexistence concept. Set up conservation reward scheme for best practice management in addressing HEC mitigation. &apos;. This project will be carried out in phases. Phase I has the following objectives and activities: Objective 1. Ensure effective planning, implementation, monitoring, evaluation and documentation of the project using a transdisciplinary approach as a model for replication within and outside Aceh. Activities under this objective include the following: Establish a transdisciplinary team with skills necessary for building an innovative model for addressing HEC. Seven positions with different skill sets will be identified to build a core team including expert consultants. A ToR will be developed for each core team member and members will be recruited. Key stakeholder roles and responsibilities will be outlined. The team will conduct baseline assessment of human-elephant conflict (HEC) threats in target districts. The core team will meet identified key stakeholders to revisit threat assessment. The model project will be based on the results from threat assessments with key stakeholder consultation. Project activities regularly monitored and results evaluated. A project monitoring protocol and schedule will be established. Regular evaluation meetings will be conducted with project stakeholders. Lessons learned and guidance for replication for successful and sustainable human-elephant co-existence in an agricultural landscape. Compile bi-annual lessons learned into a comprehensive document. Transform comprehensive lessons learned document into communication material to be published and presented to relevant stakeholders for potential replication in other areas. Objective 2. To increase the effectiveness of laws for the protection of biodiversity and natural resources of Aceh, promoting the creation of a cross-party, committed, knowledgeable and constantly expanding legislator network called Aceh Conservation Caucus. The activities under this objective include the following: Identify key members of the Aceh Congress with influence on conservation and management of natural resources and biodiversity. These key players will be those in the Aceh Congress who have influence on priority environmental issues, operating dynamics within the structure and processes of the Legislature, including national, provincial, and district governments and their interactions. Develop a relationship plan and detect specific needs and motivations of the key players identified to be part of the network of legislators interested in the environment. Establish the administrative and operational structure of the Aceh Conservation Caucus. Develop ToRs for Aceh Conservation Caucus advisors and for legislative and policy consultants. Establish and run awareness mechanisms using the Aceh Conservation Caucus with legislators and other decision makers as targeted audiences. Design, trial and conduct baseline/project end awareness survey with community stakeholders. The Aceh Conservation Caucus will conduct periodic presentations at the Aceh House of Representatives and related government agencies. Design and develop a web portal with a thematic structure that meets the needs and motivations of specific information from lawmakers, while linking them with relevant environmental issues and priorities. The portal will provide information on environmental issues, decision-making processes, statistics, include constantly updated databases, as well as being a forum for participation and dissemination of the work of the network of environmental legislators. Train volunteer groups to conduct community outreach events, and deploy core team for regular visit to specific target audience within project focal area. Record outreach process and verifiable indicators and produce activity report. Provide study tour to selected field sites for legislators and decision makers. In situ study visits will be held to expose legislators directly and intensely to the natural environment. This will also provide legislators an experiential relationship with local stakeholders, and raise thei. This project will be carried out in phases. Phase I has the following objectives and activities: Objective 1. Ensure effective planning, implementation, monitoring, evaluation and documentation of the project using a transdisciplinary approach as a model for replication within and outside Aceh. Activities under this objective include the following: Establish a transdisciplinary team with skills necessary for building an innovative model for addressing HEC. Seven positions with different skill sets will be identified to build a core team including expert consultants. A ToR will be developed for each core team member and members will be recruited. Key stakeholder roles and responsibilities will be outlined. The team will conduct baseline assessment of human-elephant conflict (HEC) threats in target districts. The core team will meet identified key stakeholders to revisit threat assessment. The model project will be based on the results from threat assessments with key stakeholder consultation. Project activities regularly monitored and results evaluated. A project monitoring protocol and schedule will be established. Regular evaluation meetings will be conducted with project stakeholders. Lessons learned and guidance for replication for successful and sustainable human-elephant co-existence in an agricultural landscape. Compile bi-annual lessons learned into a comprehensive document. Transform comprehensive lessons learned document into communication material to be published and presented to relevant stakeholders for potential replication in other areas. Objective 2. To increase the effectiveness of laws for the protection of biodiversity and natural resources of Aceh, promoting the creation of a cross-party, committed, knowledgeable and constantly expanding legislator network called Aceh Conservation Caucus. The activities under this objective include the following: Identify key members of the Aceh Congress with influence on conservation and management of natural resources and biodiversity. These key players will be those in the Aceh Congress who have influence on priority environmental issues, operating dynamics within the structure and processes of the Legislature, including national, provincial, and district governments and their interactions. Develop a relationship plan and detect specific needs and motivations of the key players identified to be part of the network of legislators interested in the environment. Establish the administrative and operational structure of the Aceh Conservation Caucus. Develop ToRs for Aceh Conservation Caucus advisors and for legislative and policy consultants. Establish and run awareness mechanisms using the Aceh Conservation Caucus with legislators and other decision makers as targeted audiences. Design, trial and conduct baseline/project end awareness survey with community stakeholders. The Aceh Conservation Caucus will conduct periodic presentations at the Aceh House of Representatives and related government agencies. Design and develop a web portal with a thematic structure that meets the needs and motivations of specific information from lawmakers, while linking them with relevant environmental issues and priorities. The portal will provide information on environmental issues, decision-making processes, statistics, include constantly updated databases, as well as being a forum for participation and dissemination of the work of the network of environmental legislators. Train volunteer groups to conduct community outreach events, and deploy core team for regular visit to specific target audience within project focal area. Record outreach process and verifiable indicators and produce activity report. Provide study tour to selected field sites for legislators and decision makers. In situ study visits will be held to expose legislators directly and intensely to the natural environment. This will also provide legislators an experiential relationship with local stakeholders, and raise the</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASIAN ELEPHANT SUPPORT</narrative>
   <usg:duns-number>962386244</usg:duns-number>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Fish and Wildlife Service/Office of International Affairs</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>888-678-6836</telephone>
   <email>feedback@ios.doi.gov</email>
   <website>https://www.doi.gov/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11849 C Street, N.W. Washington, D.C. 20240</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ID">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Having undergone a remarkable democratic transformation, Indonesia is a key regional and global player. Given Indonesia&apos;s status as the world&apos;s largest Muslim-majority nation, third largest democracy, and one of the largest greenhouse gas emitters, the United States has an interest in its continued success. Despite its progress, success is not assured and challenges still remain. In the framework of the U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Partnership, United States development assistance partners with Indonesians to improve the quality and relevance of higher education and delivery of priority healthcare, strengthen governance and democracy, sustain the environment, manage disasters, and create an environment for science, technology, and innovation to thrive. Priorities and goals for U.S. assistance will need to be flexible to accommodate potential changes in the Government of Indonesia (GOI)&apos;s own development plans, including a new 2015-2019 National Development Strategy, which was finalized in early 2015. The U.S. foreign assistance resources in Indonesia support two Presidential Initiatives. The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) implements activities to build capacity for communities to adapt to climate change, promote low emissions development, and encourage sustainable management of natural resources in support of the Global Climate Change (GCC) Initiative. USAID also works to reduce maternal and child mortality and strengthen Indonesia&apos;s response to infectious diseases in support of the Global Health Initiative (GHI).</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-10-01">300700</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-01">300700</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-01">419700</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-18">-115812.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One-time disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2013" end="2021"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-18">-3187.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One-time disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2018" end="2021"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-04-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-04-13">63502.47</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One-time obligation</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-16">115812.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One-time obligation</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2013" end="2021"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-16">3187.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One-time obligation</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2018" end="2021"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-02">300700</value>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-17">300700</value>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <usg:mechanism-signing-date iso-date="2013-08-12"></usg:mechanism-signing-date>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
