<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-21/NIG_ERF/SA1/N/INGO/20365</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scaleup of Treatment and Prevention of SAM and MAM among Children 0 - 59 months and PLW in Banki-Bama LGA, Borno state</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 2017, FHI 360 has successfully addressed severe acute malnutrition cases and improved infant and young child feeding (IYCF) practices in four locations, including Bama LGA of Borno state under the BHA-funded Integrated Humanitarian Assistance to Northeast Nigeria (IHANN) project. 

FHI 360, through this grant, will partner with Achieving Health Nigeria Initiative (AHNi), a National NGO, to implement the Scaleup the Treatment and Prevention of severe acute malnutrition (SAM) and moderate acute malnutrition (MAM) among children under-five and pregnant and lactating women (PLW) project in Banki, Bama LGA of Borno state. 
FHI 360 will expand its community-based management of acute malnutrition (CMAM), including MAM treatment for children 6-59 months and PLW. Train skilled community volunteers (community health workers) and non-skilled community volunteers (community nutrition monitors, support group promoters/facilitators) to conduct active case finding for SAM with medical complications, MAM among children under-five and PLW through mid-upper arm circumference screening and refer eligible children and PLW for treatment. Children enrolled in the growth monitoring programme (GMP) will be screened and referred for malnutrition treatment. Mothers and Caregivers will be trained on family-led MUAC screening to improve the coverage and prompt detection. Six outreach sites are planned for this intervention and linked to the FHI 360 IHANN Project sites in Banki, Bama LGA.

FHI 360 will manage MAM cases among children and PLW at the MAM centre operating within the IHANN health facilities and ensure linkage for PLW to access other reproductive health services using the Northeast Nigeria Nutrition sector strategy and protocol. FHI 360 will ensure the availability of adequate quantities of nutrition products and materials (RUSF, CSB++, Tom Brown, Vitamin A, Albendazole, Amoxicillin syrup, MUAC tapes), either from the sector or direct procurement. Through the existing Community IYCF corners in Banki, FHI 360 will manage MAM and promote IYCF in children and PLW.

For the treatment and management of SAM with complications, FHI 360&#x2019;s established Stabilization Centre (SC) in Banki will be expanded to accommodate 30 children, increased from the current eight children capacity. At the SC, FHI 360 will feed caregivers to reduce defaulter rates while conducting routine mortality audits/reviews.

FHI 360 will provide maternal infant and young child feeding (MIYCF) services using social and behavioral change communication (SBCC) strategy and cluster direction to reverse poor suboptimal IYCF practices. We will establish 100 community support groups (CSGs) across the communities led by a lead mother/father comprising of 15 persons each across caregivers categories. Trained community health workers (CHWs) will coordinate CSG activities. In addition, CHWs/Volunteers will provide group and one-on-one counselling in breastfeeding spaces at the FHI 360 health facilities, community IYCF Corner and MAM centre constructed within the health facility in Banki, Bama LGA. 

FHI 360 will conduct facility and community-based GMP to detect growth faltering and early signs of malnutrition for prompt referral and treatment. Conduct community cooking demonstration for age-appropriate complementary feeding using locally available recipes to improve dietary diversity score for women. To promote the adoption of positive behaviours, FHI 360 will facilitate community dialogue/ focused group discussions, broadcast jingles on key nutrition messages during outreaches and at breastfeeding spaces, MAM centre, Community IYCF Corner, ANC, PNC and Immunization areas. 

PLW will receive Iron and Folic acid in addition to being treated for Moderate acute malnutrition, while children 6-59 months will receive vitamin-A and micronutrients powder and be dewormed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieving Health Nigeria Initiative</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Family Health International Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Family Health International Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-23" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hadiza Khamofu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acting Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>08037376804</telephone>
   <email>hkhamofu@fhi360.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG008">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Borno</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.88898010 13.15334698</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-23"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-09">349645.83</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-20365">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-09">349645.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Family Health International Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305476738">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-16">209787.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Family Health International Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
