<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-21/NIG_ERF/SA1/E/INGO/20404</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing  Access /continuity of education,  readiness of schools   for safe schools reopening  for under-served and marginalized  crisis-affected boys and girls of rural host communities of  yola south,  Michika, Mubi North in Adamawa State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This response is need- assessment based. African Humanitarian Aid International (AHAI) conducted in March 12th 2021 a rapid assessment in 300 households  with  schooling age boys and girls  in  six (6) primary schools in host communities of  Mubi North ( Betso, Mayo Bani, Kudzum),  Michika( Husari), Madagali (Shuwa), Yola South (Modire primary school) in Adamawa  state and Pulka ( Damara Camp, CAMP A, Central primary school) in Borno State.  The need assessment aimed at identifying  learners&apos; needs, teaching needs and readiness of schools as well as schools authorities, parents, learners for safe school re-opening.  the assessment was conducted with mixed-methodology ( key informant interviews, focus groups discussions, direct observation). the target groups were parents/ caretakers, students ( boys and girls), community volunteers  teachers,  SMBCs members. the overall objective was to determine the impact of  schools closure due to covid-19 on learners education so as to provide a rapid alternate learning option.the  household level Assessment showed: 
 80% of assessed households had drop out of schools boys or girls. 60% of interviewed households lost their means of livelihoods. 50% of households had no learning materials( text books, newspapers Tv set,..), in addition, 70% of assessed households had  no radio, limited  access to power, TV and data to access  online  radio, TV broad cast learning programs). there is an urgent need to   design a context specific home and community based  quality inclusive and protective learning program to breach the barriers in access to education and maintain the learning habits of boys and girls including children with disabilities in rural areas of Adamawa and Borno.   30% of assessed primary schools had  temporal learning spaces. The Bill of quantity (BOQ)  revealed that  70% of   assessed temporal learning spaces,  10% of Tls had WASH facilities , however, they were  limited as per number of children , in addition 5% of were not  gender sensitive, not accessible for children with disabilities ( they had stairs). there is an urgent need to construct new Tls with gender sensitive services without stairs for community learning. 45% of teachers expressed the needs for teaching materials. furthermore, SMBCs expressed an urgent need for pre positioning of Hand washing station in  learning spaces.   20 temporal learning spaces (TLS) in  Yola south, Mubi north , Michika , Madagali, Pulka   need  partial  or completed rehabilitation  with minor and major repairs  ( need of ceiling board, facial board, roofing, screding and dressing walls).In  addition, the key interview conducted with  school authorities, parents  revealed, they did not  have an improved knowledge on safe school re-opening guidelines as  classroom were not fumigated, limited pre-positioning of covid-19 items  in schools( hand washing stations, hand sanitizers, running water with soaps for regular hand washing) while teachers and learners lacked PPE. There is an urgent need to distribute PPE to teachers, learners SBMCs , while classroom need fumigation as well as pre-positioning of PPE items at the entrance of schools for safe school re-opening. in addition, teachers, parents and schools authorities knowledge need to be improved on Covid-19 preventive measures ( observation of social distances, wearing of face masks, regular hand washing with soaps and running water )via awareness raising as well as awareness campaigns on gender equality..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Humanitarian Aid International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Humanitarian Aid International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Betrus stephen Yakubu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of education</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>07063339908</telephone>
   <email>betrus.ngr@aha-afric.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ngono Tsimi christian</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">program coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>07012613887</telephone>
   <email>christian.ngr@aha-afric.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG002">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adamawa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.32322733 12.40024078</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-11">100000.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-20404">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-11">100000.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Humanitarian Aid International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305416705">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">40000.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Humanitarian Aid International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305527103">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-19">40000.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Humanitarian Aid International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
