<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-21/NIG_ERF/SA1/N/NGO/20697</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Community-based Management of Acute Malnutrition (I-CMAM) project for under 5 Children in Konduga, Mafa, Kaga and MMC LGAs in Borno State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The decade-long protracted violence insurgency in the three (3) BAY states has resulted in mass displacement and loss of livelihood and increase in food insecurity, these have equally resulted in increased malnutrition among children of under 5, including nursing and lactating mothers.
The increased malnutrition is very alarming in most parts of the BAY state, it has remained high compared to the 15% World Health Organization thresholds.
The Prevalence of chronic malnutrition and underweight in children 6 to 59 months of age is still indicating high in the Borno, Adamawa, and Yobe states (NFSS IX- Oct 2021). 
Also, according to the Nutrition and Food Security Surveillance Round 9 (NFSS IX), conducted in October 2020, the level of acute malnutrition increased in Adamawa and Yobe compared to 2019. The current global acute malnutrition (GAM) rates are 10.7% in Borno (slightly lower than the 2019 mark of 11.3%) and 13.6% in Yobe.
In contributing to the overall objective of the nutrition response in 2021, which is centered around reducing the morbidity and mortality associated with acute malnutrition and prevent the overall acute malnutrition among the most vulnerable members of the targeted community including children under five, vulnerable adolescent girls, pregnant and lactating women. GREENCODE is proposing- Improving Community-based Management of Acute Malnutrition (I-CMAM) project for under 5 Children in Borno state (Kaga, Mafa, Konduga and MMC LGAs) 
Activities planned for are  
-	Conducting mass and house to house MUAC screening to identify and refer acutely malnourished children, pregnant and lactating women. 
-	Promotion of &#x201C;Family/Mother MUAC&#x201D; approach &#x2013; Training and supporting mother (and other households/community members) to self-screen their own children and refer appropriately 
-	Facilitating referral of SAM/MAM cases from very poor households to treatment centres with local transport.
-	Conduct screening and referral of infants less 6 months with breastfeeding difficulties and support in identification of foster mother/wet nurses for orphaned children and safe distribution of breastmilk substitutes.
-	Provision of prevention and treatment of MAM cases using alternative methods/strategies including use of Tom Brown approach, distribution of MNP and cooking demonstration by organizing Training of Trainers (TOT) on Tom Brown Approach for other partners in Borno.
-	Provision of both Mobile and stationed Outpatient Therapeutic Programme (OTP) services integrated into Health and Educational facilities in MMC and Konduga LGAs Borno state.
-	Promotion of appropriate Infant and Young Child feeding and care practices (IYCF) through the formation of Mother-to-Mother Support Groups, Father-to-Father Support Groups house-to-house follow-up visits, radio talk shows, distribution of IEC materials, local drama groups, and mass awareness campaigns (roadshows, walks, etc.) targeting influencers e.g. teachers, religious leaders.
-	Provision of micronutrient supplementation to children and adolescent girls with supplies from UNICEF.
-	Conduct growth monitoring promotion (GMP) and screen children under five attending school/ECD centres for acute malnutrition and referral for treatment.
-	Promote the use school-going children as agents of change in the community by training and provision of MUAC tapes for them to screen for acute malnutrition in their households/communities.
- Mainstreaming Protection related issues into the project activities.
- Deploying the Community Management of At risk Mothers and Infants under six months of age (C-MAMI) in both our TOT and field activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Concern For Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Concern For Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abubakar M. Abbas</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager - Nutrition</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2347030768024</telephone>
   <email>abubakar.abbas@greencodeng.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dekims Titus</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Finance/Admin Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2348024803183</telephone>
   <email>dekimses@greencodeng.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edem Edem</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2348037114770</telephone>
   <email>eodem40@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG008">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Borno</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.88898010 13.15334698</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">199977.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-20697">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">199977.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Concern For Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305428274">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-09">159981.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Concern For Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
