<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-21/NIG_ERF/SA1/N/NGO/20390</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scale-up access and treatment of MAM in children under 5 years and pregnant and lactating women in Yusufari, Yunusari, Geidam and Tarmua LGAs of Yobe State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jireh Doo Foundation (JDF) will implement a 10-months project in Yusufari, Geidam, Yunusufari, and Tarmua LGAs of Yobe State. Given the significant impact recorded by JDF so far with the treatment of moderate acute malnutrition (MAM) for under 5 children and pregnant and lactating women (PLW) using locally made ready to use supplementary food (RUSF).JDF will focus on scaling-up treatment and access to quality lifesaving nutrition services, this will include malnutrition treatment services to Moderate Acutely Malnourished (MAM) children 6-59 months and Pregnant and Lactating Women (PLWs) through the provision of ready To Use Supplementary Food (RUSF)Action meal which is fortified with micronutrients. This approach has proven to be very effective as JDF has used it for over 4year with significant reduction in the rate of SAM which is similar to the tom brown approach and will be very successful given our implementing LGAs which lack adequate clean water and WaSH presence based on WaSH partner operation presence map.  
JDF has chosen infant and young child feeding promotion (IYCF) and voucher assistance to vulnerable caregivers. This will be achieved by scaling up CMAM services at target locations of Yusufari, Yunusari, Tarmua, and Geidam in Yobe State for the treatment of MAM in children under 5 pregnant and lactating women. To realize these objectives JDF will continue to work with the Primary Health Care Management Board (PHCMB) and the LGA structures in Yobe state. Through this project, JDF will reach 4800 moderate acute malnourished children in the project location (Yusufari 1200, Yunusari 1200, Geidam 1200, and Tarmua 1200) and 2000 PLWs (Yusufari 500, Yunusari 500, Geidam 500, and Tarmua 500) with RUSF to reduce the risk of deteriorating to Severe Acute malnutrition (SAM). The project will adopt an innovative infant and young child feeding promotion. JDF will ensure quality nutrition service delivery by strengthening the capacity of the existing health and community structures for sustainability, Systematic identification and referral of acutely malnourished children and pregnant and lactating women will be carried out. MAM cases will be treated by using fortified locally produced supplementary food (Action Meal). Undernutrition being a multi-sectoral problem with multi-sectoral solutions, JDF will provide hygiene kits to caregivers of MAM and PLW through the WASH supply pipeline, these caregivers will also be identified through our mother family MUAC approach strategy which has proven to be very effective and has strengthened the prospects of sustainability, This approach is relevant and compliant in the COVID-19 context with the restriction on movement and large gatherings, social distancing regulations and other COVID-19 prevention, and control methods. The approach will significantly reduce exposure between the nutrition service providers and beneficiaries.
The anthropometrics of children under this program will be monitored weekly. Children with severe acute malnutrition will be referred to existing OTPs. All these interventions will be integrated with preventive nutrition interventions such as IYCF counseling and social behavioral change communication. This will be situated within a comprehensive Social Behaviour Change Communication that will include Infant and Young Child Feeding (IYCF) program in Emergency, formation, and operationalization of Mother to Mother and Father to Father Support Groups where WASH, Health and GBV as well as COVID-19 messaging will be shared. JDF will adapt the manual developed by the sector and other partners for this component of the project. In addition, the project will raise awareness on COVID-19 mode of transmission and gender-responsive and inclusive prevention strategies. JDF will manage moderate acute malnutrition via the Targeted Supplementary Feeding Programme established for MAM children aged between 6-59 months amp MAM Pregnant and Lactating Women (PLW) using action meal</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jireh Doo Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jireh Doo Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Josephine Habba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2348036283457</telephone>
   <email>Jhabba@jirehdoo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jackson Emokpaire</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Nutrition Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2348135783412</telephone>
   <email>jemokpaire@jirehdoo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kingsley Okpabi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2348038731276</telephone>
   <email>kokpabi@jirehdoo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG036">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yobe</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.29868022 11.43706584</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-03"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-02"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-20">323650.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-20390">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-20">323650.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jireh Doo Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
