<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-21/NIG_ERF/SA1/N/NGO/20476</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of Community Nutritional and Tom Brown approach intervention in  Hong LGA  and Mubi north LGA of Adamawa state.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LABDI continues to trend for implementing highly stimulating and sustainable projects for children in Adamawa state with specific plan seeking to contribute immensely to the Nutrition sector needs to meet the overall objective of the nutrition response in 2022 which is to reduce morbidity and mortality associated with acute malnutrition and prevent the overall acute malnutrition among the most vulnerable members of the targeted community including children under five, vulnerable adolescent girls, pregnant and lactating women. The Nutrition Sector&#x2019;s lifesaving interventions will be targeted in all accessible locations, complemented with developmental activities. Directly applicable to the NHF 2021 First Standard Allocation, the Nutrition Sector response focuses on the transfer of knowledge and skills to the government, communities and local partners to address lifesaving needs and build resilience at community level. For example, to empower the community, the Nutrition Sector will scale-up the &#x201C;Mother/Father MUAC approach&#x201D; which involves training and providing households with MUAC (mid-upper-arm circumference) tapes to enable them to independently screen, identify and refer children with acute malnutrition.
centres/activities as a community-based structure to sustainably promote prevention and treatment of acute malnutrition and micronutrient deficiencies and an entry point to target vulnerable adolescent girls..
The crisis has also exacerbated pre-existing conditions of malnutrition, driven by a number of inter-related factors. These include weak health infrastructures poor infant and young-child feeding (IYCF) practices limited access to safe water and health and sanitation services the prevalence of water-borne diseases poor
hygiene conditions and seasonal food insecurity. More than 1.5 million people need life-saving nutrition services, comprising over 1 million children under
five (of whom about 200,000 are living with disability) and half a million women of reproductive age within the BAY states. Of the 1.5 million people needing
humanitarian nutritional services, 15% are IDPs, 15% returnees and 70% are in host communities. (HNO 2021,HPC 2021)

LABDI will be focusing on these two Nutrition sector priority needs: strengthen the quality and scale up preventive nutrition services for most vulnerable groups through supplementary feeding activities, appropriate infant and young child practices, micro nutrients supplementation and optimal maternal nutrition. Strengthen the screening, identification and referral of acute malnutrition among children under five, adolescents, pregnant and lactating women and Strengthen the screening, identification and referral of acute malnutrition of among children under five, adolescents, pregnant and lactating women. The following activities will be conducted during implementation so as to meet up with the overall objective of preventing and treating acute malnutrition and micronutrient deficiencies among children, adolescents, women and other vulnerable members of the targeted population. LABDI will also saves life by providing timely and integrated multisector assistance and protection intervention to the most vulnerable.
 Conduct growth monitoring promotion (GMP) and screen children under 5 in all target communities both children in Early childhood development(ECD) in school and out of school for acute malnutrition and referral for treatments.
 Conduct screening and referral of acute malnutrition among adolescent girls (risk of low birth weight) and refer for treatment at a decentralized medical center for appropriate medical care.
 MUAC screening to identify and refer acutely malnourished children, pregnant and lactating women. MUAC screening conducted by Community Health Workers (CHW) / community nutrition mobilizers (CNMs) through regular house-to-house screening and mass MUAC screening campaigns (integrated during other community activities e.g., EPI campaigns.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life at Best Development Initiative</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life at Best Development Initiative</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-11" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jabani James</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>08035077212</telephone>
   <email>jabani@labinigeria.org.ng</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ladi Clark Musa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>08032797074</telephone>
   <email>ladiclark@labinigeria.org.ng</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG002">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adamawa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.32322733 12.40024078</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-19">246117.17</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-19">7669.37</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-20476">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-19">253786.54</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life at Best Development Initiative</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305394403">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-25">101514.62</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life at Best Development Initiative</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305601620">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-31">76135.96</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life at Best Development Initiative</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
