<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="AR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>LB-MOI-497-1.7</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="LB-MOI-497" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD- Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rolling-out of 108 self-care sessions on a monthly basis for front-liners in each of the six governorates. Please refer to activity identifier  LB-MOI-497-DMFA-ABAAD19-21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBV front liners</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to complete this activity, the NMHP has invited the MHPSS Task Force organizations to a ToT from which 22 applicants were selected according to their educational background, years of experience and previous experience in conducting trainings after submitting a filled Google form and a signed letter of intent from their organization to conduct 5 self-care sessions for frontline workers. The 2 days ToT took place on the 15th and the 16th of October 2018 in the presence of an observer from ABAAD and facilitators from the NMHP (attendance sheet+ Agenda- Annex# 6). The master trainer from the NMHP presented the self-care manual at the first day of the ToT and explained to participants how to conduct the training, how to deliver the main key messages and how to use the self-care techniques in each domain. At the end of the first day, the master trainer assigned every person to a section of the manual in order to prepare it and present it the next day using one facilitation method as an example to what can be done in the actual self-care sessions. The entire second day was dedicated for the presentations of the assigned section of the manual, after every presentation the other participants as well as the master trainer and the observer from ABAAD gave constructive comments and feedback to improve the performance of participants when they start their own self-care sessions with front-liners. Evaluation sheets were distributed at the end of the first day to take the feedback of participants on the material and the master trainer. The compilation of the evaluation forms showed that 45% of participants thought the overall training was excellent and all of them answered yes when asked if they recommend the training to others. Training evaluation results: Figure 1: Training of trainers-Overall training rating Figure 2: Training of trainers-Training recommendation outcomes In terms of the training workshop the main points where participants strongly disagreed were: that the content is organized and easy to follow (14%), the training techniques and methods were useful and helpful (10%) and that the time allotted for the training was sufficient (10%). And more than 50% strongly agreed that the trainer was well prepared and knowledgeable about the training topics. Figure 3: Training of trainers-Training evaluation outcomes Refresher training A one day refresher training was scheduled as a follow up to the ToT and invitations were sent to all the participants who attended previously. The main goal of the refresher training was to further support participants in the implementation and roll out of the self-care sessions in a standardized and harmonized way. The refresher training session was held on the 14th of December 2018 with 15 participants out of the 22 (attendance sheet-Annex 7). During this session, the master trainer shed the light on important concepts and gave participants additional tips on how to conduct the sessions. The hand-outs and pre-post-tests that are supposed to be handed to frontliner&#x2019;s attending the self-care sessions were distributed to participants to get their feedback before their finalization. After the refresher session all participants were urged to start planning the 5 self-care sessions to frontliners taking into consideration that the first session should be supervised by a team member of the technical unit of the NMHP or by the observer from ABAAD team. Rolling-out of self-care sessions: The trainers started the first supervised self-care session with frontliner&#x2019;s from their own organizations, The supervisors (from ABAAD and NMHP) filled a trainer&#x2019;s evaluation form and constructive comments were given to the trainer onsite for them to improve performance in the next 4 unsupervised sessions. A Total of 54 self-care sessions in the six governorates for front-liners were conducted by 15 trainers completed their first supervised sessions targeting 412 participants from which 32 are males and 380 are females. Certificates were distributed to trainers who completed the training and held self-care sessions to frontliner&#x2019;s. Conclusion: The national self-care manual for front-liners is considered a guide for organizations who are interested in training their front-liners on self-care and providing them with practical tools and techniques to help them take care of themselves. Self-care component should be included in the policies of all organizations generally and in organizations working in the humanitarian field specifically. Those TOTs has created a group of trainers committed to training the largest number of front-liners possible in all of the sectors in Lebanon ensuring sustainability, however more TOTs are needed in order to create a wide pool of self-care trainers. Moreover, 28 info sessions about the manual were conducted, targeting around 560 of the GBV and CP front-liners In all regions, aiming at defining the guide, its objectives and the importance of its adoption and implementation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">ABAAD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q3 year 1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">Q3 year 2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">59400</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1.7">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">59400</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.RAR" url="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1jE7PubfDRCAJMWXSoec4cyhcA6fW2tkz">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">1.7 Documents Zip Folder</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="AR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="LB-MOI-497-Program" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">108 Self-care sessions</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="AR"># of self-care sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
