<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>LB-MOI-497-2.6</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="LB-MOI-497" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD- Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Produce a platform/ on-line interactive portal that will Produce first-hand gender sensitive reports and media pieces around women&#xFFFD;s and gender issues in conflict situations. Please refer to activity identifier  LB-MOI-497-DMFA-ABAAD19-21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As such, under &#x201C;NASEEJ&#x201D; project, Fe-male has re-constructed and re-launched &quot;Sharika wa Laken - SWL&#x201D;: https://www.sharikawalaken.media which is an independent women&apos;s news website based in Lebanon. The website is an initiative founded by Fe-Male and is a continuation of its work to raise awareness and advocate for women&apos;s issues in Lebanon, the Arab world in particular and the globe. Its team consists of a group of women journalists who are committed to human rights and the role of the media in raising awareness and achieving positive change in societies. The website&apos;s team focuses on monitoring and observing the reality of women in Lebanon and the Arab world, criticizing this reality, disseminating news about it, as well as supporting the work and struggle of women&apos;s and human rights organizations in Lebanon and the Arab world. SWL aims to be one of the main sources of news and information about women in Lebanon and the Arab world. The site is committed to the following principles: Freedom of expression of ideas, views and opinions, and producing news that are important to women in particular, and the public in general. It&#x2019;s also committed to gender-sensitive reporting and coverage in news editing, ensuring the security of data and the highest levels of accuracy through reliable sources, impartiality, transparency and objectivity, in addition to refraining from broadcasting any content that incites violence, sectarianism, racism, intolerance or discrimination. Preparation phase: - new visibility guidelines and lifting the logo, contracting a company that took care of rebuilding the website and data migration (so as not to lose the archive and the database of years), - Choosing the staff who will be working on implementing the activities and a meeting with several journalists and reporters who will be on board of the team producing material for the Facebook page and the website. - Elaborating the basic functionality required from the website: A preliminary study and analysis was made to serve as the basis for designing, developing and maintaining the track and approach for delivering an online interactive, engaging, multilingual and multicultural website. The website interface emphasizes on the ease of locating the required data within the minimum amount of time to all types of users and herewith the specifications of this website: - WordPress Solution: Setup a fresh WordPress site for hosting the new site/data. - Security: Several security measures/plugins to minimize to high extent security issues. - Performance Optimization/CDN: Caching measures to help speed up the site and optimize the site for fast loading, along with setup along with a &quot;Content Delivery Network&quot; for further speedup and experience optimization. - Theme: Setup, configure, and customize WordPress theme officially licensed. - Customization for proper display of content as needed and site functionality. - Core Plugins: Setup and configure essential plugins to handle data backup automation, SEO optimization, Google Analytics tracking and any other needed plugin. Moreover, Fe-male collaborated with over 30 journalists from Lebanon and the Arab world such as Egypt, Yemen, Palestine, and Jordanto produce written and video content, in addition to info graphics for the website. Which led to create a wide network of journalists who are willing to volunteer, ensuring sustainability, in writing for Sharika wa Laken because they know the value of work the SWL is doing and its impact on the new media. Nevertheless, during the span of this project: - 255 reports, articles and videos produced and published since SWL launching in November, 2018, - A total of 917 posts were migrated, this included posts which were set as draft/deleted status and were kept for legacy also as draft status under the new website, so only previously active posts are available as published. - A total of 12 categories were migrated. - A total of 1,600 tags were migrated. - All categories and tags have been properly associated with relevant tags. Tags and Categories properly link to their related articles via clicking on tag/category links - A total of 5,000 media images (different sizes) have also been migrated to the new site, and properly associated with each relevant article as featured images. - A total of 7 pages have been migrated. - 89.59% engagement on the site, with the traffic on the page reached 99.3% with a total of 9,698 views. link to the written content https://www.sharikawalaken.media/category/&#x645;&#x642;&#x627;&#x644;&#x627;&#x62A;- &#x648;&#x62A;&#x62D;&#x642;&#x64A;&#x642;&#x627;&#x62A;/ link to the videos https://www.sharikawalaken.media/category/videos/</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Despite the Right to Access Information Law that was passed early 2017, it is still very difficult in Lebanon to access data and information from government bodies. Fe-Male planned to develop a national web-platform to harness new media and data journalism, i.e. info-graph and multi-media all tailored to address key issues related to violations of women&#x2019;s human rights in addition to other human rights violations and active citizenship rights. This web-platform was to act as a digital citizenship and human rights&#x2019; magazine that produces cutting-edge, first-hand and evidence-based information, in addition to re-producing and representing existing information (studies, and produced knowledge) on related matters that are not accessible for the general public. More specifically, the web-platform team was to use investigative journalism to address key human rights and citizenship issues in the Lebanese society and act as a watch-dog for government work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Female</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-18" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">117000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2.6">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">86670</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1WkV9ete19_7fWsFYaVbxslE6bu1VajWr">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SWL Report</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="LB-MOI-497-Program" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Platform/ on-line interactive portal that will produce first-hand gender sensitive reports and media pieces around women&#x2019;s and gender issues in conflict situations</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of platform/ on-line interactive portals that will produce first-hand gender sensitive reports and media pieces around women&#x2019;s and gender issues in conflict situations</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-06-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
