<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="AR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>LB-MOI-497-2.1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="LB-MOI-497" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD- Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Production of a Code of Conduct between Media institutions/personnel and Women NGOs on gender-sensitive media coverage in conflict/post conflict situation. Please refer to activity identifier  LB-MOI-497-DMFA-ABAAD19-21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD sub-contracted a local feminist NGO called Fe-Male for the completion of these activities. Fe-Male is a civil feminist collective organization working with women and girls to eliminate injustice through building young feminist movement, empowering agents of change, and campaigning together against discriminatory norms and policies. Based on its strategic objectives, Fe-Male strives to improve the representation of women in media, and to eliminate the predictable social images that are projected on women and girls. Therefore, Fe-male was selected for their experience in working at the grassroots level in the media domain, and then trained. afterwards, using this extensive training, Fe-Male hired two consultants to write and produce the CoC, covering women&#x2019;s issues in media in Lebanon, a code that aims at challenging women&#x2019;s objectification in ads; and in covering women&#x2019;s issues, mainly women survivors of violence, during and post conflict situations . The need for this CoC is due to the gap in available media resources and means of protection specifically for women and children. Despite efforts to make media in Lebanon more protective, these groups remain vulnerable, particularly in the case of conflict and post-conflict contexts. The main goals of this code are as follows: - Develop practical recommendations for gender-sensitive media coverage, particularly on issues of violence against women in armed conflict and post-conflict settings - Encourage the application of CoC clauses and manifests its recommendations on a practical and ground-level, including practicing gender-sensitive media coverage that does not judge (vilify or glorify) experiences of women and children survivors of violence - Guarantee the protection of women and children survivors of violence from the harsh light of gender-insensitive media (e.g. the harsh and decontextualized depiction of women survivors of domestic violence or sexual assault) Five Focus Groups discussions were held in November 2017 , one out of which was held with GBV survivors and the remaining four were held with fifteen professionals each, including case managers, academics, researchers, decision makers, social and case workers, NGO media officers and coordinators, as well as journalists. The CoC has been finalized, translated, proofread by 3 experts, designed, printed and disseminated through actors in both GBV and media sectors/networks, and launched during the event that took place on the 29th of May 2018 at NDU university during a one-day conference entitled, &#x201C;A Voice of Our Own: Retelling the Stories of Gender Based Violence,&#x201D; that was organized by the Faculty of Law &amp; Political Science at the aforementioned University. The event was compromised of a gender NGO fair. TV host, writer, life coach, and trainer Milad Hadchiti hosted the opening ceremony, in the presence of the first Secretary of the Embassy of the Kingdom of Netherlands, Ms Bina Saib where she said, &#x201C;We need to step away from stereotypes and challenge ourselves to tell a nuanced and balanced story that engages the public.&#x201D; and the presence of Chairperson Dr. Dany Ghsoub where he called for &#x201C;the immediate implementation of the COC to deal with all kinds of exploitation and protect freedom from oppression&#x201D;. Moreover, an interactive panel discussion entitled &#x201C;A Voice of Our Own,&#x201D; took place during the event, moderated by the news reporter, writer, producer, and TV host Jad Ghosn. The Panel included Ms. Ghida Anani (ABAAD founder &amp; Director), Mr. Frank Elbers, Ms. Hala Bejjani, Ms. Nidal Ayoub, and Mr. Eugene Sensenig. The speakers all agreed that social responsibility requires us to construct GBV stories in a way that enables us to celebrate survivors. Following the event, NDU&#x2019;s FLPS professors vowed to continue their commitment to create an open space for people to communicate on gender-related issues by carrying out research projects, white papers, and a variety of GBV-related events, focusing on social justice and conflict resolution as well as considering including the toolkit in their curriculum - https://www.facebook.com/NaseejProject/videos/204940453634490/</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media institutions/personnel and GBV sector</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">Female</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">26500</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2.1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">26500</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.RAR" url="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1J7Gnnhvnn0i_H4RrE-2MOVUm3QFET4yq">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">2.1 Documents Zip Folder</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="AR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/COC-Arabic-20180330010320.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">CoC</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="LB-MOI-497-Program" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">CoC between Media institutions/personnel and Women NGOs on gender-sensitive media coverage in conflict/post-conflict situations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CoC has been finalized, translated, proofread by 3 experts, designed, printed and disseminated through actors in both GBV and media sectors/networks, and launched during the event that took place on the 29th of May 2018 at NDU university during a one-day conference entitled, &#x201C;A Voice of Our Own: Retelling the Stories of Gender Based Violence,&#x201D; that was organized by the Faculty of Law &amp; Political Science at the aforementioned University. The event was compromised of a gender NGO fair. TV host, writer, life coach, and trainer Milad Hadchiti hosted the opening ceremony, in the presence of the first Secretary of the Embassy of the Kingdom of Netherlands, Ms Bina Saib where she said, &#x201C;We need to step away from stereotypes and challenge ourselves to tell a nuanced and balanced story that engages the public.&#x201D; and the presence of Chairperson Dr. Dany Ghsoub where he called for &#x201C;the immediate implementation of the COC to deal with all kinds of exploitation and protect freedom from oppression&#x201D;. Moreover, an interactive panel discussion entitled &#x201C;A Voice of Our Own,&#x201D; took place during the event, moderated by the news reporter, writer, producer, and TV host Jad Ghosn.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CoC between Media institutions/personnel and Women NGOs on gender-sensitive media coverage in conflict/post-conflict situations</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
