<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="AR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>LB-MOI-497-3.2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="LB-MOI-497" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD- Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Up-scaling/replicating the current Men Center Model to provide engendered psycho-therapy sessions for Men and male youth with abusive behaviors. Please refer to activity identifier  LB-MOI-497-DMFA-ABAAD19-21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternatively and as stated in original project document, and in order to mitigate any delay, ABAAD raised the proposition to replicate the Men Center through MOSA existent SDC structures and the Ministry agreed on establishing Men Centers in three main areas in Lebanon: the South, the Northern ML and Baalbek and to contribute fully to provide the location and its operational expenses from MOSA side. The centers of the MOSA ensures very long term sustainability. Moreover, ABAAD is familiar with the MOSA structure and its hierarchical system and has been able to work within and around it, based on the signed MoU between ABAAD and MoSA. As such, no challenges are foreseen on that front and this buy-in from MOSA can ensure sustainability of the service beyond the project. Furthermore, replicating these structures under MOSA can come as complementarity step for the roll-out of the National GBV SOP being led by MOSA and can open the gate for wider replication across the country beyond the three centers solely. For this end, ABAAD organized bilateral meetings with MOSA and local authorities to concretize and establish the Men Center across Lebanon, as well as homogenize the aforementioned SOP, which led to sign an MOU with MOSA for the up-scaling of the Men Centers (annexed #18) in order to homogenize referral pathways to the Men Center, as well as the Red Cross and/or SDC for the provision of these services. The 3 areas were strategically chosen based on a service gap needs&#x2019; identification. More specifically, Baalback was chosen to complement ABAAD&#x2019;s Case Management Unit in Labweh &amp; MWH in Beqaa. South/Bisariyyeh also complement the Women &amp; Girls Safe Space in Bint Jbeil and the MWH in Southern Mount Lebanon. MoSA contributed with the physical structure, and ABAAD refurbished and equipped the centers in both areas , recruited the staff, managed and train the personnel composed of Psych-Social Worker, Case Worker, Center Coordinator as a permanent Staff and contracted with Psychotherapist form both areas. Both centers, begin running in the first half of 2018. In addition to this, MoSA contributed to normalize the concept of service provision specifically tailored for men and men&#x2019;s rights to receive psychosocial services based on their gender roles, and the potential violent impacts and forms witnessed by men based on societal expectations and manifestations. Hence, four (8) support groups (4 groups in each center), 12 sessions each group, were conducted in the center&#x2019;s catchment area targeting 108 adult men (74 Lebanese and 34 Syrian) With the aim at providing emotional support. The objectives revolved around providing participants with an open space to express and talk about daily stressors, expression of anger in a healthy way, and reflect on experiences of migration and exile in order to help the participants in &#x201C;re&#x201D;-creating complete narrative frames relevant to their personal stories. The participants were given an open platform to share fears and concerns as well as identify stress factors resulting from life events such as death, relationships and sexuality. In addition, the sessions contributed in providing the participating men and male youth with techniques and tools related to stress management, understanding gender roles, and acquiring positive coping mechanisms to respond adequately to the plight of the situation they are living in. The support group sessions were held over a period of two months for each group, covering three hours per session. The approach used in the delivery of support group sessions is based on a participatory model through which the participants debrief their emotions resulting from stressful events in a safe and trustworthy environment as well as reflect on their own experiences and thoughts. This exchange of opinions and experiences allows addressing misconceptions around topics of concern by setting the ground for a peer to peer support network that would be sustainable after the time of intervention is due. Themes and topics addressed: Through the above explained approach, two main layers, including several themes, were addressed as per the below: - Structured Psychosocial Support (GBV Oriented) - Identification of fears and concerns - Identification of anger and stress symptoms - Managing stress and anger - Emotional Support (Dealing with fears and concerns) - Death and separation - Friendship and relationships - Sexuality/Emotions Additionally, men participants in the support group sessions were referred to benefit from individual psychological services and follow up. This is considered as a first step toward achieving the purpose of the existence of the center in the area, since men statistically are less likely to seek help and more likely to discontinue participation in programs of psychosocial support period. This phenomenon is a result of the negative social stigma for men and help seeking behavior as it contradicts patriarchal masculine gender role socialization. Furthermore, during the span of the project, six workshops on &#x201C; Anger And Stress Management&#x201D; took place within 2018 (3 workshops in the South and Bekaa centers) trageting 76 beneficiary (40 Syrian men and 36 lebanese men). These sessions contributed as mentioned above in providing the participating men and male youth with techniques and tools related to stress management, understanding gender roles, and acquiring positive coping mechanisms to respond adequately to the plight of the situation they are living in. Moreover, three (3) Community / Sports Events based and aligned with the Men Center campaign objectives has been carried out, targeting 1,062 men (592 from Syrian nationality and 470 form the Lebanese nationality), in collaboration with the municipalities in the areas. These events constitutes of:Marathon: Ghazieh International Race on 25 Nov 2018 were 600 Men and teenagers: - male Run with the aim of stop violence, wearing T- shirts with the slogan of the Men Center Campaign (&#x625;&#x62D;&#x633;&#x628;&#x647;&#x627; &#x635;&#x62D;!) and the following activities tooked place: - MC flyers Distribution - Bracelets Dissemination, with printing the men center helpline number - Booth - in the presence of Municipality mayor and SDCs directors , 2 football teams (Male and female- gender equivalents) a mini football game took place were we: - Spread the messages of engaging men and ending VAW during the encouragements, - Distribute brochures about Abaad and men centers services - Distribute cups for the two teams and medals for the players In the interim, the center in Beirut was up-scaled to accommodate more capacity of sessions with men. As a direct result of the Men Center refresher campaign in September 2017, promoting as well the center&#x2019;s line, ABAAD witnessed an increased number of beneficiaries at the center, from both refugee and host communities. Hence, the center in Beirut now can accommodate sessions in parallel in addition to a large space for support group sessions and stress &amp; anger management workshops. - During the project period, around 400 men received psychotherapy sessions (around 4 sessions per beneficiary per month) as follows: 83.05% individual therapy, 14.41% couple therapy(only in Beirut Center), 2.54% family therapy(only in Beirut Center).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men and male youth with abusive behaviors</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the start of the project, ABAAD assessed the possibility of replicating the Men Center services at the Lebanese Red Cross (LRC) structures in both Tripoli and Saida and beyond. After several meetings with LRC head and concerned team, ABAAD identified possible challenges to proceed with LRC due to their hierarchical structure that might pose delays related to the prolonged and timely procedures they require, and that would span beyond the timeframe of the project. Furthermore, LRC is in process of developing their own internal GBV SOP system, and were leaning more towards on completing that process before deciding on scope of engagement in the GBV response (whether with men or women).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">ABAAD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">391900</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3.2">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">364714.71</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.RAR" url="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1AP_JPdCtdm_173-vhQfPy-UBLRHfe87b">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">3.2 Documents Zip Folder</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <language code="AR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Report-on-Men-Center-Campaign-2017-(2)-20180330020342.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Report-on-Men-Center-Campaign-</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="LB-MOI-497-PROGRAM" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD raised the proposition to replicate the Men Center through MOSA existent SDC structures and the Ministry agreed on establishing Men Centers in three main areas in Lebanon: the South, the Northern ML and Baalbek and to contribute fully to provide the location and its operational expenses from MOSA side. The centers of the MOSA ensures very long term sustainability</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="AR">For this end, ABAAD organized bilateral meetings with MOSA and local authorities to concretize and establish the Men Center across Lebanon, as well as homogenize the aforementioned SOP, which led to sign an MOU with MOSA for the up-scaling of the Men Centers (annexed #18) in order to homogenize referral pathways to the Men Center, as well as the Red Cross and/or SDC for the provision of these services. The 3 areas were strategically chosen based on a service gap needs&#x2019; identification. More specifically, Baalback was chosen to complement ABAAD&#x2019;s Case Management Unit in Labweh &amp; MWH in Beqaa. South/Bisariyyeh also complement the Women &amp; Girls Safe Space in Bint Jbeil and the MWH in Southern Mount Lebanon. MoSA contributed with the physical structure, and ABAAD refurbished and equipped the centers in both areas , recruited the staff, managed and train the personnel composed of Psych-Social Worker, Case Worker, Center Coordinator as a permanent Staff and contracted with Psychotherapist form both areas. Both centers, begin running in the first half of 2018. In addition to this, MoSA contributed to normalize the concept of service provision specifically tailored for men and men&#x2019;s rights to receive psychosocial services based on their gender roles, and the potential violent impacts and forms witnessed by men based on societal expectations and manifestations</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
