<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="AR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>LB-MOI-497-2.3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="LB-MOI-497" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD- Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organizing three national capacity building workshops with around 75 media personnel on the produced toolkit, to ensure gender-sensitive reporting of cases on GBV. Please refer to activity identifier  LB-MOI-497-DMFA-ABAAD19-21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media institutions/personnel</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The set of three training workshops based on the above mentioned toolkit produced by Fe-Male was conducted on 28-29 of September 2018 and on 12-13 and 19-20 of October 2018 targeting journalists and reporters from various areas in Lebanon, were the workshops&#x2019; agenda was based on the toolkit&#x2019;s content. For the selection, an announcement was shared on social media as well as sent via mailing list (attached in the annexes folder), and all applications were received through a Google form (https://goo.gl/forms/5rhgWEwQgLu2SZtP20 . The criterion upon which the trainees were selected was the years of experience. Around 100 journalists and media personnel in local and international NGOs applied to participate in the workshops, but only 75 (53 females and 22 males) were selected. Those who sat for the first training were those with minimal years of experience. The trainers were selected based on their expertise and knowledge: Dr. Nahawand Al Kaderi, a university professor and a researcher in media, Dr. Khouloud Al Khatib, a human rights and fundamental freedoms defender, researcher and trainer in the fields of human rights and international, regional and national protection mechanisms, Ms. Sanaa Khoury, independent Lebanese journalist, specialized in cultural journalism. She is known for her critical articles, and follows the popular culture and women&apos;s affairs in the Arab region and the world, Ms. Aliaa Awada, a journalist and a feminist activist with a twelve-year experience in human rights, equity and gender, she is co-founder at Fe-Male and has worked in advocacy and campaigning at different local and international organisations, and Ms. Reem Maghribi, an editor, publisher, and communications consultant. She develops and runs projects that center on documentation, communication and the media. The results of the pre/post tests showed a great improvement in all three trainings. The percentages were increase in knowledge by 58%, 92%, and 92% respectively in the three workshops. To ensure the toolkit&#x2019;s sustainability, Fe-Male has published it online and it&#x2019;s an available resource for anyone to adopt; be it a student, academician, journalist, activist or expert. In addition, Fe-Male plans to use this toolkit in its future trainings as well as planning to organize a TOT so that its content spreads among all journalists.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="LB-MOI-497" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD - Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">21300</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2.3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">21300</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.RAR" url="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1EtHV7tZ_EAqSoOYkPF0kW3HvllGCG5oA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">2.3 Documents Zip Folder</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="AR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="LB-MOI-497-Program" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">National capacity building workshops with around 75 media personnel</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR"># of National capacity building workshops with media personnel</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="AR">The set of three training workshops based on the above mentioned toolkit produced by Fe-Male was conducted on 28-29 of September 2018 and on 12-13 and 19-20 of October 2018 targeting journalists and reporters from various areas in Lebanon, were the workshops&#x2019; agenda was based on the toolkit&#x2019;s content.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
