<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>LB-MOI-497-1.8</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="LB-MOI-497" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD- Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Production of a national toolkit/curriculum on the psychological considerations while dealing with couple dynamics in cases of Intimate Partner Violence or GBV. Please refer to activity identifier  LB-MOI-497-DMFA-ABAAD19-21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Despite the work of NGOs in advocating for women&#x2019;s rights and protection, violence against women remains pertinent in Lebanese society. One of the most silent and normalized forms of violence is IPV. For this reason, ABAAD chose to create a national toolkit/curriculum on the psychological considerations of dealing with couple dynamics in this case. In the past, ABAAD&#x2019;s psychotherapists conducted training on IPV for the ISF. Throughout these trainings, these psychotherapists assessed a need for a more sustainable and structured tool to deal with IPV and couple dynamics. In response to this need, ABAAD, in coordination with Tabyeen (a national psychotherapy supervision center in Lebanon) and the ISF, had finalized the production of a national toolkit on the psychological considerations of dealing with couple dynamics in cases of IPV or GBV. This toolkit is comprised of an operational manual and annexed with a conceptual framework of the agreed-upon considerations. This toolkit not only considers the woman&#x2019;s position, but also the men&#x2019;s role in participating in the rehabilitation and amendment of the situation. It stresses the importance of engaging men with violent or abusive behaviors in the solutions for IPV, and, on a broader level, VAW. On that level, this toolkit takes a multifaceted and proactive approach to dealing with couples in these circumstances. Among other provisions, it offers: - Coordination between security, judicial and legal work, criminal investigative work, and protective psychological work (diagnosis, classification, treatment, and rehabilitation), in order to build a coherent and integrated system for legal, social and psychological development; - Building the capacity of security officials in the ISF to deal with victims and perpetrators of IPV; - Link national security phenomena with global security, personal security and psychological security; - The establishment of investigations, verifications and judgment of IPV in the framework of gender equality, justice and neutrality; - Developing listening, writing and speaking skills in dealing with IPV phenomena among ISF officers. This activity complements the development of ABAAD&#x2019;s GBV SOP (the part related to ISF) as well as the CM Curriculum, as they share similar objectives. This manual will serve as a training material to all ISF internal workshops.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Internal Security Forces</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="LB-MOI-497" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD - Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q2 year 1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q4 year 1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">43100</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="1.8">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-24">41711</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000000210" ref="XM-DAC-7"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.RAR" url="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1Fja5fr3fmuYPGZ1d0R5Kuj4OghOCb-Fy">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.8 Documents Zip Folder</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="LB-MOI-497-Program" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National toolkit/curriculum on the psychological considerations of dealing with couple dynamics in cases of Intimate Partner Violence (IPV) or GBV for Internal Security Forces</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of national toolkit/curriculums on the psychological considerations of dealing with couple dynamics in cases of Intimate Partner Violence (IPV) or GBV for Internal Security Forces</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-08-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
