<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="AR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>LB-MOI-497-1.3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="LB-MOI-497" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD- Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Production of the Arabic version of the GBV Case Management Training Curriculum in close coordination with GBV sector in Lebanon. Please refer to activity identifier  LB-MOI-497-DMFA-ABAAD19-21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">An expert consultant was subcontracted to produce the National GBV Case Management curriculum, the first of its kind nationally and regionally and in the local language. After completion of desk research on the available resources, the first drafts of the main handbook and the facilitator&#x2019;s guide (a tool designed to provide the trainer with all needed resources) were finalized. The GBV Case Management Curriculum is finalized, composed of 17 modules as following: - Module 1- Gender - Module 2: Sociology of Gender - Module 3: Human rights - Module 4. Women&apos;s rights - Module 5. Gender equality - Module 6. Gender analysis - Module 7. Gender-based violence - Module 8. Causes and effects of gender-based violence - Module 9. Combating gender-based violence - Module 10. Integrated Case Management - Module 11. Case identification steps - Module 12. Evaluation phase - Module 13. Planning phase - Module 14. Implementation and follow-up phase - Module 15. Closing of the Case - Module 16. Case manager - Module 17. Communication skills - Forms This final version of this curriculum serves as a tool for Non GBV specialists, academic personnel, university students and GBV specialized, to get introduced to the GBV concept, problematic and the Case management process. It is also worth mentioning that each module of this curriculum is considered as a standalone training package, allowing diversity of themes and topics for trainings and workshops related to GBV prevention, and ability to target participants with different background and experience. Additionally, ABAAD worked on producing 7 animation videos on the &#x201C;Do&#x2019;s and Don&#x2019;ts&#x201D; for case workers during their work with GBV survivors that were included in the mobile application and circulated among the GBV actors and their case workers/ case managers. ABAAD sub-commissioned the same mobile developer who created RESPOND mobile App to produce the animation videos. Between September 2017 and June 2018, seven animation videos were completed. Following are the YouTube links to the videos: - How to deal with disclosure: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9-wXWt01r7s - Recommendations for Staff: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y2LiUcXAkYY - Types of Disclosure: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FmLFsPrTzTo - Informed Consent: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IXPrfDSOu6U - Home Visits: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YRqZM5vUrZc - Referral Process: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jSSaNVwjDzE - Dealing with Survivors: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6945df0-raU&amp;t=9s</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBV sector</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">ABAAD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q2 year 1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q3 year 1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">105800</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="1.3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">109200</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000000210" ref="XM-DAC-7"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1LdJTvC5folCRiuuOac-lxjzgb5oBbQDM/view?usp=sharing">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">Case Management Curriculum</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="AR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="LB-MOI-497-Program" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arabic version of the GBV Case Management (CM) Training Curriculum</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">An expert consultant was subcontracted to produce the National GBV Case Management curriculum, the first of its kind nationally and regionally and in the local language. After completion of desk research on the available resources, the first drafts of the main handbook and the facilitator&#x2019;s guide (a tool designed to provide the trainer with all needed resources) were finalized.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arabic version of the GBV Case Management (CM) Training Curriculum</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-09-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
