<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="AR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>LB-MOI-497-1.5</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="LB-MOI-497" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD- Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organizing four (4) national TOTs on the produced tool. Please refer to activity identifier  LB-MOI-497-DMFA-ABAAD19-21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">GBV case and social workers</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pursuant to the development of the GBVCM curriculum and the animated SOPs, ABAAD conducted 3 national ToT workshops on the use of the tool. Each of the capacity building workshops were held for 5 days starting February 2018; The first workshop was targeted 29 ABAAD frontline personnel including social workers and case workers as a pilot testing, to assess and validate consistency with planned objectives, to correct deviation from original plan, to enhance and improve quality of the curriculum, to troubleshoot potential gaps in knowledge and information delivery, to address specific needs of information by relevant audience, the second workshop was targeted 15 social workers at the Social Development Centers under the Ministry of Social Affairs, and the third workshop was targeted 15 from the Lebanese University&#x2019;s Faculty of Public Health with the fourth year students of Medical Social-work Faculty. In total, 64 social workers, case managers, front line personnel, and care providers were targeted under this activity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The workshops aimed at building the capacities of the aforementioned personnel on GBV Case management and standardizing the case management system in the response programs using ABAAD GBV CM curriculum. The training was based on the developed curriculum in addition to the instructional video on GBV case management &amp; SOP (using the video under the GBV SOP mobile app. The toolkits focused on the do(s) and don&#x2019;t(s) in working with survivors and aimed at building local actors capacities in various steps of case management in addition to the conceptual framework and the SOPs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="LB-MOI-497" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD - Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-30">33900</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1.5">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">26867.98</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.RAR" url="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ELRehaL2Rp6SxrJZB9Fncd_kVyBDhLuo/view?usp=sharing">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">1.1 Documents Zip</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="AR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="LB-MOI-497-Program" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">Four (4) national TOTs (on the produced CM curriculum)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="AR"># of national ToTs on the CM curriculum</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
