<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="AR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>LB-MOI-497-3.7</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="LB-MOI-497" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD- Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Launch a nation-wide media campaign to announce for the help-line GBV holistic services. Please refer to activity identifier  LB-MOI-497-DMFA-ABAAD19-21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a part of ABAAD&#x2019;s advocacy strategy, the First organized media campaign aims to shed light on holistic services available to survivors to ensure their accessibility That being said, in 2017, ABAAD conducted two nation-wide campaigns to promote the up-scaled Men Center services (71283820). The campaign aimed at sensitizing the public audience in Lebanon about the services of the Men Center.s</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The campaign included an out-door campaign along with a promotional TV spot (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FM8KcrPKIR8) . The TVC portrays a man&#x2019;s voice self-reflecting on conflicting emotions: fear, sadness, and anger. Emotions that have resulted of tiredness, stress, irritation, and at times a feeling of ineptitude and inadequacy. The trigger of these stressors were the loss of an income source among other reasons. &quot;Do I lose control, or do I cry?&quot; pondering this man&#x2019;s voice. Facing this self-reflection, we see an abused woman trying to hide the bruises on her face, and another woman not showing any bruise, as the silence sometimes hurts much more than any word could. The campaign introduced the services of the Men Center to the general audience as it was able to reach a nation-wide audience through 1000 billboards across the country, tens of community awareness sessions with men along with Men Center Line number distribution, social media and tens of media outputs. The TVC calls for men to consider the effects that anger, abuse, neglect, or violence could have on men&#x2019;s families. It warns them not to wait until it is too late. It informs them that the low-cost, confidential, and anonymous services of the Men Center is a phone call away. On another note, the project/the Netherlands contributed as well to the 16 Days National campaign of Activism Against VAW 2017 Advocacy campaign calling upon increased sentences in case of incestuous rape by covering printed and audiovisual materials promoting the central Helpline (81788178) to ensure accessibility of GBV survivors to protection services and encourage disclosure. Direct link to Poster: http://www.abaadmena.org/documents/ebook.1511865964.jpg flyers: http://www.abaadmena.org/documents/ebook.1513600656.pdf TVC: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g5nejQHvKIU</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">nation-wide media campaign to announce help-line for holistic GBV services</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="LB-MOI-497" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD - Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">230000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="3.7">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">230000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XI-IATI-497-Program" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">media campaign aims to shed light on holistic services available to survivors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="AR">Between September and October 2017, over 150 calls were registered on the Men Center log, 47% of which were provided with appointments to start receiving individual psychotherapy sessions. Approximately 2/3 of these calls were a result of the visibility that was provided by the Men Center campaign, through the billboards and the TV spot. in year 2016, the Men Center assisted 40% of its beneficiaries to increase healthy non-violent communication skills.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
