<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="AR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>LB-MOI-497-3.5</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="LB-MOI-497" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD- Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of multi-sectoral services namely legal education sessions, psycho-therapy sessions, as well as CMR services for women survivors of SGBV. Please refer to activity identifier  LB-MOI-497-DMFA-ABAAD19-21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD&#x2019;s Women and Girls Safe Spaces (WGSS) throughout the country (North, Bekaa, South, Beirut and Mount Lebanon) that provides direct prevention and response services for women and girls survivors or at risk .</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women SGBV survivors residing in Lebanon</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">the overall aim is to protect vulnerable women and girls from violence, exploitation, abuse and neglect, including GBV, the eight Model Centers provide holistic care (case management, legal consultations, court representation, CMR services, psychotherapy, psychiatric evaluation and follow up) as well as referral (GBV/family violence protection orders) to emergency safe housing (Al Dar) and soft skills/economic empowerment training</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="LB-MOI-497" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAAD - Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">388283</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3.5">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">386360</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On going services through ABAAD centers and shelters</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000000210" ref="XM-DAC-7"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.RAR" url="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1KAW3yidszYaDzBaKV4HufOsN4SkQwpMN">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">3.5 Documents Zip Folder</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="AR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/cedaw-leaflet---8-2-18-20180330020331.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="AR">cedaw-leaflet-</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="AR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/WGSS-Meal-forms-20180330030329.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WGSS-Meal-forms</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="LB-MOI-497-PROGRAM" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PROVISION OF MULTI-SECTORAL SERVICES NAMELY LEGAL EDUCATION SESSIONS, PSYCHO-THERAPY SESSIONS, AS WELL AS CMR SERVICES FOR WOMEN SURVIVORS OF SGBV</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="AR">These WGSS&#x2019;s, during the span of the project, provided services for 34,861 women and beneficiaries as showed below: - 23 Women benefited from Psychiatric consultations, - 13 women benefited from Forensic doctor consultations , - 843 women benefited from Case management [2] sessions , - 164 women benefited from Individual psychotherapy sessions - 82 women benefited from Legal counselling sessions, - 122 women benefited from Community-based groups [3], - 946 women benefited from Socio-economic empowerment [4] sessions, - 20,229 women, girls, boys and men benefited from Sensitization sessions [5], - 438 women benefited from Group Therapy women - 12,001 women, girls and men&amp; Boys benefited from PSS cycles, using the Basic Life Skills toolkit (BLSP). Additionally, under this component, ABAAD partnered with: - Women Working League Association (WWLA) to address the need to increase knowledge about legal rights and the Lebanese Labor Law, National Social Security Fund (NSSF) &amp; Personal Status Codes. This legal education aims at empowering women to be more socially and socioeconomically engaged, as to decrease rates of structural and domestic violence. Legal awareness sessions were provided by lawyers and experts free of charge to 397 women. By learning about personal-status and labor laws, women make better-informed decisions and are given more agency. Parallel to this, WWLA conducted legal consultation sessions for 150 women across the reporting period. These sessions aimed to provide direct and accessible information about personal status laws and their restrictions on women&#x2019;s rights in Lebanon. The women receiving the consultation were often in compromising circumstances and received information about potential legal steps they could take going forward. - AFEL, a specialized CP and GBV national NGO, provided 24 awareness sessions/ Psycho- Social Support (PSS) activity targeting 512 children at risk for or survivors of SGBV, in addition to 132 case management sessions for 90 Care- Givers and 102 case management sessions for 63 Children. Also, AFEL provided 72 individual psychological follow-up sessions for 18 children and one support group with 6 sessions for 18 children. - Committee for the Follow-up on Women Issues in Lebanon (CFUWI) to address the issue of women&#x2019;s rights in the international framework mainly (CEDAW), for this end, CFUWI has developed a flyer on the international protection mechanism and CEDAW convention, and had executed 16 awareness sessions about this subject targeting 485 women (279 Lebanese and 206 Syrian) participants in the 4 governorates of Lebanon. - PALWHO, that conducted 100 Psychotherapy sessions for 20 women (5 sessions each), 18 Health Education sessions targeting 180 beneficiaries, 5 PSS activities targeting 100 women. Another partner, PALWHO, conducted psychotherapy sessions for 12 women (5 sessions each) and PSS activities for 50 women.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-03-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-01"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
