<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="29" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/21607" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-5-21607</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nepal Earthquake Recovery</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">After more than two years in Nepal, All Hands Volunteers has impacted over 20,000 people throughout our response and recovery efforts.  A total of 2,775 volunteers from 72 countries have donated 54,795 days toward putting families back in homes and kids back in schools in the districts of Kathmandu, Sindhupalchowk, Nuwakot and Thulo. Across Nuwakot, four schools &#x2013; Bachchhala Secondary, Pritvhi Secondary, Kalyani Devi Secondary and Jalpa Devi Secondary &#x2013; were built, with 35 new classrooms provided and also new WaSH facilities (water &#x2013; sanitation &#x2013; hygiene) with both toilets and clean water.

In Sindhupalchowk, Bachchhala Devi Secondary was completed in April 2017. Then Chamuna Primary, Kakaling Secondary and Janakalayan Primary schools were all finished in July 2017 &#x2013; providing 23 classrooms and yet more WaSH facilities.

In addition to building these schools, the teams added renewable energy and new playgrounds, but they didn&#x2019;t stop there. Already, they have spearheaded many critical Renew projects driven by community needs, including female masonry training, school reading projects and language lessons. In addition we continue to collaborate with each community to identify community-led projects where we can work side-by-side with community members  to accomplish their goals and get work done. Examples include rebuilding WaSH stations for the community so they have access to clean water  to building new community staircases to replace those damaged from landslides and allow families to pass safely to school.

After more than two years, the Nepali people are still in dire need and children are still unable to go to school or are attending unsafe, temporary schools. As a result, All Hands Volunteers have re-focused our efforts on one goal &#x2013; getting the children of Nepal back to school.  So far, we have directly helped an estimated 8,000 children get back to school in Nepal and in the process, have impacted thousands more across whole communities.

Program Nepal re-opened in September 2017, after closing briefly for the monsoon season, and we are now operating in Haibung. Base construction is nearing completion and Community Engagement projects are underway.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">On April 25, 2015, a 7.8 earthquake hit Nepal near the capital city of Kathmandu, the worst of its kind in more than 80 years. More than 9,000 people were killed, a further 23,000 were injured and the destruction to infrastructure and homes was massive.  Over 5,000 schools schools were either damaged or completely destroyed. On May 12, 2015, a second 7.3 earthquake struck the country, causing further devastation and loss of lives. 72 hours after the first earthquake, All Hands Volunteers arrived and got to work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-20-3414952" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">All Hands and Hearts - Smart Response</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="5-21607" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All Hands and Hearts - Smart Response</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.hands.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="29" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Construction</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="3" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Prevention and Preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="5" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
