<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011894-01-3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Social business e sviluppo innovativo della filiera agro-industriale nella regione di Thi&#xE8;s (SB-AGROIN)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social business innovative development of the agroindustrial value chain in the Thi&#xE8;s Region (SB-AGROIN)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto ha lo scopo di aumentare la sicurezza alimentare e il reddito dei piccoli produttori agricoli sviluppando la filiera agroindustriale nella regione di Thi&#xE8;s. Il progetto vuole rispondere ai sopra citati problemi migliorando le tecniche produttive dei piccoli agricoltori e sviluppando la filiera agro-industriale, principalmente la vendita e diffusione di fattori produttivi innovativi e la trasformazione dei prodotti ortofrutticoli e la loro commercializzazione. La logica &#xE8; che la maggiore produzione ortofrutticola generata da tecniche migliori e innovative contribuisca al raggiungimento della sicurezza alimentare per i produttori dediti all&apos;autoconsumo e costituisca un aumento di reddito per coloro dediti alla loro commercializzazione. Questi ultimi potranno vendere in modo costante i prodotti a imprese capaci di trasformarli e commercializzarli. L aumento della produzione sar&#xE0; ottenuto tramite iniziative di formazione su tecniche agricole, che coinvolgeranno 1.200 piccoli produttori, utilizzo e produzione di migliori sementi, e l&apos;adozione di innovazioni in campo agricolo quali: gestione tra pi&#xF9; piccoli produttori di sistemi integrati di pozzi/pannelli solari/pompe e irrigazione goccia a goccia e/o adozione di sistemi Agritube che consentono una resa produttiva maggiore con un considerevole risparmio idrico. Il progetto si propone di installare 6 sistemi integrati in terreni comunitari di 6 villaggi e 18 sistemi Agritube(3 per ogni villaggio). Queste azioni serviranno soprattutto a mostrare ai piccoli produttori il loro funzionamento e resa. La loro diffusione sar&#xE0; promossa tramite un fondo rotativo gestito dai partner di progetto e al quale i piccoli produttori potranno accedere per finanziare i miglioramenti produttivi necessari. Si prevede che almeno 300 piccoli produttori accederanno al fondo rotativo per tale scopo. Per sviluppare la filiera agroindustriale il progetto collaborer&#xE0; strettamente con la rete delle donne produttrici e trasformatrici di Ker Moussa di cui fanno parte 65 donne. Per lo sviluppo della filiera agro-industriale si prevede di sviluppare le seguenti imprese: un&apos;impresa di trasformazione di frutti ortaggi e cereali, un&apos;impresa che produca e installi i sistemi Agritube, un&apos;impresa che si occupi di installare sistemi integrati di pompe/pannelli solari/goccia a goccia. Cos&#xEC; come per le innovazioni in campo agricolo anche la costituzione delle imprese sar&#xE0; finanziata con il fondo rotativo in una logica di ownership e presa in carico da parte dei beneficia</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to increase food security and income of small agricultural producers by developing the agro-industrial supply chain in the Thi&#xE8;s region. The project aims to respond to the aforementioned problems by improving the production techniques of small farmers and developing the agro-industrial chain, mainly the sale and diffusion of innovative production factors and the transformation of fruit and vegetables and their marketing. The logic is that the greater fruit and vegetable production generated by better and innovative techniques contributes to the achievement of food security for producers dedicated to self-consumption, while it constitutes an increase in income for those dedicated to their marketing. The latter will be able to sell products to companies that are able to transform and market them. The increase in production will be achieved through training initiatives on agricultural techniques, which will involve 1,200 small producers, use and production of better seeds and the adoption of innovations in the agricultural field such as: management between smaller producers of integrated systems of wells/solar panels/pumps and drip irrigation and/or adoption of Agritube systems that allow a higher production yield with considerable water saving. The project aims to install 6 integrated systems in community lands of 6 villages and 18 Agritube systems (3 for each village). These actions will mainly serve to show small producers their functioning and yield. Their dissemination will be promoted through a revolving fund managed by project partners and from which small producers can draw from to in order  to finance the necessary production improvements. At least 300 small producers are expected to access the revolving fund for this purpose. To develop the agro-industrial chain, the project will work closely with the Ker Moussa network of women producers and transformers consisting of 65 women. For the development of the agro-industrial chain it is planned to develop the following companies: a company that processes fruit, vegetables and cereals, a company that produces and installs the Agritube systems and a company that deals with installing integrated systems of pumps/solar panels/drip irrigation. In the same way as for innovations in the agricultural field, the constitution of companies will be financed with the revolving fund in a logic of ownership and take over by the beneficiaries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASES - Agricoltori Solidariet&#xE0; e Sviluppo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011894/01/3" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+ 39 06 32492 305</telephone>
   <email>info@aics.gov.it</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">via Salvatore Contarini 25, 00135 Roma</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31165" percentage="60" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural alternative development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="32161" percentage="10" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agro-industries</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="32130" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Small and medium-sized enterprises (SME) development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-01">800136</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-01">480081.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-01">320054.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-10">800136</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-011894" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
