<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-21/DDA-3482/3RA/PROT/NGO/19125</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advocacy, monitoring and documentation of HR and IHL violations and related trends in the Gaza Strip and West Bank</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project supports the ongoing efforts of the three implementing partners (Al-Haq, Al Mezan, and PCHR) to monitor and document the violations of IHR/IHRL in the Gaza Strip and West Bank. 
The proposed project will contribute to timely documentation and collection of evidence of human rights and International Humanitarian Law (IHL) volitions committed by Israeli military during the &#x2018;Guardian of the Walls&#x2019; operation as well as ongoing IHLR/IHL violations committed thereinafter in the Gaza Strip, including grave violations against children. The project will also entail monitoring and documentation of human rights violations in the West Bank, with focus on grave violations against children, settler violence and excessive use of force against protected persons in East Jerusalem, H2 and Area C, with a view of intensifying international advocacy and information sharing to push for concrete actions.

The project objective is directly linked to Humanitarian Response Plan Country Level Strategic Objective 1: The rights of Palestinians under occupation are protected in accordance with IHL and IHRL, and linked to strategic result statement 1 of the Protection Cluster: 1. Increased respect for International Humanitarian Law and Human Rights Law and Accountability for Violations. 
The project will be implemented by three independent human rights organizations which are Al-Haq, Al-Mezan and PCHR, and it will last for six months starting from June, 2021.
The activities of the project will vary between monitoring and documentation, reporting of the violations and advocacy activities to push for actions against these violations.

Additional fieldworkers/researchers will be deployed in the Gaza Strip to support existing fieldworkers (senior fieldworkers) to complete documentation of incidents of violations recorded in the recent military offensive, inter alia, incidents of killings, maiming of women and children, damage and complete destruction of buildings, vehicles, farmlands, livestock farms, water wells, schools and other public institutions. Lawyers will also support in documentation of key incidents and collection of affidavits to build legal case files for future engagement with international justice mechanism. About fifteen thousand violation forms are expected to be completed through interviews with victims and/or witnesses before being verified and inserted into electronic database, with supporting evidence, including official documents, testimonials and affidavits. Partners expect to conclude the documentation related to the 11-day offensive within the first three months of the project.

The collected information will be utilized for publication of regular weekly and monthly updates on violations in the Gaza Strip and the West Bank, a number of thematic reports/factsheets, multiple audiovisual material, and one comprehensive report on the recent military offensive on Gaza, all of which will be widely circulated through implementing organizations&#x2019; websites, social media accounts and mailing lists. Field data on the recent military offensive as well as ongoing human rights violations in Gaza and the West Bank will also shape and feed into implementing organizations&#x2019; international advocacy, including submissions to and communications with UN mechanisms, particularly the Human Rights Council 47th and 48th regular sessions, the UN Special Procedures, and the UN HRC Commission of Inquiry.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Haq</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Mezan Center for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Center for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Center for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feda&apos; Murjan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">fundraising and program officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0598763623</telephone>
   <email>fmurjan@pchrgaza.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Raji Sourani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PCHR-Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0599608811</telephone>
   <email>pchr@pchrgaza.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-03">161349.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-03">32906.73</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-19125">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-03">194255.85</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Center for Human Rights</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305137122">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-10">77702.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Center for Human Rights</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
