<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-21/DDA-3482/1SA/EDU/NGO/20966</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Psychosocial Support for Vulnerable Students Affected by Education-related Violations and COVID-19 in Gaza Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The education system in Gaza Strip has been hit hard. It faces several challenges and obstacles as a result of prolonged education-related violations including attacks on schools and inadequate safe school infrastructure. These challenges have been significantly compounded by the outbreak of COVID-19. Based on assessment conducted by the MoE, it showed that the public schools in Gaza Governorate have recently witnesses heavy attack by the last escalation on Gaza Strip. It has resulted in a severe deterioration of the already precarious living conditions of the people in Gaza. Thus, this project will be implemented in Gaza Governorate and will target 10 public schools in Gaza Governorate (5 in East Gaza Directorate  and 5 in West Gaza Directorate). 
The project proposed duration will be 12 months aiming at providing psychosocial support for vulnerable school students, staff and parents who have been affected by the education-related violations and COVID-19. In specific, the project will respond to the psychosocial issues faced by 1150 students aged from (6-15) and 100 teachers alike as a result of the coercive environment they are subjected to. The data of the target students will be obtained from MoE database, and will be verified by the project staff.  The data verification will be approached by contacting the school counselors to get more data about the cases as well as organizing home visits to meet the student&#x2019;s parents or caregivers who will provide the social workers and the psychologists more information about the students life.
Also, the project will target 250 parents to ensure effective participation and community support for student during project implementation. 
In this context, this project shall be achieved through the implementation of the following activities:
1. Train the projects&#x2019; staff and schools&#x2019; counselors through conducting a package of trainings on: 
1.1 Training on PSS methodology that will be adopted as a psychosocial tool to ultimately develop the personal and social skills of vulnerable students, and therefore improve their resilience and psychosocial wellbeing. 
1.2 Training on &#x201C;Remote Pscyhosocial Support&#x201D; to equip the trainees with the skills needed to enhance the psychosocial services provided to teachers, students, and parents during the crisis.
1.3 ToT on &#x201C;Psychological First Aid&#x201D; (PFA) to equip the trainees with the skills needed to assess the immediate concerns and needs of an individual in the aftermath of a crisis.
2. Provision of individual and group counseling activities for the most affected students including students with disabilities. Also, structured psychoscocial recreational activities will be provided for students through the implementation of activities including psychodrama, puppet shows, theatre, storytelling, drawing, and music. These activities will be provided in cooperation with the schools&#x2019; counselors to improve the overall psychosocial wellbeing following the IASC guidelines, and use different methodologies developed by PSCF. 
3. Provision of sessions on (PFA) and self-care targeting school student, teachers, and parents. Sessions will be age, gender and diversity friendly. 
4. Conduction of joint child-parent activities for 100 families. These activities will be provided to enhance the protective environment of the students, improving the communication inside the family and a better understanding of each other. These families will also benefit from the PFA sessions.
5. Providing target schools with equipment and materials needed including LCDs, laptops and its accessories, so they can provide the essential psychosocial services for students during the crisis and other times. 
6. To address the learning and psychological needs of the students with disabilities and students with development learning disorders, 4 resource rooms will be upgraded and 20 resource room teachers will be equipped with skills needed to run the activities in the room.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestine Save the Children Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestine Save the Children Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afaf Al Khaldi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>082626285</telephone>
   <email>info@pscf.ps</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-16">196291.41</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-16">49241.49</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-20966">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-16">245532.9</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestine Save the Children Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
