<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-21/DDA-3482/3RA/SNFI/INGO/19027</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing an emergency assistance to respond to the shelter and NFI needs of vulnerable households affected by the May 2021 hostilities in Middle Area, Khan Younis and Rafah governorates, Gaza Strip</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to support the most vulnerable households affected by the May 2021 hostilities in the Gaza Strip through the provision of emergency assistance to respond to the shelter and NFI needs. This will be achieved through the provision of cash for partially damaged shelter repair and the distribution of essential NFIs to vulnerable HHs furthermore, a complimentary cash assistance for transitional shelter and one-off reintegration package will be provided to most vulnerable IDPs, as well as the provision of cash for NFIs and/or adaptation works, contributing to reduce hosting and IDPs families&#x2019; vulnerabilities. Throughout the implementation of all activities, COVID-19 prevention measures will be integrated to ensure the safety of beneficiaries and staff. 

Specifically, ACTED and the local implementing partner Unlimited Friends Association for Development, will implement a multi-pronged approach in Middle Area, Khan Younis and Rafah governorates to restore shelter and NFIs standard needs of vulnerable households and IDPs, through the following means: 

-	Conducting a technical assessment to define precise needs for shelter repair on partially damaged shelters and NFIs through the production of detailed Bills of Quantities (BoQs) and their subsequent remedy through clear workplans
-	Providing cash assistance and technical support for shelter rehabilitation and upgrade to the most vulnerable households 
-	Providing in-kind NFIs to the same vulnerable households living in partially damaged houses, where needed
-	Facilitating shelter transitional solutions for IDPs whose shelter is uninhabitable or totally destroyed through the provision of cash for renting or minor shelter repair
-	Providing a one-off cash reintegration package to the IDPs 
-	Providing cash for NFIs and/or improving their living conditions through shelter adaptation works for hosting families and hosted IDPs  
-	Providing on-the-job coaching and mentoring of Community-based Protection Committees (CBPCs).

In total, the project will directly benefit 280 households in the Middle Area, Rafah and Khan Younis governorates, comprising 1,596 individuals and 18 members of CBPCs.  First, 150 households living in partially damaged homes and in need of urgent restoration will benefit from both the provision of restricted cash repair assistance for minor/partial damages (activity 1.1.2) and in-kind NFIs distribution (activity 1.1.3). Secondly, 80 IDPs families whose houses were totally destroyed and whose houses were uninhabitable will benefit from both the cash assistance for transitional shelter solution (activity 1.1.4) and the provision of a cash one-off reintegration package (1.1.5). In addition, 50 hosted families (IDPs families living in hosting families) and hosting families will benefit from the provision of cash for NFIs and/or improve their living condition (activity 1.1.6). Finally, 18 CBPC members (of 3 CBPCs) will be monitored and receive on-the-job coaching (activity 1.1.7).

The project will be supported by the mainstreaming of an Integrated Protection Approach (IPA), with a specific focus on the most vulnerable groups, including women, girls, boys, the disabled, and the elderly. Gender principles will be mainstreamed throughout the entire action and CBPCs will be refreshed about referral mechanisms of protection cases such as gender-based violence (GBV) with a particular focus given to women and children. Finally, Accountability to Affected Populations (AAP) will be core to the proposed Action by giving account to, taking account of, and being held to account by affected populations. The proposed intervention is in line with the Shelter cluster&#x2019;s objective 1,3 and 4, and has been developed and will be implemented in coordination with the Shelter Cluster, the Ministry of Social Development (MoSD) and other shelter partners, including PUI, NRC and MAAN.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unlimited Friends Association for Social Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ginny Haythornthwaite</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+970 598111809</telephone>
   <email>ginny.haythornthwaite@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-11"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-16">472677.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-16">27322.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-19027">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-16">500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
