<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-21/DDA-3482/1SA/PROT/INGO/21069</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enabled and inclusive community based MHPSS and GBV services in East Jerusalem and Areas C in Ramallah and Tubas</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the West Bank (WB), including East Jerusalem (EJ), Palestinians continue to face a coercive environment due to excessive use of force by Israeli armed forces, in addition to Settler violence, in addition to the continued effects of Covid-19. 
The proposal is based on the findings of a Rapid Needs Assessment (RNA) conducted by Terre des hommes in  Gaza, West Bank including East Jerusalem in May 2021 amidst the crisis. The main health concern expressed by respondents was mental health, presented as stress, a psycho-social or well-being issue of importance not just in terms of current presenting symptoms and conditions, but in terms of future psychological and physical health. Children and youth are especially at risk, facing arbitrary arrest and risk of violence. The findings revealed that EJ is among the areas with the highest MHPSS needs as reported by the key informants&apos; interviews, and that women and girls were among the most affected. Currently, there is insufficient provision of services: there are very few Palestinian specialised organizations providing services in Jerusalem. The project directly contributes to the SRP Objectives 2 and 3, as it strategically aims at creating conditions for CP and GBV prevention and response mechanisms to be accessible to 9 communities in hot spot areas in East Jerusalem, and Area C in Ramallah and Tubas, especially for people with disabilities. In East Jeursalem, the project will target Sheikh Jarrah, Old City and Shufat camp. In Ramallah, The project will target Deir abu Mushal, Saffa and Kufr Neimeh and in Tubas, the project will target Aqaba, Ein Al Beida and Attouf (Tamun). The action will strategically focus on strengthening community-based protection mechanisms, through building the capacities of Community-based organization service providers to provide qualitative and inclusive CP MHPSS and GBV responses. This includes adapting the MHPSS models to disability inclusion,  capacity building and coaching of Community volunteers and CBO staff on raising awareness, providing MHPSS structured support, case management processes, safe identification and referral of CP cases and referral of GBV cases. In addition, the project will build their organisational capacity in disability mainstreaming, safeguarding and PSEA. The proposed interventions equip the targeted communities to establish functional community protection mechanisms, and enhance the sustainability of these services, which is vital, especially when formal protection mechanisms are lacking due to security conditions in area C and/or when lockdown is imposed due to COVID 19.
The project project reflects good complementary among project partners, Tdh&apos;s technical capacity in terms of MHPSS, GBV and case management,  YWCA  through  its long terms presence in targeted localities ( Jerusalem, Ramallah and Jericho) and strong connections with the targeted CBOs in the different localities, and Stars of Hope for empowerment of women with disability in disability mainstreaming throughout all project activities.
The project will directly target 4024 persons ( 1026 males, 1018 women, 990 boys, 990 girls) including 370 persons with disability ( 170 women, 100 boys, 100 girls) and indirectly target 5000.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stars of Hope Society for empowerment of women with disability</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Lausanne</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Lausanne</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young Women Christian Association Palestine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young Women Christian Association- Jerusalem</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HPSE21-PRO-CPN|PRO-GBV|PRO-MIN|PRO-170980-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-27" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elizabeth Cossor</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCD Country Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>962777778174</telephone>
   <email>elizabeth.cossor@tdh.ch</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vanda Younan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head Of Jerusalem and West Bank Office</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>972549700748</telephone>
   <email>vanda.younan@tdh.ch</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HPSE21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">occupied Palestinian territory 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-31">305494.51</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-31">94505.49</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-21069">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-31">400000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Lausanne</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
