<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-21/DDA-3482/3RA/PROT-EDU/INGO/19040</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive summer recreational activities providing vulnerable children with MHPSS support and Explosive Ordnance Risk Education Awareness Sessions.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HI designed a 3-months action aiming to support vulnerable children affected by May 2021 escalation providing non-formal education services and PSS support through inclusive recreational summer activities and enhance their safety with Explosive Ordnance Risk Education (EORE) Awareness sessions 
The proposed intervention is fully aligned with the Third Allocation Strategy May 2021 and the 2021 Humanitarian Needs Overview. It also supports the achievement of 2021 HRP, specifically Objective 2 &#x201C;the basic needs of vulnerable Palestinians living under occupation are met through the provision of quality basic services and improved access to resources, in accordance with the rights of protected persons under IHL&#x201D;.
The project is needs-based designed and tailored on the findings and recommendation of the Flash Appeal of May 2021, Education Cluster including Summer Activities Working Group: Protection Cluster including the Mining Action Working Group (MAWG). It responds to the identified priorities of the Third Reserve Allocation: ensuring that children can access safe and inclusive learning opportunities through the provision of non-formal education services and reducing deaths and injuries caused by Explosive Remnants of War (ERW) and Explosive Ordonnance Disposal (EOD).
The project will implement Inclusive Summer Activities targeting 1,860 boys and girls including 700 children with disabilities in the 5 governorates of the Gaza Strip to support vulnerable children psychologically affected by May 2021 escalation. Caregivers, family, and community members will participate during the open-day session where the participants will present the recreational activities outputs. The action is built on the previous experience of HI in implementing inclusive summer activities for boys and girls with and without disabilities since 2015. In addition, two local implementing partners with extensive experience (more than 20 years) on the provision of community recreational and non-formal education activities and summer activities have been selected: Tamer Institute for Community Education (Tamer) and The Culture and Free Thoughts Association (CFTA). The summer activities will be designed in session of 2 days each, 6 sessions will be implemented in each governorate targeting between 60 to 70 boys and girls each session, in line with the MoE COVID indications. The summer activities will include, sport activities, expressive and creative art activities, cultural and life-skills activities and adolescents led-initiatives. 
CFTA and Tamer facilitators and animators will be trained by HI to develop their skills and knowledge to adapt summer programs activities, materials, and equipment for the use of children with disabilities and ensuring their inclusion.

Within its second outcome HI will conduct a Needs Assessment on EORE to identified risk area, vulnerable target groups and mean of communication setting priorities and support the coordination with other relevant actors (i.e. Demining Working Group members) avoiding duplication and more important exclusion of persons at risk. Explosive Ordnance Risk Education session will be included in the summer activities enhancing children&#x2019;s skills in recognize the risk and apply correct behaviour to increase their safety. Tailored training will be implemented to ensure a child-friendly approach and the application of the Do Not Harm principle considering the sensitivity and level of trauma children are already exposed</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Culture and Free Thought Association (CFTA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tamer Institute for Community Education</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-27" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federico Dessi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+962799245995</telephone>
   <email>f.dessi@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laurent Palustran</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Manager Palestine</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+972 (0) 545 270 704</telephone>
   <email>l.palustran@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="74" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="26" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-10-27"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-10">220449.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-19040">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-10">220449.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305143809">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">220449.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
