<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-21/DDA-3482/1SA/WASH-FSL/INGO/20980</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian response to improve access to services for the unserved communities in Hebron H2 restricted neighborhoods  Area C: A collaborative response in WASH  FSL sectors</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AAH&#x2019;s proposed project aims to address the needs listed in the 2021 oPt Humanitarian Needs Overview (HNO), specifically WASH and FSL needs for vulnerable families in Um Sidra community in Area C of Hebron governorate and H2 area of Hebron city. This multisectoral project aligns with AAH&#x2019;s 2021 Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP) (HPSE21-WSH-171018-1) and the clusters&#x2019; strategic objectives. In addition, the project comes in line with the pillars of the Inter Cluster Coordination Group (ICCG) Action Plan for Hebron H2 area. This project presents a pioneering intervention in intersectoral collaboration (WASH in Agriculture) in Area C by providing access to sewer services for vulnerable households (HHs) alongside providing more opportunities for agricultural and irrigation solutions as well as introducing solutions to enhance the communities&#x2019; resilience to the negative consequences of climate change and supporting more environment-friendly practices in Area C. Through this project, vulnerable families living in H2 and in Um Sidra will have improved access to sanitation and hygiene services, in particular the families living in the &#x2018;closed military zone&#x2019;. In addition, the project targets Um Sidra community in Hebron governorate to provide a sewer network system with a treatment plan that would assist the community in securing access to a sewer system and in providing more environment friendly living conditions as well as assisting the community in agriculture in terms of securing processed water for agricultural usage. The project is based on the identified needs and in line with the coordination process with the relevant stakeholders Hebron municipality, Palestine Water Authority (PWA), the Ministry of Agriculture (MoA), and local councils and communities&#x2019; representatives in both areas.
The project includes two main interventions: first, the construction of a sewer water network for a targeted neighborhood in H2 Area (Al-Kassara) to connect 400 HHs with a sewer network. This network will connect the houses in the area to a sewer lifting station constructed by the Hebron municipality(Annex 1 Hebron municipality letter). This will entail joint implementation with the municipality which will implement the structural and electromechanical work of the lifting sewage station in line with this intervention. Second, construction of a sewer water network to connect 40 HHs with a small-scale sewage treatment plant in Um Sidra community. This will be a pilot intervention that provides a complete solution for the sewer problem in the community, where the sewer water will be treated and used for irrigation and public purposes. 
Most of H2 HHs do not have adequate access to sanitation facilities due to the lack of proper infrastructure in the Area. The HHs rely on the construction of septic tanks to discharge wastewater, which adds many financial and environmental risks to the already existing risks in the area. The same for Um Sidra community, which is located in Area C to the south of Ramadeen town and suffers from lack of sanitation services in addition to other risks pertaining to its location. The intervention will provide treated water for multi usage trees and forage irrigation as standardized by the permitted laws, increasing green areas in the community, arboreal farming, and treated water usage for other public use. 
This activity is expected to meet one of the most urgent WASH needs of the targeted families and to alleviate their suffering, improve access to services, and enhance their resilience. 
AAH has an extensive experience of working in H2 area and other sensitive locations in Area C, and a strong understanding of the current protection concerns and legal situation. AAH will promote active engagement of all partners and community members during all phases of the project to ensure a community-based approach, wide participation and sense of ownership and awareness of their rights.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Accion Contra El Hambre (Action Against Hunger )</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Accion Contra El Hambre (Action Against Hunger )</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-27" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dalia Sbeih</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+972 543 326 550</telephone>
   <email>dsbeih@pt.acfspain.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="17.68" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="82.32" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-27"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-29">498000.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-20980">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-29">498000.69</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Accion Contra El Hambre (Action Against Hunger )</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
