<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-21/DDA-3482/1SA/HNC/NGO/21009</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing COVID-19 rapid diagnostic testing in all Gaza Strip governorates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The indicators regarding the epidemiological situation of Covid19 in the Gaza Strip show that they are escalating despite their slowness, amp the expectations of the MoH indicate that the Gaza Strip is a candidate to receive the 4th wave of Covid19 at the beginning of next year. These expectations come in light of limited health resources available in the MoH, especially for facing Covid19 pandemic. 

Hence, the project&#x2019;s idea comes in response to the coming stage by providing COVID19 rapid diagnostic testing for early detection of Covid19 cases, as the service will be provided free of charge for 50,000 persons of both sexes amp of all age groups, including PWDs in all governorates of the Gaza Strip through AWDA&#x2019;s 8 health facilities that spread throughout the Gaza Strip. 

Results of positive and negative cases will be registered at MoH&#x2019;s HIS, while samples of positive cases will be sent to the MoH&#x2019;s lab. for a confirmatory examination via PCR. 

As part of raising awareness about preventing the spread of COVID19 pandemic, leaflets will be distributed to the detected cases including guidelines on self-care during the quarantine period, in addition to preventing transmission of infection to other people.

The project will work in an integrated manner with the MoH to reduce the burden on the Ministry on the one hand amp contribute to early detection of cases amp limit the spread of the pandemic on the other hand. Where the project idea was coordinated with the MoH amp the Health Cluster Coordinator, who expressed their support for the idea (MoH support letter is attached). 

It is worth noting that the AWDA has experiences in fronting COVID19 pandemic, as it carried out activities related to health follow-up of home quarantine cases, adding to its contribution to the COVID19 vaccination campaign in coordination with the MoH. Moreover, Al-Awda Hospital provides COVID19 rapid testing to admission amp maternity cases adding to persons from the community, also Al-Awda Hospital owns a PCR lab. Accordingly, this project came to expand AWDA implemented activities to limit the spread of the COVID19 pandemic.

Concerning access to information, the local community will be informed about the project activities, locations amp AWDA complaint system through radio spot amp facebook advertisements. 

Due to the short project duration (3 months), AWDA management has prepared the tender doc. to purchase the COVID19 rapid tests, so the procurement process can start immediately after the approval of the project proposal (Tender doc. is attached). And to provide the project services to the targeted No. of beneficiaries, the service will be provided in 8 AWDA&#x2019;s health facilities (6 facilities over 2 shifts/day amp 2 facilities 1 shift/day), therefore lab. technicians amp data entry workers will be hired, as the data entry workers will document the results of the tests (positive and negative) on the AWDA&#x2019;s amp MoH&#x2019;s HIS to monitor the detected Covid19 cases amp to conduct a statistical analysis of the documented positive cases to follow the epidemiological curve.

In application of the principle of Do No Harm amp to ensure that COVID19 infection is not transmitted to those attending the AWDA&#x2019;s health facilities, rapid examination units will be separated from the facilities&#x2019; units, amp PPE will be provided to ensure the safety of the project staff amp the beneficiaries in addition to the implementation of safety amp prevention protocols implemented in accordance with WHO amp MoH guidelines. amp to provide maximum protection against SEA, the project staff will learn about AWDA&apos;s PSEA policy amp will sign work contracts that include a special clause about the mandatory adherence to PSEA. 

In the context of involving the local community in all phases of the project, they were involved in identifying needs (Needs assessment is attached) amp they will be involved in the monitoring amp evaluation of the project through FG amp questionnaires.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Awda Health and Community Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Awda Health and Community Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-07" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jehan Al Aklouk</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundraising Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0599731994</telephone>
   <email>j.aklouk@awda85.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-07"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-12">240850.58</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-21009">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-12">240850.58</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Awda Health and Community Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305581607">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-19">240850.58</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Awda Health and Community Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
