<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1148143-SDN - 003</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1148143" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholder Democracy Network</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building inclusive political representation in Rivers State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will aim to increase political participation and representation by women and young people in Rivers state in the run up to 2023 election and secure policy commitments and actions by political aspirants, representatives, and political parties, in response to the demands of women and young people</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;At least 300 young people and women (aiming for at least 65% female, and at least 50% aged below 35) who will have increased skills, experience and networks as a result of their participation in the campaigning, policy and influencing programme, increasing their opportunities to advance their ambitions in politics and/or social movements. Out of this number, 240 community advocacy members (10 per community) and 60 beneficiaries drawn from civil society, activists, influencers, the media and students will be engaged to mobilise citizens and actively participate in campaigns to further their organisational and social objectives. 

The indirect beneficiaries of the project are women and young people across Rivers state, and particularly those in the four focus LGAs, who are intended to benefit through increased opportunities for political participation (including campaigns to encourage increased voter registration and transfer) and an improved response by those in positions of power to policy priorities relevant to them. The estimated total population of Rivers is 7.3m (NBS, 2016) and for the four LGAs: Obio/Akpor (649,000), Port Harcourt (756,600), Okrika (312,300) and Ogu-Bolo (105,800). While up-to-date and detailed population data do not exist, it is reasonable to assume the target demographic (young people aged 18-35 and women aged 18 and over) comprise at least a third of the population. 
&quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-CHC-1148143 - SDN - 003" ref="NG-CAC-73022" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger Delta Stakeholders Initiative for Community Development and Empowerment</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-CHC-1148143 - SDN - 003" ref="GB-CHC-1148143" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholder Democracy Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-CHC-1148143 - SDN - 003" ref="GB-CHC-1148143" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholder Democracy Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholder Democracy Network</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@stakeholderdemocracy.org</email>
   <website>https://www.stakeholderdemocracy.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15151" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-03"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-09-03">184257</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-04-01">235743</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="1st Year Funds - 1st Tranche">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-10-14">128775</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1st Year Funds - 1st Tranche</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1148143 - SDN - 003" ref="GB-CHC-1148143" type="21"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1st Year Funds - 2nd Tranche">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-01-31">55482</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1st Year Funds - 2nd Tranche</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1148143 - SDN - 003" ref="GB-CHC-1148143" type="21"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2nd Year Funds - 1st Tranche">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-05-25">75183</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2nd Year Funds - 1st Tranche</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1148143 - SDN - 003" ref="GB-CHC-1148143" type="21"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Q1 Expenditure 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-12-31">126147</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Q2 Expenditure 2022">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-31">43952</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome: To initiate a sustained process of increasing female and youth representation in politics and improved engagement with political representatives in Rivers State via: 
- Increasing political engagement by women and young people in the run up to 2023 election
- Securing commitments and actions by political aspirants, representatives, and political parties, and Rivers State Government (including the State House of Assembly) which respond to the policy demands of women and young people in the areas of political representation, unemployment and soot pollution</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This entails the the government, political parties, and INEC are influenced by project to initiate or implement existing policies, take actions or commitments that promote women, young people and PwDs inclusion and participation in decision-making and democratic processes.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OC Indicator 4. %  of estimated potential registrants in project target LGAs that participated in the 2021/2022 CVR exercise disaggregated by young people, women, PwD, and general</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="5" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baseline study shows that Rivers State has at least 1.2 million potential registrants to be targeted  by INEC through the ongoing 2021/2022 CVR exercise. An estimated  63% of this 2023 estimated eligible voters are young people, and 48% are women. 


The 4 project target LGAs  forms 36% (445,400) of potential registrants to be targeted by INEC in Rivers State.  Only 5% of the potential registrants was captured as at baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="45">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 45% of the estimated potential registrants  (especially young people, women including PwDs) in target LGAs registered during the 2021 CVR process compared to the 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <dimension name="Gender"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OC Indicator 2. Number and type of commitments made and actions taken by political aspirants, representatives and political parties to deliver on the demands of the Women and Youth Agenda for Rivers State.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reviewed project advocacy engagement diary</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least  six (6) commitments or actions secured from political aspirants, representatives and political parties which make provisions to  deliver on the demands of the Women and Youth Agenda for Rivers State.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No commitment recorded yet</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OC Indicator 1. Number and type of commitments made and actions taken by political aspirants, representatives and political parties which make provisions to increase the representation of women and young people in party positions, as electoral candidates and in appointed positions, as a result of project campaign and advocacy activities.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reviewed project advocacy engagement diary</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least commitments or actions secured from political aspirants, representatives and political parties which make provisions to increase the representation of women and young people in party positions, as electoral candidates and in appointed positions</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Speaker of the  Rivers State House of Assembly (Hon Ikuinyi O. Ibani) during the International Women&apos;s Day peace walk protest conveyed by SDN in collaboration with other CSOs  committed to sponsor and support motions, bills, agendas, and policies target at improving women representation in political administration in Rivers State</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OC Indicator 5. Level of change in the perception of young people and women about the value of engaging in the democratic process, level of confidence in the electoral process, and willingness and interest to engage in politics (e.g. by voting or running as a political candidate) in target LGAs.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator measures the interest and confidence of young people and women in the electoral processes in Rivers State</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="23" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">While 23% are confident, an average percent (77%) of sampled women and youth across the four LGAs are not confident on the electoral processes in River State. 

An average of 45% sampled women and young people demonstrated high interest and 27% slightly interested to participate in various democratic processes</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;OC Indicator 6. Commitments and actions taken by INEC to facilitate greater voter registration and transfers by women and youth voters
&quot;</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1: Women and young people in Rivers state, with a particular focus on four local government areas, are supported to become more politically active and engaged with the democratic process in advance of the 2023 elections.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator 1.1: Number of frontline ambassadors (women and young people) who successfully complete leadership, campaigning, policy and influencing skills training (disaggregated by gender, age)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">At baseline, the porject was still identifying and selecting ambassadors</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="300">
      <dimension name="Gender" value="50"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Train 300 frontline ambassadors</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="298">
      <dimension name="Gender" value="51"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">298 frontline ambassadors (51% female, 49% Male; also 66% between 35 years and below) drawn from 24 communities across project target LGAs, and CSOs were sucessfully trained on leadership, campaigning, policy and influencing skills.

72% of the frontline ambassadors demonstrated improved knowledge  on leadership campaign, policy and influencing skills.This was measured via pre-and-post knowledge test</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 1.4: Estimated reach of public campaign activities (e.g. in person, via radio, social media) to promote voter registration, transfer and participation (disaggregated by communication channel)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">At baseline, the project are yet to implement campaign strategy</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3,500,000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directly reach at least 5000 and indirectly 3,000,000 Rivers state citizens on voter CVR through project campaign channels</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2,027,000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SDN has used both traditional and digital media platforms to sensitise Rivers State citizens on the ongoing Continuous Voter Registration (CVR), our weekly radio programme which airs on NigeriaInfo Fm 92.3 and Wazobia Fm 94.1 has indirectly reach at least an average of 2,000,000 listeners that tunes in weekly to the radio programme across the two radio stations used for the project campaign.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 1.3: Number of frontline ambassadors (disaggregated by gender, age) who actively participate in the delivery of the campaign activities (e.g. by producing social media content, attendance at advocacy activities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Campaign was not ran at baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="240">
      <dimension name="Gender" value="50"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 240 frontline (50% women) ambassadors are activitly involved in the delivery of the campaign activities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="240">
      <dimension name="Gender" value="51"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">240 ambassadors from 24 communities  (composing 81% of the trained frontline ambassadors) activiely engaged in sensitizing and mobilizing their community members to register in the ongoing CVR process. So far the project has recorded 34 instances where the community ambassadors either sensitized or mobilized citizens to register in the ongoing CVR in Rivers State.

The ambassadors have directly reached and sensitized above 27,000 individuals across the 24 target commuties and has influenced an average of  500 persons to register to get PVC for the 2023 election in Rivers State</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator 1.2: Estimated number of people reached through campaigns to provide advice on voter registration, voter transfer, and positive messages about youth and female political participation.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">project was still planning campaign strategy at baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3,500,000">
      <dimension name="N/A" value="N/A"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directly reach at least 5000 and indirectly 3,000,000 Rivers state citizens on voter CVR through project campaign channels</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2.1: Support the civil society cluster to develop and deliver campaigns on specific civic space issues in each state, and establish a process of regular, constructive dialogue between the civil society Output 2: A mass campaign is mobilised with women and young people in Rivers State in the run up to the 2023 elections, to engage election candidates, existing political representatives, and political parties to call for action to increase the representation of women and young people in politics, and respond to their priority policy concerns.cluster and State governments, where it is possible to challenge government and other actors without fear of repercussions.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.7 Number of other organisations, interest groups, celebrities and influencers that endorse the Women and Youth Agenda for Rivers State</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agenda is noy yet produced at baseline and other organisations, interest groups, celebrities and influencers are yet to be engaged</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30">
      <dimension name="Stakeholder Types"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 30 organizations, interest groups, celebrities and influencers endorse the women and youth agenda in Rivers State</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.8 Number of political aspirants, representatives, and political parties who participate in at least one advocacy engagement (e.g. launch event, one-on-one meetings, roundtable discussions), including disaggregated data on position, party etc.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no engagement activities by project at baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 10 stakeholders (political aspirants, representatives, and political parties ) participates in at least one project advocacy engagement</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.1: Existence of campaign strategy document, which is reviewed and updated with a range of stakeholders at least on a quarterly basis</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the initiative of the project to be developed by the ambassadors</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">One comprehensive campaign strategy developed and readily available for use</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.4 Number of individuals who participated in consultations/the provision of suggestions/inputs to the Women and Youth Agenda for Rivers State (disaggregated by age and gender, if possible to collect this data)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="240">
      <dimension name="Gender" value="50"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consult  at LGA level, all the 24 communities (10  women and youth representative each) to document suggestions/inputs to the Women and Youth Agenda</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="213">
      <dimension name="Gender" value="51"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">213 community members (female =109 ; male = 104 ; - figure including 10 PwDs) across the 24 communities actively participated by making valuable input during the Women and Youth Agenda consultation meeting.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.3 Number of individuals (disaggregated by gender, age and affiliation) who were actively involved with delivery of the campaign (as measured at the end of year one and two)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="300">
      <dimension name="Gender" value="40"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 300 people (40% women, 60% youths including PwDs) are actively involved with the delivery of the campaign</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="60">
      <dimension name="Gender" value="40"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SDN in collaboration with women groups in Rivers State such as GADA, Kebetkache, ALIVE, Mother of Good Counsel, We-YOU Ambassadors, male champions estimated at about 60 persons marked the IWD with a peace walk to protest the rejection of 5 Gender Bills by the NASS. The group made significant stops at the Rivers State Judiciary, the NUJ and finally the Rivers Sytate House of Assembly. The group was addressed by the Speaker of the House who showed support and commitment to improve women represenattion in political administration in the State</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.5 Existence of a Women and Youth Agenda for Rivers State, validated and completed in consultation with expert stakeholders in Rivers State</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Youth Agenda readily available for use</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
