<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="UAH" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>UA-EDR-39795443-SUB1177-2020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="UA-EDR-39795443" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO &#x201C;Centre for Economic Strategy&#x201D;</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project UA2002: Donbas Economic Transformation Strategy Support</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to support the Ministry of Reintegration of Temporarily Occupied Territories of Ukraine (MTOT) in its efforts to prepare the ground for drafting a Donbas Economic Transformation Strategy focused on government-controlled areas of region. The technical assistance will enable the MTOT to prepare an outline national support framework for the region. The framework will provide the critical parameters and thematic elements of the strategy and lay out the GOU&#x2019;s approach to re-energising economic growth, facilitating domestic/foreign investments, and deliver tangible economic benefits to the citizens in the region</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-10633588" role="1" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abt Britain Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Milestone #1
Output 1: Diagnostic report on the current state of Donbas, gaps, and challenges that the strategy should address, taking into account GESI perspective
Milestone #2
Output 2: Report on assessed policy options, modelling results and recommended policy options for the Donbas Economic Transformation Strategy (including GESI consideration)
Milestone #3
Output 3: TOR for legal experts to draft legislative and regulatory changes needed for implementation of the policy initiatives

Output 4: Set of documents for the Donbas Economic Transformation Strategy, including short-listed policy options and KPIs, and a roadmap for the implementation of the Strategy, which will be GESI-sensitive and citizen-oriented</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will be implemented in three phases: (1) Data collection and analysis; (2) Collection of assumptions and modelling; (3) Developing policy options and implementation roadmap. It will form a package of documents and outline the necessary legislative changes for development, adoption and implementation of the Donbas Economic Transformation Strategy, with the long-term goal of helping to stabilise the economic and social situation in Donbas. Data collection will include analysis of various studies, statistical data, interviews with key stakeholders and target groups (including major donors with related TA). Based on the deep and comprehensive analysis, a set of potential policies in priority areas for the Donbas region&#x2019;s development will be prepared and tested through a modelling exercise to come up with a shortlist of the most effective policies to be included into the Strategy and further implemented by the GoU. The project has a special focus on GESI-related analysis, including a review of the current situation from the perspective of women, IDPs and other vulnerable groups, as well as impact assessment of the suggested policies in order to avoid any harmful effect on vulnerable groups and in the best case improve their current conditions.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The reintegration of Donbas Region temporarily occupied territories and sustainable development of the area under Ukrainian control is a strategic national priority for the President and the Government of Ukraine (GoU). Developing a holistic strategy for economic transformation of Donbas (controlled territories), as well as tools for its implementation, is seen as a key instrument for stabilising the conflict-affected region via facilitating economic growth, attracting foreign investment, boosting local business, creating jobs, and protecting vulnerable groups. The project will provide the GoU with a set of inputs to draft an evidence-based people centred Donbas Economic Transformation Strategy including a methodology, analytical products, economic modelling, public consultations, policy recommendations.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="51010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">general programme assistance (when not allocable by sector).</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-18">135387.24</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
