<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-29002</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zain-Iraq Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provide needed investment in a priority fragile and conflict affected country:  Iraqs economic growth has been stunted by years of political instability and violence. The limited private investment that has reached the country has been concentrated in the real estate and oil sectors, which account for over 75% of total FDI. This investment will contribute to the strengthening and diversification of the Iraqi economy. 

Expand telecommunications services: With a population of 30 million and per capita income of US$3,000 (PPP terms), Iraq is one of the poorest countries in the Middle East. Although the telecommunications sector has rebounded in recent years, access to telecommunications continues to be limited and service quality is poor. By extending its network, Zain Iraq will be able to offer communications to remote and underserved populations that previously have not had access to telecommunications services;
Support the delivery of social services: The 2003 conflict as well as ongoing security challenges have interrupted the delivery of basic services in Iraq.  In environments such as these, telecommunications operators are pioneering the delivery of social services such as banking, education and healthcare using the mobile platform. This Project will enable Zain Iraq to expand on these initiatives, and thus extend basic services to a larger share of the population.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This investment involves the strengthening and expansion of a nationwide GSM cellular telephone network in Iraq, owned by Atheer Telecom Iraq Limited (Zain Iraq or the Company).

Formerly known as MTC-Atheer, Zain Iraq launched operations in Iraq in December 2003, having been awarded a temporary (24-month) license to provide mobile telecommunications services in southern Iraq. (Similar temporary licenses were awarded to Asiacell Communications Company Limited (Asiacell) for northern Iraq and Orascom Telecom Iraq Corporation (Iraqna) for central Iraq.)  In August 2007, the Iraqi government auctioned three, new nationwide licenses to replace the existing short-term contracts.  Five bidders took part in the auction. Ultimately, Zain Iraq, Asiacell and Korek Telecom, an operator based in northern Iraq, won fifteen-year licenses for a fee of US$1.25 billion each.  Citing the high price, Iraqna withdrew from the auction and sold its network to Zain Iraq, in January 2008, for US$1.2 billion equivalent. The acquisition of Iraqna transformed Zain Iraq into the leading mobile operator in Iraq with over 50% market share. Despite the challenging political and security environment, Zain Iraq has continued to strengthen its operations, reaching 10.3 million subscribers as of December 2009. 

Zain Iraq is currently seeking funding to support its 2010-11 investment needs which include: (i) capital expenditures to improve capacity and network quality, and increase customer acquisition efforts especially in underserved areas; (ii) funding the remaining payments for the Companys mobile telecommunications license; and (iii) funding payments related to Zain Iraqs 2008 acquisition of Iraqna.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATHEER TELECOM IRAQ LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-29002" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-02-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IQ-Iraq">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zain Iraq is a GSM mobile phone company headquartered in Baghdad Iraq. Zain Iraq presently has 2408 sites in operation throughout Iraq.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.0000000000 44.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AC - Mobile Telephony</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $250.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2011-02-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-02-24">200000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2011-02-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-02-24">50000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-02-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-02-24">200000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATHEER TELECOM IRAQ LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-02-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-02-24">50000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATHEER TELECOM IRAQ LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/29002/zainiraq-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
