<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-31876</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gulftainer II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gulftainer Company Limited (Gulftainer or the Company), a UAE Limited Liability Company founded in 1976, is developing port and logistics activities in Iraq since 2009 where it operates since August 2010 a multipurpose terminal at Umm Qasr port, southern Iraq. Gulftainer has now decided to expand its container, cargo and logistics operations at Umm Qasr. It plans to develop and operate a 750,000 m2 bonded dry port north of Umm Qasr port (Umm Qasr Logistics Center or UQLC), which is expected to serve not only the container traffic at the port, but also the transport and logistics needs of the oil and gas industry in Southern Iraq (the Project). Gulftainers objective is to establish a first class logistics and oil field supply facility in the Basra region based on two main activities: A fully fledged dry port (inland container depot) targeting general traffic; and Additional services targeting specifically oil and gas companies looking for integrated and secured facilities to operate in Southern Iraq including (i) rental offices and accommodation, (ii) field support rental of equipment and transport, and (iii) long- and short-term rental of serviced but undeveloped plots for hazardous, fabrication, commercial, and oil and gas industry clients.  The Project is expected to have a significant contribution towards the redevelopment of the logistics and transport infrastructure in Iraq which is essential for the economic development of the country as well as its integration into the global economy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Once regarded as having one of the Middle East&apos;&apos;s most comprehensive transportation systems, Iraq&apos;&apos;s transport and logistics infrastructure has suffered from more than two decades of neglect and underinvestment. Rehabilitation of such infrastructure is a major national and regional trade issue. Gulftainer investments in Umm Qasr Port should help solve this issue and thus contribute to Iraq integration in the regional and global economy.  Iraq relies heavily on imports for its consumer goods and for its reconstruction program. Cost effective transport of imported goods is therefore critical to Iraq&apos;&apos;s economy. The 2012 Doing Business indicators however show that Iraq&apos;&apos;s is lagging behind other countries in the region in terms of logistics performance. Gulftainer&apos;&apos;s investments to modernize one of Umm Qasr berth combined with its experience to efficiently manage container terminals is expected to improve the situation.  At present, a substantial portion of goods coming into Iraq are off-loaded at ports in the neighboring countries such as Kuwait, Turkey and Jordan and are then transported into the country by road, which tends to increase the time and cost of delivering the goods to the end consumer. The Project should have a significant impact on reducing these impediments to trade in Iraq and foster the country&apos;&apos;s reconstruction efforts along with its economic growth and development.   Efficient and well-developed transport and logistics infrastructure is an essential component for the expected growth in Iraq&apos;&apos;s oil and gas production and export-related activities and the Project would play a strong role in facilitating these improvements.  In addition to its direct impact on trade, the Project should also contribute towards socio-economic development through the creation of several hundred jobs, reduction in the cost of goods paid by the end consumer (through reduction of costs incurred in the transportation process) as well as substantial royalty payments to the Government of Iraq.  Through its involvement at Umm Qasr port, Gulftainer will also play a strong role in training and improving the skills of the employees of the Iraq Port Authority, help introduce industry best-practice and contribute its valuable know-how in managing ports and logistics operations, which should improve the overall efficiency of the sector.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GULFTAINER COMPANY LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-31876" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-09-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peter Smith, Terminal Manager  Gulftainer Co. Ltd. Office c/o South Oasis Co. Ltd. Basrah, Iraq tel: + 964 (0) 7703227749</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stephen Ogden,  Group Operations Manager  PO Box 225, Sharjah, UAE tel: + 97165724201/2  http://www.gulftainer.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IQ-Iraq">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is expected to be located in the southern part of Iraq at Umm Qasr, about 70 km south of Basra.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.0000000000 44.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="493" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">E-CA - Storage (Including Agricultural Products)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $30.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-09-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-09-13">30000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-09-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-09-13">30000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GULFTAINER COMPANY LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/31876/gulftainer-ii">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/31876/gulftainer-ii">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
