<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>KE-NCB-OP2180511619410357-c2t</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="KE-NCB-OP2180511619410357" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF Kenya</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catchment to Tap (C2T)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed Catchment to Tap (C2T) programme has the goal of improving access and availability of clean and safe water in adequate quantities and sanitation services for all users, as well as enhance climate resilience and inclusivity in the water sector. The programme will be implemented around the Rift Valley Basin. The programme will also have a light-touch in the Upper Tana Basin (Thika catchment) and Lake Victoria South Basin (Homa Bay), where the partners are able to leverage existing work through the WaterWorX and Blue Deal projects. The project&#x2019;s activities will be implemented through an integrated approach centred around the IWRMWASH nexus demonstrations in Module 2. Through participatory approaches with the communities, particularly women and youth, the project will implement IWRM-WASH nexus demonstrations using a catchment approach, taking into account the human and climate induced changes degrading water source areas and impacting downstream users&#x2019; water supply and health outcomes. The catchment approach also facilitates the identification of bankable projects and the team will support additional high potential interventions with technical expertise to demonstrate sustainable business models that can be invested in and scaled through external finance. While each module will achieve specific outcomes, Module 1, 3 and 4 will create the necessary enabling conditions for the demonstration projects in Module 2 - i.e. raise awareness on the importance of IWRMWASH, increase capacity and knowledge in IWRM institutions, and improve institutional systems and structures with the WRA (Nakuru, Kisumu, and Embu) and WRUAs. Each module&#x2019;s design builds sustainability and ownership of IWRM-WASH through IWRM institutions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004370" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KE-NCB-OP2180511619410357-c2t" ref="KE-NCB-OP2180511619410357" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KE-NCB-OP2180511619410357-c2t" ref="KE-NCB-OP2180511619410357" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14015" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="KES" value-date="2021-01-01">98732469</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-04">347630</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004370" ref="XM-DAC-7"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-29">500480</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004370" ref="XM-DAC-7"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="KES" value-date="2021-12-31">20368331</value>
  </transaction>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">More and better knowledge development/sharing in Kenya on integrated, C2T approaches to WASH-WRM and IWRM</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of IWRM for WASH interventions or good practices adopted/implemented as a result of C2T Project</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will track IWRM for WASH- related good practices that will be adopted/implemented by the the project stakeholders within the project sites, as a result of C2T project support</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of replicable IWRM for WASH  best practices generated, as a result of C2T project</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will track New IWRM for WASH best practices that will be generated under demonstrations. The best practices will cut across all the outcomes of the C2T project.  Best practices will include for example succesful collaborations on IWRM between partners (e.g between KFS, WRA and 2 counties), IWRM for WASH demo sites, dissemination of the best practices will be through mainstream media, social media platforms, publications, peer learning etc</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of policy briefs/articles produced from IWRM knowledge sharing meetings held (stakeholder, Dutch partner)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will track number of briefs/ articles produced  as a result of  National level (stakeholder, Dutch partner)  IWRM knowledge sharing meetings held to discuss opportunities and problems arising from the shared information and data. In various geographical regions (if possible) to highlight local challenges and include a range of local stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of WRM stakeholders trained on IWRM-WASH C2T technical and strategic topics (disaggregated by gender and youth, type/name of institution, catchment, topic of training</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will track the number of people /WRM stakeholders trained  IWRM -WASH topics. The trainings will be on technical and strategic topics such as  climate resilience, IT skills, GIS, data collection, applied data handling, digital data devices and analytics, IWRM-WASH C2T skills, mandates towards BWRCs, advocacy, communication, conflict management, human-rights based approaches, gender mainstreaming, and working harmoniously with county leadership,  and applied C2T approaches. Stakeholders will include WRA staff from regional and sub-regional offices, WRUA members, and other organizations involved in IWRM for WaSH within the project area. The trainings will be both general for WRM stakeholders, as well as targeted technical trainings for each stakeholder based on the stakeholder&apos;s mandate, e.g specific trainings for WRUAs. This indicator captures training activities across all project outcomes</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="481"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people accessing the IWRM-WASH open knowledge platform developed  under the C2T project</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will track usage level of the developed platform (viewing, downloading data etc). The platform will initially be used by a selected group of key-stakeholders and, after evaluation, improved and developed into a more tailored platform used by a broader group of key stakeholders in Years 3-5. The platform will share data and knowledge of the various stakeholders to contribute to well informed decision-making for IWRM, WASH, and climate resilience</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="250"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved ability of WRA to fulfil its mission, through structural improvements in actor alignment, water allocation/ permitting/ compliance, data/ management and transparency-accountability, in particular at WRA Regional and sub-regional level, and of yet to be established BWRCs, and WRUAs</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of institutions with improved capacity to address IWRM issues (disaggregated by type of institution, Capacity Area) via Stakeholder Forum</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutions with improved capacity will be better able to govern, coordinate, analyze, advise, or make technical decisions or to provide inputs to decision making related to IWRM for WASH.  Relevant institutions will include  public sector entities (e.g. ministries, departments, working groups, public utilities, etc.), private sector entities (private utilities, service providers, etc.), community groups (user groups, women&#x2019;s groups, CBOs or NGOs, etc.), or others. The capacity areas will include information management, stakeholder involvement, Theoretical IWRM background and best practices, etc</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of investment proposals developed for IWRM interventions as a result of C2T project</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will monitor and track investment proposals developed on IWRM interventions. WRA regional offices staff will be supported in developing investment proposals for IWRM interventions</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of WRA staff with increased capacity to deliver WRA mandate as pertains IWRM for WASH, as a result of C2T project support (disaggregated by gender, capacity area, level of WRA institution)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will monitor and track the number of WRA staff at different levels who have improved their ability to implement WRA mission and mandate. Capacity building will include several training activities for WRA staff (e.g. Laboratory Development, Quality Standard, Data Management, Stakeholder etc) aimed at enhancing their ability to execute and deliver WRA mandate pertaining IWRM for WASH. Capacity building will target WRA staff at HQ, Regional and sub-regional levels. To qualify increased capacity, the trained staff will be assessed on their personal and institutional capacity improvement in delivery of roles</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="63"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage change in WRA institutional capacity score, as measured by OCAT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This will monitor and measure change in WRA organizational capacity score as measured by OCA tool.  A customized version of Organizational Capacity Assessment Tool (OCAT) will be used to &#x201C;grade&#x201D; specific skill sets required of institutions to fulfill their self-determined milestones and targets.  Once established, the OCA tool will be incorporated into the C2T project monitoring plan and will be used to assess WRA institutional advances against targets and milestones on an annual basis, and also to re-establish targets as necessary given their performance over the year. No other institutions will count towards this indicator</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relevant audiences have developed an understanding of, and have been mobilized to act on the challenges and risks associated with (not) meeting future water demand and have been provided with options to act</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage change in the average institutional capacity  score of targeted WRUAs , as measure by Organizational Capacity Assessment (OCA) tool  for assessing WRUAs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A customized version of Organizational Capacity Assessment Tool (OCAT) will be used to &#x201C;grade&#x201D; specific skill sets required of WRUAs to fulfill their self-determined milestones and targets.  Once established, the OCA tool will be incorporated into the C2T MEL plan and will be used to assess WRUA institutional advances against targets and milestones on an annual basis, and also to re-establish targets as necessary given their performance over the year. The OCAT tool provides a system to measure changes in institutional capacity resulting from the project. Only WRUAs subjected to OCA under this project will count towards this indicator</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of IWRM resolutions as a result of C2T multi-sector stakeholder engagement meetings</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will track and monitor IWRM-related resolutions or recommendations arrived at as a result of C2T multi-sector stakeholder engagement meetings</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of IWRM  for WASH demos sub-granted and implemented</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will track the number of grants issued and implemented</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people sensitized on IWRM for WASH  to enhance their understanding on future water (in)security, disaggregated by gender, county and youth, and media mode</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will track the number of people that will be engaged in the different forums at all levels, i.e policy makers, communities user groups etc to sensitize them on IWRM for WASH. This will be through physical community engagement meetings, digital and mainstream media sensitization campaign.  The reach of people sensitized will be for general public (beyond project scope area) due to use of digital and mainstream media platforms. The reach on social and mainstream media will only be quantified in numbers reached</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2000000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of water stewardship plans developed/ implemented with private sector</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will track the number of water stewardship plans developed/ implemented with private sector as a result of C2T project interventions</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Change in level of commitment and action on specific  policy related issues on IWRM for WASH, as measured by WWF level of commitment tool</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Level Of Commitment and Action Tool will be used. This indicator will monitor and measure the extent to which targeted actors/institutions will have engaged in, adopted or implemented policy and practices on IWRM for WASH. The policy issue(s) will be determined at the beginning of implementation of the C2T project when the right holders will prioritize the issue that has to be acted upon by the duty bearer</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people directly benefiting  from C2T demonstrations, disaggregated by gender, and catchment</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will track number of people benefiting from the project enabling environment demonstrations/solutions</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of water risk assessments undertaken</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will track the number of water risk assessment carried out within the project area as a result of the C2T interventions. These assessments will inform the development of water stewardship with private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
