<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-2153193-GB-COH-2153193-AP61ER</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-2153193" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Facilitating Social Norm Realignment and Reintegration of Kawar Maila Ward</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of the project greater agency will be created for community members in Kawar Maila Ward in MMC and they will be empowered with greater capacity for conflict resolution (current) and conflict prevention (future). Access of Kawar Maila Ward members to the wider community will be increased, thereby reducing stigma and increasing trust among community members and between them and service providers. Finally, Kawar Maila ward members will be empowered with conflict resolution skills and will be able to access neighbouring communities and security officials with greater ease and trust, and even among themselves.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the Kawar Maila ward perception among community members is high that they are not trusted by neighbouring wards within MMC due to their heavy losses of boys to JAS recruitment. Residents, women and youth in particular, are worst affected with loss of loved ones, means of livelihood, including shelter which were burnt down by security agencies on assumption that they were harbouring JAS.  Kawar Maila ward members are isolated from others wards and due to mistrust they do not seek the needed social services (in particular psychosocial services aiming to reduce or heal trauma deriving from JAS actions and security services) nor do they try to reintegrate into the greater MMC society. In addition, resistance by other communities to engage with members from Kawar Maila community reduces their livelihood opportunities and economic prosperity. 

Efforts to redress grievances at the community level about the role JAS has played in negatively damaging the social fabric, causing community mistrust in service provision and security institutions as well as each other within communities and between communities, will be able to contribute to overall peace building at the community level. This will reduce stigma of the Kawar Maila, especially among women who are perceived by other communities as being connected to JAS because their sons joined the group. 

The project will focus on the Kawar Maila community, one of the worst affected communities by both the atrocities of the insurgents and the mismanagement of the situation by security agents. Activities will be implemented by the local CSO Herwa Community Initiative, founded in in 1999 as Friends of the Habitat in response to the low and pervasive literacy level, rising HIV prevalence, malaria and widespread poverty. Herwa is today a leading CSO in Borno state working on security and governance, addressing issues around conflicts</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kawar Maila Ward community members, women and youth in particular</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-2153193" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@international-alert.org</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Weiller</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring, evaluation and learning coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+44(0)2076276800</telephone>
   <email>mweiller@international-alert.org</email>
   <website>http://www.international-alert.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-10-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-07">17000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-01">34613</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">10790.29</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q01</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="GB-GOV-1"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-AP61ER" ref="GB-COH-2153193">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q01</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">24843.83</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q01</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-AP61ER" ref="GB-COH-2153193">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q01</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
