<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-2153193-GB-COH-2153193-AP71MR</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-2153193" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bolstering Rural Economies and Knowledge of Workable Actions to Enable Reconciliation in Central and Southern Mali (BREAKWATER)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">130 communities - (60,912 indirect beneficiaries including dependents) of which 18,274 will be direct programme participants.
? 18,274 participants to Outcome 1 activities of which 40% female.
? 18,274 participants to Outcome 2 activities of which 60% female.
? 18,274 participants to Outcome 3 activities of which 40% female</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In full alignment with Sida&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x2122;s strategy for Mali focused on human security and strengthened peace and reconciliation mechanisms, as well as strengthened democracy, gender equality and greater resilience to environmental and climatic drivers of instability, BREAKWATER aims to prevent the further spread of violent conflict in Central and Southern Mali. It will do this by addressing contemporary and historical root causes of conflict in communities situated on the frontier between the relatively stable South and the most volatile parts of the Centre. It will also ensure that conflicts which rise to the surface are peacefully mitigated through local systems wherever possible. The programme will work to overcome natural resource management challenges, the breakdown of inter-ethnic relations and traditional mechanisms for conflict resolution, economic drivers of conflict, and a broken social contract between citizens and the state. The programme&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x2122;s goal is focused on increasing human security among the population in these zones. The concept of improving human security relates to the identification and successful resolution of widespread and crosscutting challenges to the survival, livelihood and dignity of people. BREAKWATER will be implemented by Mercy Corps, International Alert and Humanity &amp; Inclusion, and would run for four years, reaching 60,912 beneficiaries/participants across 130 communities in specific Cercles (indicatively identified on the map above but to be further refined during the program inception phase) within Koulikoro, Mopti and Segou Regions where the risk of the spread of violent conflict is greatest and where potential to build on positive local capacities provides opportunity for demonstrable impact.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1: Improved local capacities to effectively manage inter/intra-community relational drivers of human insecurity.
? R1.1: Improved gender-responsive local and commune level capacities for conflict prevention and resolution.
? R1.2: Improved equitable and inclusive local and commune level management of land and natural resources
? R1.3: Improved understanding and advocacy within the Malian government, development and peacebuilding community of key factors strengthening resilience to conflict among communities in South-Central Mali.
Annex B &#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x201C; Project Document 21-Jan-2020 5
Outcome 2: Improved individual, household and community capacity to offset economic and environmental drivers of human insecurity.
? R2.1:Increased and more resilient production and income for agro-pastoralists
? R2.2: Improved capacity of market actors to provide-off farm employment and sustain demand for local agricultural products in communities threatened by conflict.
Outcome 3: Improved relations between citizens and the state to overcome governance-related drivers of human insecurity.
? R3.1: Increased trust between communities and political and technical local authorities
? R3.2: Improved engagement of local authorities to deliver better services for men, women, boys and girls in target communities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-2153193" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@international-alert.org</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liz Dobson</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Resource Management</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+44(0)2076276921</telephone>
   <email>ldobson@international-alert.org</email>
   <website>http://www.international-alert.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">1977336</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1C</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="SE-0"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-AP71MR" ref="GB-COH-2153193" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1C</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-30">141057.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q02</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="SE-0" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-AP71MR" ref="GB-COH-2153193" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-30">28322.81</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q01</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-AP71MR" ref="GB-COH-2213649" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q01</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-30">41180.27</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q02</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-AP71MR" ref="GB-COH-2153193" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q02</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
