<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-2153193-GB-COH-2153193-SA02AE</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-2153193" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Towards a Global Programming Framework for Transforming Discriminatory Gender Patriarchal Norms - Nepal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">#N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local implementing partners, representative from local government, Nepal Police, policy makers, community leaders and activists</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project objectives:

1.	To build a localised evidence-base on the varying articulations and impacts of patriarchal norms and gendered inequalities in Kyrgyzstan, Philippines, Nepal and Nigeria through the delivery of four projects;
2.	To analyse and synthesize the commonalities and differences of patriarchal gender norms and the construction of masculinities across various contexts; 
3.	To (a) develop an organisational programming framework on transforming patriarchal gender norms and violent masculinities in conflict settings and (b) drive the year two of Alert&#x2019;s gender advocacy strategy from 2022 onwards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To address the findings in &apos;Twenty years of implementing UNSCR 1325 and the women, peace and security agenda: Lessons from the field&apos;, and act upon identified gaps in programmes that constructively engage with men and masculinities, Alert will build a cross-regional intervention that will develop and connect existing gender programming to reveal and dig into the manifestations of patriarchal gender norms at a local level. Projects will be focused in four locations, Nigeria, Philippines, Kyrgyzstan and Nepal. These interventions will assess the distinct influences of discriminatory patriarchal gender norms reflected in varying aspects of gender inequalities, including sexual and gender-based violence (SGBV) and women&#x2019;s participation in peace processes. The programme is proactively adopting a bottom-up approach which will form the foundations of a new global programming framework for working towards transforming these patriarchal gender norms through constructive engagement with men and violent masculinities in conflict-affected contexts. This bottom-up initiative will also feed into our three-year gender advocacy strategy &#x2013; &#x2018;Addressing patriarchal gender norms and the construction of masculinities in conflict settings&#x2019;. Local evidence and approaches will drive our advocacy and influencing upstream at the national and international levels. This project is financed through CORE funding from Sida, with &#xA3;20,000 available for each project and &#xA3;10,000 earmarked for internal costs including production of a final report.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-2153193" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@international-alert.org</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liz Dobson</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Resource Management</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+44(0)2076276925</telephone>
   <email>ldobson@international-alert.org</email>
   <website>http://www.international-alert.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-01">30000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1C</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-12-31">29996.82</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q03</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-SA02AE" ref="GB-COH-2153193" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q03</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-12-31">24996.82</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q03</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-SA02AE" ref="GB-COH-2153193" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q03</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
