<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-2153193-GB-COH-2153193-ME20SR</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-2153193" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting marginalised urban communities in confronting impacts of COVID-19 in Tunisia&apos;s interior regions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building on International Alert&#x2019;s longstanding experience in addressing regional disparities through its research and democratic governance programmes, this proposal reflects input from local partners working on health and our engagement with communities in Kasserine, Tataouine, and Douar Hicher and Ettadamon in Greater Tunis. 

While ongoing grassroots projects have focused on urgent response interventions, such as providing masks and sanitizers, and providing basic commodities to citizens in need, we believe that there is a need for more coherent and sustainable interventions to respond to the crisis. Those interventions need to in part be developed through an engagement with affected and vulnerable communities. This is why it is imperative to conduct participatory diagnostic of needs of communities utilizing a bottom-up approach in order to respond to the needs of citizens through various tools and initiatives in the three governorates of implementation: Sousse, Sidi Bouzid and Tataouine.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Municipal garbage collectors, social workers, and youth groups</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OECD, Shamseya for healthcare solutions, local municipalities, and local CSOs in the three governorates.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this project is to develop a short and medium-term response to the health crisis in Tunisia&#x2019;s marginalized border regions and neighborhoods with some of the most precarious urban communities. It does this by focusing on providing protection in the workplace for government employees who deal with women, youth-at-risk, the elderly, and municipal garbage collectors. The role of employees in those sectors proves to be central in maintaining state service delivery and the sanitary system of the municipalities in times of crisis. The project will also mobilise communities to support infection protection through technological tools and mechanisms that promote transparency, accountability, and community engagement. Expected medium-term impacts of the project include improving governance and state-citizen relationships in some of the most marginalised municipalities. In designing the project, the identified needs of the Ministry of Local Affairs and the Ministry of Social Affairs have been taken into consideration.  

The project will be implemented in partnership with elected municipalities, medical doctors, local civil society organizations focusing on health and the environment, and relevant sub-national government entities through three components that are complementary and build on each other. The fact that the project responds to identified needs by the ministries will facilitate the implementation process. The six municipalities are Sidi Ali Bin Oun and Sebelet Ouled Askar (Sidi Bouzid Gouvernate), Enfida and Sidi El Heni (Sousse Governate), and Ghomrassen and Bier El Ahmar (Tataouine Gonernate). Alert has an office in Tataouine that has already implemented projects in Ghomrassen and Bier El Ahmar, additionally, our office in Kasserine will oversee the implementation in the governorates of Sidi Bouzid and Sousse. Alert has previously implemented activities in Sousse.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-2153193" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@international-alert.org</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liz Dobson</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Resource Management</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+44(0)2076276925</telephone>
   <email>ldobson@international-alert.org</email>
   <website>http://www.international-alert.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-11-06">126000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1C</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="47080" type="40"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-31">37729.44</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q01</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="47080" type="40"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-31">25641.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q02</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="47080" type="40"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-ME20SR" ref="GB-COH-2153193" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q02</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-30">59171.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q03</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="47080" type="40"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-ME20SR" ref="GB-COH-2153193" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q03</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-31">2130.85</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q01</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-ME20SR" ref="GB-COH-2153193" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q01</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-31">107377.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q02</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-ME20SR" ref="GB-COH-2153193" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q02</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
