<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-2153193-GB-COH-2153193-AP61FR</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-2153193" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Countering narrative of Apathy to Western Edu  and  Promotion of Peace Edu in Islamiya Schools</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Efforts are needed to bring about community awareness of the role of Islam in peacemaking and peace building, the compatibility of Islam with &#x201C;western&#x201D; notions of conflict resolution, and the sensitization and advocacy of religious officials (including school directors and Arabic and Islamic scholars) to their role in shifting the narrative from what is &#x201C;Boko Haram&#x201D; to what is &#x201C;Boko Halal.&#x201D;  Levels of understanding are low at the moment, however levels of apprehension to the compatibility of Islam and western principles are quite high among the population, including community members and Islamiya school directors. Dialogue at the community level focuses on either conflict resolution or Islam but rarely both.

1. design/adoption of a manual which highlights the ways in which Islam is compatible with &#x201C;western&#x201D; concepts of conflict resolution , with proposed ideas for how mediation, negotiation and dialogue occurs within Islam in Nigeria. 
2. sensitization of parents of children in Islamiya schools through sensitization meetings to the compatibility of Islam with &#x201C;western&#x201D; education and concepts of conflict resolution, including community mediation and negotiation. 
3. series of media campaigns such as radio panel discussion, phone-in talk show and regular public forums using a media outlets</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamiya School Directors and religious scholars; teachers of Arabic and Islamic studies linked to Islamiya schools in MMC; male and female scholars and preachers  in MMC; parents of children at Islamiya schools</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall this project will lead to an increase in understanding among participants of the compatibility of principles of Islam and conflict resolution principles. Specifically, the project is aiming for an increase in understanding among parents and pupils of Islamiya schools on the alignment of these three principles and how education and conflict resolution can be facilitated at the community level to foster a greater sense of peacefulness and acceptance of western education in the community. Specifically, Islamiya schools in Borno State have almost the same number of young girls as young boys as well as female and male teachers and directors; therefore, by rolling out the manual with core principles of conflict resolution in it, we will be able to reach all relevant stakeholders (women, men, girls, boys, parents, community members, etc).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-2153193" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@international-alert.org</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Weiller</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring, evaluation and learning coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+44(0)2076276800</telephone>
   <email>mweiller@international-alert.org</email>
   <website>http://www.international-alert.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-01">31776</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">9905.95</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q01</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="GB-GOV-1"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-AP61FR" ref="GB-COH-2153193">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2I Q01</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">23874.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q01</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-COH-2153193-AP61FR" ref="GB-COH-2153193">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3E Q01</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
