<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285908-219294</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285908" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision United Kingdom</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">219294 3UN FY22 OCHA Provision of Life Saving Nutrition Services Afghanistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to Afghanistan Humanitarian Needs Overview for 2021, over the past 5 years, the food security situation in Afghanistan has steadily deteriorated with the percentage of food insecure people doubling (from 37 per cent in September 2015 to 76 per cent in Nov 2020), while the proportion of people in crisis or emergency levels of food insecurity has increased more than five-fold (from 8 per cent to 42 per cent over the same period). In 2021 the situation devastated due to the drought conflict as well as nutrition and economic impact of the COVID-19. The recently updated Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC) analysis shows the food security situation has further deteriorated with worrying implications for the winter lean season ahead. An estimated 22.8 million people, or 55 per cent of the population, are expected to be in crisis or emergency levels of food insecurity (IPC 3+) between November 2021 and March 2022, a nearly 35 per cent increase from the same season last year (16.9m). 
 
 Acute malnutrition is a public health issue that predominantly affects children under the age of five, as well as PLW. The Nutrition Cluster estimates that 27 out of 34 provinces are above the emergency threshold for acute malnutrition. At least 3.9 million people need acute malnutrition treatment services in 2021, including one million children under five with severe acute malnutrition (SAM), 2.2 million children under five with moderate acute malnutrition (MAM), and 0.7 million pregnant and lactating women (PLW) with acute malnutrition. Stunting already stands at a staggering 41 per cent in Afghanistan and in the last drought year (2018), 74,000 children had died from acute malnutrition.
 
 World Vision (WV) Intends to deliver the required nutrition services through the establishment of seven Mobile Health and Nutrition teams (MHNTs) in Ghor and Badghis provinces (Ghor: Firozkoh,Taiwara, Dolaina and Badghis: Jawand, Qadis, Balamorghab). 
 World Vision will focus on the provision of essential nutrition treatment for severely acute malnourished children by forming seven Mobile Nutrition teams. WV will also provide emergency lifesaving nutrition services in the hard to reach and uncovered areas using the IMAM protocol, facilitate community screening for malnutrition and support referral, provide financial support for the referral of SAM management and provision of , provide Winterization kits and clothing to PLW with acute malnutrition in liaison and coordination with ESNFI cluster for provision p of the IYCF services at the community and health facility level and integrate MHPSS and deliver the services through Mobile Nutrition teams.
 The project will focus on early action to avoid severe malnutrition by targeting the, borderline cases of acute malnutrition through prevention-oriented services such as counselling on optimal care practices to mothers of children who borderline in terms of their Mid-Upper Arm Circumference (MUAC). This approach can reduce the risk of rapid deterioration of the nutritional status of children with a MUAC result of 12.5-13.5 cm. This will be done at the MHNTs level by nutrition nurses and at the community level by community nutrition promoters. 
 
 The adaptation mechanism will be taken into consideration during any capacity building efforts, IYCF promotion session based on the WHO/MOPH and WV Standard Operating Procedure for training, public gatherings, and IEC distribution under the COVID-19 circumstances. The project will focus on the provision of lifesaving referral for those cases that require inpatient services and will ensure that a transportation and treatment facility are provided for them. WV attends the EPR meetings on a weekly basis and will update the key actors including DoPH, UNICEF and WHO on the project progress; the project report will be shared on a weekly and monthly basis to the key nutrition cluster focal points and DEWS surveillance focal points.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="US-EIN-95-3202116-AF" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="US-EIN-95-3202116-AF" ref="US-EIN-95-3202116" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-285908" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision United Kingdom</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-285908" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision United Kingdom</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision United Kingdom</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.worldvision.org.uk</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="P13" percentage="100" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="52010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
