<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5410017102-GGG-12182</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 WHO Forskningsst&#xF6;d 2020-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 WHO Research support 2020-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
De tre f&#xF6;ljande WHO-baserade forskningsprogrammen har ans&#xF6;kt om fortsatt st&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n Sida: 
i) The UNICEF-UNDP-World Bank-WHO Special Programme for Research and Training in Tropical Diseases (TDR);  
ii) The UNDP-UNFPA-UNICEF-WHO-World Bank Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction, (HRP); 
iii) Alliance for Health Policy and Systems Research (AHPSR). 

Det f&#xF6;reslagna st&#xF6;det &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning p&#xE5; tidigare avtal 2016-2019. Det totala beloppet &#xE4;r 307,8 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r perioden 2020 &#x2013; 2022, varav 138,8 MSEK till TDR, 99 MSEK till HRP och 70 MSEK till AHPSR. St&#xF6;det &#xE4;r i huvudsak icke &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt. 

TDR:s aktiviteter kommer under avtalsperioden att ha tyngdpunkten p&#xE5; forskning om hinder f&#xF6;r effektivt genomf&#xF6;rande av befintliga kontrollprogram f&#xF6;r fattigdomsrelaterade infektionssjukdomar. HRP:s inriktning innefattar forskning om en bredd av fr&#xE5;gor relaterade till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och r&#xE4;ttigheter (SRHR), bland annat migranters behov av SRHR, ungdomars behov av SRHR och kvinnors st&#xE4;rkta m&#xF6;jligheter till s&#xE4;ker abort. AHPSR kommer att fokusera ytterligare p&#xE5; att genom forskning om h&#xE4;lsosystem och policies tillsammans med beslutsfattare bidra till att fattiga l&#xE4;nder kan nyttja sina resurser f&#xF6;r h&#xE4;lsosektorn p&#xE5; ett s&#xE5; effektivt s&#xE4;tt som m&#xF6;jligt.

Ut&#xF6;ver icke &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt st&#xF6;d ing&#xE5;r fyra komponenter med s&#xE5; kallad &quot;mjuk &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkning&quot;: en global h&#xE4;lsoforskningskonferens (genom AHPSR), n&#xE4;tverket ESSENCE, initiativet f&#xF6;r social h&#xE4;lsoinnovation, och st&#xE4;rkt WASH-integrering (de tre senare genom TDR). Totalt uppg&#xE5;r denna mjuka &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkning till 8% av insatsens budget.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The following three WHO-based research programmes have applied for continued support from Sida:
i) The UNICEF-UNDP-World Bank-WHO Special Programme for Research and Training in Tropical Diseases (TDR); 
ii) The UNDP-UNFPA-UNICEF-WHO-World Bank Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction, HRP; 
iii) Alliance for Health Policy and Systems Research (AHPSR). 

The proposed support is a continuation of the previous agreement 2016-2019. The total amount is SEK 307,8 million for the period 2020 - 2022, of which SEK 138,8 million to TDR, SEK 99 million to HRP and SEK 70 million to AHPSR. The contribution support is essentially unearmarked

During the agreement period, TDR&apos;s activities will focus on research on barriers to effective implementation of existing control programs for infectious diseases disproportionally affecting people living in poverty. HRP&apos;s focus includes, amongst many areas related to sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR), research on migrants&apos; needs for SRHR, on adolescents&#x2019; need for SRHR, and women&apos;s enhanced opportunities for safe abortion. AHPSR will focus further on researching health systems and policies together with policy makers to help low- and lower middle-income countries use their resources for the health sector as efficiently as possible.

In addition to undesignated support, there are four components with so-called &quot;soft earmarking&quot;: A Global Health Research Conference (through AHPSR), the ESSENCE Network, the Social Health Innovation Initiative, and enhanced WASH integration within the TDR (the three latter through TDR). In total, this soft earmarking amounts to 8% of the total support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Three WHO-based research programmes are proposed for continued support:
i) The UNICEF-UNDP-World Bank-WHO Special Programme for Research and Training in Tropical Diseases, TDR; ii) The UNDP-UNFPA-UNICEF-WHO-World Bank Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction, HRP; and iii) Alliance for Health Policy and Systems Research, AHPSR, or &quot;the Alliance&quot;.
Sida/Sweden is a long-standing supporter of TDR since its creation in 1974. TDR is one of the earliest examples of a Global Health Partnership and has repeatedly received good reviews by external evaluators because of its relevance to both health and development. TDR is the 2011 recipient of the Gates Award for Global Health. With its long history of support, Sida is well familiar with the achievements of the programme. TDR helps facilitate, support and influence efforts to combat diseases of poverty, with the mission to &quot;support effective and innovative global health research, through strengthening the research capacity of disease-affected countries, and promoting the translation of evidence into interventions that reduce the burden of infectious diseases and build resilience in the most vulnerable populations&quot;. TDR main areas are i) Research for policy; ii) Research for implementation; iii) Research for innovation; and iv) Research for integrated approaches.   
Sida/Sweden is an as long-standing supporter of HRP, even since a couple of years before its creation in 1972. As such, Sida is equally familiar with the HRP&apos;s achievements. HRP is the main instrument within the United Nations system for research in human reproduction, bringing together policy-makers, scientists, health care providers, clinicians, consumers and community representatives to identify and address priorities for research to improve sexual and reproductive health. The mission of HRP is &quot;the attainment of all people of the highest possible level of sexual and reproductive health. HRP strives for a world where all womens and mens rights to enjoy sexual and reproductive health are promoted and protected, and all women and men, including adolescents and those who are underserved and marginalized, have access to sexual and reproductive health information and services&quot;.
AHPSR is a younger programme than TDR and HRP and recently celebrated its 20th anniversary. Sweden was one of the drivers of the creation of AHPSR and has been actively involved since then, leading to good insights into their activities. AHPSR work to improve the health of those in low- and middle-income countries by supporting the generation and use of evidence that strengthens health systems. Together with organizations around the world, the AHPSR aims to i) provide a unique forum for the health policy and systems research community; ii) support institutional capacity for the conduct and uptake of health policy and systems research; iii) stimulate the generation of knowledge and innovations to nurture learning and resilience in health systems; and iv) increase the demand for and use of knowledge for strengthening health systems.
&#xA0;
HRP and TDR are special programmes of WHO which gives them an independent status in relation to WHO. They are co-sponsored by a number of UN-agencies (UNICEF, UNDP, World Bank and WHO are co-sponsors of both TDR and HRP, and additionally, UNFPA is co-sponsor of HRP). As a WHO-hosted partnership, AHPSR is also guaranteed its independence. The difference between the two set-ups used to be the co-sponsorship of the special programmes, although today the definitions are being discussed at WHO. The future format of AHPSR is described later in this appraisal.
When the special programmes were created in the early 1970s WHO did not actively engage in research, but as a number of member states could see the importance of producing research of relevance (in this case tropical diseases and human reproduction), TDR and HRP were created. Over the years, the importance of producing evidence to feed into policies and guidelines was increasingly recognized and other UN agencies joined the effort as co-sponsors.
Similarly, the areas of health policy and systems research were neglected and in the late 1990s a group of global health leaders, including senior scientists, policy makers and representatives of various agencies and programs with a stake in health policy and systems research agreed on the need to create a body that would address these areas, and AHPSR was created as a hosted partnership at WHO.
Being based at WHO and having a close interaction with the co-sponsors provides the research programmes with a unique opportunity to accelerate translation of research results into policies and guidelines. Through country and regional offices and their close relation to a countys Ministry of Health, the possibility for implementation at this level is also improved. As WHO is now putting more emphasis into the country and regional offices, this is expected to play an even more important role in the coming years. The importance of research and evidence is even more clear now that WHO has assigned a first Chief Scientist and a Science Division, and one can foresee a closer interaction between the research programmes and WHO at all levels.
Over the years, as the world changes, the areas of research addressed as well as the ways to address the need of evidence and implementation have changed in the three programmes. The research programmes show an embedded ability to adapt their activities to changes in global health and to take leading roles in the global research agenda.
There are still pertinent questions to be addressed in the programmes respective areas. For example, there is presently a strong focus on implementation research and interaction with decision-makers, as well as strengthening research capacity in LMICs and ensuring that high quality research is done in countries. 
As the bulk of Sida&apos;s support to the programmes is given as undesignated funding, the results of the upcoming phase are expected to contribute to the attainment of the respective missions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41143" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WHO/World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41143" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WHO/World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="121" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health, General</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12182" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical research</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.b - St&#xF6;dja forskning om och utveckling av vaccin och l&#xE4;kemedel mot de smittsamma och icke-smittsamma sjukdomar som i f&#xF6;rsta hand drabbar utvecklingsl&#xE4;nder. S&#xF6;rja f&#xF6;r tillg&#xE5;ng till ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomliga grundl&#xE4;ggande l&#xE4;kemedel och vaccin, i enlighet med Doha-deklarationen om TRIPS-avtalet och folkh&#xE4;lsa, i vilken det bekr&#xE4;ftas att utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna har r&#xE4;tt att fullt ut utnyttja den flexibilitet som avtalet om handelsrelaterade aspekter av immaterialr&#xE4;tter erbjuder f&#xF6;r att skydda folkh&#xE4;lsan och, framf&#xF6;r</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.b - Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public healt</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">3583178.6051662923</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">5363243.129802143</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">3847543.9844232765</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">3583178.605166292</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">5363243.129802144</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">3847543.984423276</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">12161091.023594</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">3583178.6051662923</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-28">3847543.9844232765</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-28">1515699.1453788665</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_AmendmentWHO2021signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1st amendment WHO research programmes, 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_WHO_Researchamendment2signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2nd amendment research programmes at WHO</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_WHOagreement_Supporttoresearchpg2020-2022.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WHO agreement_ Support to research pg 2020-2022.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_BeslutominsatsWHOForskningsstod2020-2022.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats WHO Forskningsst&#xF6;d 2020-2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_DecisiononAmendmentofContributionWHO2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om &#xE4;ndring av insats WHO forskning juni 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_DecisiononAmendmentofContributionWHOadditionalfunds2021_signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on 2nd Amendment of Contribution to research programmes at WHO</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alliance for HPSR
As for all organisations, the past year was colored by the Covid-19 pandemic and the Alliance for Health Policy and Systems Research (HPSR) responded by both adapting its activities to the new situation, and carried on with what was still possible. In addition, the Alliance took the opportunity to play an important role in understanding the impacts of the pandemic and country response on the health systems (see more below).

Selected results  2020
In 2020, the Alliance supported 18 ongoing projects, representing 145 grants across 38 countries. There were in total 420 grantees, of which 53% are women, and 20% are early-career researchers. A total of 70 peer-reviewed journal articles were published, of which 59% of the journal articles lead authors are female, and 44% of journal articles lead authors are from LMICs. 

One of the main individual capacity strengthening initiatives the Alliance runs is a mentorship programme for early-career women. In 2020, 22 early-career female researchers were supported through  this programme. In the end, nine articles were accepted from first-time women authors from Kenya, Viet Nam, Uganda, Ghana, Ethiopia, Bangladesh, Nigeria and Brazil, examining issues as diverse as immunization, nursing leadership, social accountability, violence in pregnancy, primary health care and indigenous health.

The Alliance has recently put efforts into their communication strategy, resulting in a 26% increase in website sessions from previous year, and a 33% increase in Twitter followers since 2018. Their efforts also resulted in the Alliance winning the Best Not-for-Profit Story at the 2021 Shorthand Awards for its digital longform Pillars of strength: How embedded research supports resilient health systems in Mozambique.

The Alliance collaborated with the BMJ to release a special collection on Increasing the Impact of Health Research through Co-production of Knowledge, which provides an overview of the evolution, potential, influence, learning and challenges in co-producing evidence to inform decision-making in health policy and practice, and points to the core principles which should underpin it.

The Alliance also published a report Build back fairer: achieving health equity in the Eastern Mediterranean Region, which provides (according to the Alliance) ground breaking insights into the state of health inequities in the Region and urges countries to take action to address the social determinants of health to reverse the worsening trend of inequity  aggravated by the COVID-19 pandemic, ongoing conflict, mass movements of people, environmental challenges, gender inequities and unemployment.

An example of how the Alliance collaborates with global programmes is in Ethiopia, where the Alliance started a project in collaboration with Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance and UNICEF  to support decision-maker-led implementation research for immunization. 

Responding to the Covid-19 pandemic
Just months after the Covid-19 pandemic was declared a public health emergency of international concern, the Alliance was able to convene a small group of experts and policy-makers to identify priority areas of research to support the Covid-19 response beyond the biomedical and epidemiological realms. The group identified three key areas of focus: a) better understanding influences on government decision-making around Covid-19, b) engaging vulnerable populations and, c) disruption to routine health service provision.

Based on these areas, the Alliance commissioned 14 studies from teams across Bangladesh, Burkina Faso, Ethiopia, India, Georgia, Ghana, Mexico, Mozambique, Nigeria, Pakistan, Trinidad and Tobago, Uganda and Viet Nam. Initial findings from these studies have been shared at both the national and global levels, and the studies will be published in 2021.

With regards to the pandemic, the Alliance commissioned 14 demand-driven studies, established 4 rapid review platforms synthesising evidence for Covid-19, and enabled 10 Covid-19-focused rapid reviews.

This is actually a key moment for the Alliance. Covid-19 resulted in an increased recognition of health systems failures (policy, planning, delivery, data) in pandemics, and health systems strengthening is one important answer.

Development of a next 5-year Strategy
In 2020, an external evaluation was undertaken, as well as a management review, all of which has informed the thinking of a next strategic phase. The Alliances long-term focus has been  and will likely continue to be  on research to support UHC, the past year has seen an expansion of their work around health emergencies. There is also an increased recognition that peoples overall health depends on many factors. Therefore, the plan is to expand partnerships on areas such as non-communicable diseases and broader determinants of health, like climate change, with the aim of reinforcing and strengthening health systems.

Sida has a seat on the Board of the Alliance, and has been involved in defining the strategy and ensuring that key components are present (such as focus on LMICs, including gender aspects, ownership, capacity building, WASH, AMR, climate change and a broad approach to health) and that all relevant stakeholders were consulted (other departments of WHO who also include views of country and regional offices, other UN-organs and large programmes of relevance, researchers, funders). The Strategy was approved in the beginning of 2021 after several rounds of stakeholder consultations, and Sida appreciates the new Strategy. This is a new and promising take on health systems.

In 2019-2020 the Alliance looked into possibilities to broaden the concept of health systems, beyond the six building blocks. Several staff members, including a new strong researcher, investigated options and opportunities for the Alliance to engage in WHOs third goal healthier populations. Swedish MoFA seconded a person for three months who looked further into the possibilities to strengthen healthier populations of WHO. A main take-home message is that we need to see to that civil society actors are involved to a greater extent in the defining of research questions; its not enough with the MoH.   

Sixth Global Symposium on Health Systems Research (HSR)
HSR2020, focused on re-imagining health systems, was planned to take place in November in Dubai, although due to the pandemic the entire symposium was re-imagined into three phases, and the Alliance is involved across all of them. Phase 1, which took place from 8-12 November, brought together over 2 296 people. The Alliance participated in or organized four sessions, including: a funders roundtable, a capacity strengthening session on systems thinking and two launches. Phase 2 started at the end of November and continued through March 2021, with the Alliance contributing to the multimedia strand, holding an organized session and three satellites. Participation shows that a larger proportion than usual of the participants were from LMICs.
Sida funds travel for participants from LMICs, although this time the funds were reallocated to core activities of the Alliance instead, especially considering healthier populations.

Innovations in implementation research
&quot;It is important for countries to consider integrating implementation research into their major health programmes, supported through domestic funds to ensure self-reliance and sustainability.&quot;, says Zsuzsanna Jakab Deputy Director-General World Health Organization, in the Alliance annual report.

A supplement on Innovations in Implementation Research in Low- and Middle-income Countries, published in November 2020, has gained attention. The mainstreaming of such research within public health programmes around the world is vital for the achievement of the SDGs, and is something we (Sida research) bring up on a regular basis. The supplement, produced by the Alliance, features 12 articles that showcase innovations in implementation research. The articles cover a range of public health challenges, from the electrification of rural primary health care facilities in Ghana and Uganda, to improving the quality of team-based primary health care in India. The WHO Chief Scientist, Deputy Director-General and Regional Director of EMRO co-authored a commentary on the importance of implementation research for learning health systems.
___________________________________________________________________________________________

HRP

2021 was both a challenging and successful year for HRP. At a general level, the backlash to SRHR is challenging, especially as some activities are complicated to implement, in particular at country-level. The backlash is also an opportunity, as certain donors show an increased will to support HRP activities. In 2021, the Covid-19 pandemic still affected HRPs work, both challenging the implementation of ongoing projects and bringing in opportunities such as research connected to the pandemic and its consequences. In addition to this, new initiatives were initiated, such as a stronger emphasis on decolonisation/historical power imbalances and the connection between climate change/environmental degradation and SRHR.  

In March 2021 the current HRP Director announced his retirement but agreed to stay on until December 2021. In March, the process of recruiting a new Director was initiated, resulting in a final decision early 2022. The new Director will be in office from July 1st 2022. Recruitment is generally a long process at WHO and positions at country and regional level are favoured. HRP is still understaffed (25% in 2021) but some improvements have been possible (20% in 2022), including two critical positions: a gender advisor and a human rights advisor with expertise in SRHR. These two advisors presented their initial thoughts at the online intersessional meeting in November. The intersessional meeting was the second one of its kind. Having such a meeting decreases some of the pressure from the annual Policy and Coordination Committee (PCC) meeting (HRP&apos;s Steering Board) by providing information on various processes and allowing for discussions amongst the PCC members. The intersessional meeting also keeps a certain momentum and interest, and provides members with updated information to be shared in member countries/donor organisations. Sida has been instrumental in initiating these meetings. In 2021 the intersessional meeting included an updated financial report and analysis, a technical session on HRPs work on gender and human rights, and an update on HRP results and activities so far.

The highlight of the year is usually the PCC meeting, and the Conclusion on Performance is usually written in connection with this meeting. At PCC all reports are presented and discussed for final approvals.  

PCC35 and some highlights
This 35th PCC meeting 27-28 April 2022 was all virtual for the third time, and even more smoothly carried through than previous years. There were participants from all over the world, as far as Tonga. Prior to PCC there were three technical webinars: one on HRP participation on Covid-19 response and how local researchers were crucial in the response; one on rights and gender, and one on the integration of digital tools and self-care in national health systems. The webinars allowed for online discussions which were summarised and further discussed for potential recommendations at PCC. There were presenters from country-level and different actor groups in the webinars, and even the Minister of Health of Burkina Faso gave a presentation. As Chair, Sweden had an active role in the session on rights and gender. 

The reports were shared with Sida as preparations of the PCC meeting, and all reports were sent on time this year (as opposed to last year). 

Selected results from HRP in 2021:
- 88 projects were supported by HRP, of which 38% are headed by partners in AFR.
- 211 articles were published in peer-review scientific journals, and of non-WHO papers 42% had a lead author from AMR (mainly Brazil) and 25% from AFR. 67% are published by an institution in a LMIC. 60% have a female lead author. Most publications (35%) are related to maternal and perinatal health. 
- 34 systematic reviews were published in 2021, where the great majority (52% of those excl WHO reviews) were published by an institution in AMR (mainly Brazil) and 66% in LMIC. Also here the majority is related to maternal and perinatal health. 
- The co-sponsors of HRP (UNFPA, WHO, UNDP, UNICEF and WB) are important partners to HRP, especially as they can effectively get an impact of research results produced by HRP. The number of collaborations with co-sponsors and other UN partners has increased much the past years, and in 2021 there were 121 ongoing projects. Most are with UNFPA and WHO, and mainly within the areas of family planning and contraception, and health systems, including self-care and digital innovations. Collaboration take place both at country-level and international level (more details can be found in the dashboard linked to above). One example is the development of new guidelines, the WHO&apos;s Digital Adaptation Kits (DAKs) which were pioneered by HRP. The DAK for Family Planning (developed together with WHO, UNFPA and other partners) provided a new tool for countries implementing the WHO recommendations in their digital systems. 
- In 2021, 1 173 individuals (60% female) were trained as a result of HRP Alliance activities, a doubling compared to 2020. The HRP training hub in Brazil, CEMICAMP, was very active and trained 627 of them. Only 15 were trained by APHRC in Nairobi, who also get support from Sida/Sweden directly (both from the research strategy, and from the regional SRHR strategy). Most courses were short, but there are a few PhD students (5) and Masters students (17). Most (44%) of the individuals trained come from AFR. 87 scientific articles were published within the HRP Alliance initiative. 
Since inception five years ago, 92 individuals have completed their MSc degree and 35 their PhD. A mentorship programme with early career female researchers was initiated in 2020 with 13 mentor-mentee pairs. This programme is to be scaled in 2022. 
- Each day, about 800 women and girls die from complications related to pregnancy or childbirth, most of which are preventable or treatable. 99% occur in LMICs, and the highest risk of maternal death is for adolescent girls under 15 years. HRP is addressing research and evidence needs from different perspectives, including the use of &quot;living guidelines&quot; to respond to new, important evidence as it emerges. This way, the latest evidence and recommendations reach health workers worldwide as quickly as possible. In 2021, nine recommendations were updated related to maternal health. 
- An HRP-led study involving 17 countries shed light on the severity of abortion-related complications and their clinical management. Data was collected from 20 000 women, and evidence showed that women in Africa are twice as likely to have a potentially life-threatening complication, or nearly died, than in Latin America and the Caribbean. 
- In 2021, the &quot;WHO preferred product characteristics&quot; (PPCs) for gonococcal vaccines were published. PPCs are supposed to encourage innovation and development of vaccines. Vaccination for gonorrhoeae is crucial, as resistance to the existing antibiotics is hindering treatment. 
- New recommendations for screening for cervical cancer were developed, including a DNA-based test for human papillomavirus (HPV) which increases availability. The new guidelines include specific recommendations for women living with HIV, who have a six-fold risk of cervical cancer. 
- WHO and HRP published a series of country profiles to summarise data on key issues for adolescent sexual and reproductive health and rights (ASRHR). This gives an accurate picture of ASRHR issues for 50 different countries, and bring together relevant data on ten different areas, including sexual activity, child marriage, gender-based violence and menstruation. 
- HRP coordinated with partners across the world to produce guidance on digital health. This innovative digital tools aim to connect decision-makes with health systems, and health workers with high-quality evidence-based WHO guidance. HRP also conducts research on self-care innovations.
- HRP launched the &quot;SRHR Policy Portal&quot;, to improve access to the most up to date global, regional and country data for policies and indicators related to SRHR. 
- Aspects of historical power imbalances (incl decolonisation) are increasingly included throughout HRP activities. 

_______________________________________________________________________________________________

TDR
Many positive stories  emerged in the background of the global crisis. TDR&apos;s  long-term investments in strengthening health research capacity in low- and middle-income countries have helped build resilience to respond to crises such as the current pandemic.

The skills acquired through three TDR research training programmes have allowed hundreds of scientists to contribute to both research and frontline efforts tackling COVID-19 demonstrating the value of investing in people, and in research training, ahead of emergencies.

Highlights of results achieved during the year 2020:
1) Research for Implementation:
*African research networks collaborate to mitigate the impact of COVID-19 on
tuberculosis (TB) services
*New toolkit developed for evaluating the implementation and scale-up of digital technologies for TB care
*13 West and Central African countries launch research to optimize delivery of Seasonal Malaria Chemoprevention during COVID-19 pandemic
*Guidance framework published for implementing a multisectoral approach to vectorborne diseases
*Global directory of medical entomology courses launched to help build capacity to tackle vector-borne diseases
*New toolkit supports researchers to incorporate intersectional gender analysis into research
*Assessment finds high-quality evidence for universal health coverage generated by the Structured Operational Research and Training Initiative (SORT IT)
*Innovative virtual platform developed to overcome COVID-19 restrictions in research and training
2) Strengthening Research Capacity:
*Research training and COVID-19 response:
Almost 60% (411 of 699) of survey respondents who received TDR training have been involved in research on COVID-19. Almost 80% (315 of 411) of those involved are directly applying skills learned during TDR training to fight the pandemic.
*Adapting training programmes to the pandemic:
The seven universities participating in the postgraduate training scheme actively adopted virtual trainings to ensure continuation of the scheme.
More than 3000 researchers participated in the Massive Open Online Course on
Implementation Research (IR) in English, French and Spanish.
*New training partners:
Institutions in Senegal and Malaysia have joined TDRs global network of research training partners, filling a gap in French-speaking West Africa and strengthening activities in the WHO Western Pacific Region.
3) Global Engagement
*TDR joins COVID-19 Clinical Research Coalition to contribute to data sharing
agenda
*Social Innovation in Health Initiative partners with WHO Health Emergencies
Programme on community engagement package
*48 research grants awarded in the six WHO regions through small grants scheme
*TDR Globals initiative on innovative financing for research leads to successful
crowdfunding campaign
*A new intersectional gender research strategy launched to promote more inclusive research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="54100171" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1140102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0.0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <title>Research cooperation 2015-2022</title>
    <titleSV>Forskningssamarbete 2015-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
