<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5405025701-GGG-25010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">B4D 3K Chamber Trade Sweden</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">B4D 3K Chamber Trade Sweden</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CTS is an organisation carrying out international cooperation on      behalf of 8 Swedish Chambers. The aim of the contribution is to       strengthen the capacity of sister organisations in a number of        selected countries, one focus area is women economic empowerment. The overall objective is i.a. strengthented competetiveness among         companies in the local private sector.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">CTS &#xE4;r 8 svenska handelskammares organisation f&#xF6;r internationellt     samarbete. Insatsens syfte &#xE4;r att st&#xE4;rka systerorganigationer i       utvalda l&#xE4;nder (&#xD6;stafrika, Zambia, Etiopien och Irak). Genomg&#xE5;ende    tema kommer att vara &quot;women economic empowerment&quot; och man kommer      dessutom att jobba mycket med n&#xE4;tverkande och policy advocacy.        Insatsens m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r st&#xE4;rkt konkurrenskraft hos lokalt n&#xE4;ringsliv.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donor Country NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Make Trade</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="250" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business &amp; Other Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="25010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Policy and Administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">1329610.4241457253</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1381809.248909906</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1311972.4777329117</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">1329610.4241457253</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1381809.248909906</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1311972.4777329117</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-11-01">3988831.272437</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-28">1329610.4241457253</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">1381809.248909906</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-11-28">1311972.4777329117</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: The Chamber Academy Program was initially set up to be implemented as a business for development programme (B4D) in 2012. During the implementation some initially designed activities has been altered and the project period was prolonged for even better goal- and results achievement.

The programme has been implemented in partnership with nine business member organisations (BMO&#x2019;s) in 10 countries and one key to the success of the programme is the actual cross sector coordination of the activities and the synergies between them. 

The programme&#x2019;s impact on development in general has led to a strengthening of the private sector which is crucial for economic development and poverty reduction. The programme has contributed to increased trade and a sustainable development of the business segments in the programme. A sustainable and more &#x2018;fair&#x2019; trade is crucial for poverty reduction within the sphere of the participating organisations and their communities.  

For the participating Business Member Organizations (BMO) partners the project has led to increased capacity to contribute to a better business climate and support members to grow and develop. They have further been capacitated to promote sustainable development and women entrepreneurs within trade and private sector activities. 

Specific results within the focus areas of the programme:

 - Policy Advocacy - Increased capacity to influence decision makers 

 - Services - Increased capacity to offer services to member companies 

 - Networking - Increased capacity to take part in and arrange networking groups 

-  WEE - Increased engagement with women entrepreneurs 

All local BMO partners that have taken part of the program have been strongly engaged and have taken ownership of the implementation and their own development. 

The women&#x2019;s economic empowerment (WEE) component which was highly successful had an outreach to over 30 business member organisations in 15 countries and with more than 100 (mostly female) participants. 

The WEE programme goal was to develop the participant women&#x2019;s networks to develop capacity and exchange experiences for strengthening private sector development within the partner&#x2019;s organisations and communities.

Within this framework the programme gathered both partner organizations connected to CTS&#x2019;s work and a wider circle of business organizations and WEE ambassadors from developing countries. During the four years of implementation, this group gathered for networking events in South Africa, Indonesia and as a wrap up in Stockholm in March 2016. 

Through this work, the programme built a unique platform to promote WEE and entrepreneurship in the participant developing countries. 

The network is an asset not only for the project partners in developing countries but also for suppliers associated in the partner countries but also for the members (in Sweden) of CTS and other Swedish partners.

The results for the overarching programme have contributed to meeting the outcomes that was set in the program and this will contribute to the overall impact goal of strengthening the private sector and contributing to increased trade, sustainable development and poverty reduction for the participating organisations and their communities. 

The programme component of leadership through mentorship, Train the Trainers, on setting up local mentorship programs, has evolved to be offered to companies as a service for the chambers in Ethiopia, Zambia, Zimbabwe, and Iraq as well as in East Africa through the African Women Agribusiness Network (AWAN).  

Advocacy and training on sustainable industrial development - The partner organizations have been trained to sharpen their ability to work with competitiveness issues and political influence with seminars and workshops on Industrial Development. 

Specific issues in the training have been the importance of increased regional trade and removal of trade barriers, discriminatory taxes, labour market regulations, as well as sustainability, health and safety. 

Promoting an efficient commercial dispute resolution through arbitration and mediation has a major role for business, trade and investment as it provides efficiency and predictability in solving business conflicts. 

The programme has worked extensively with training in Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR) which enables so-called third-party services and revenue for the chambers. The program has for example strengthened the ADR capacity for the Addis Ababa Chamber of Commerce (AACCSA), which already had an arbitration institute but which needed increase both the government support (signing the UN convention on arbitration) and business deal flow on ADR. AACCSA has through the program received both national and international recognition and increased the number of cases submitted to the Institute for commercial dispute resolution.

The Zambia Chamber of Commerce also took an important step thanks to the program to build up an independent arbitration institutes and concluded agreements on this with the major key players Zimbabwe has also moved forward on wanting to take similar steps.

An important part of the programme results are tied to increased market access and direct trade with Sweden and the Nordic market. Several trade delegations have visited Sweden from East Africa (e.g. EAC countries), Ethiopia and Iraq. Direct trade deals have resulted from this and specifically from the so called Spicy Kitchen trade activities done with AWAN, for flower exports from Ethiopia to Sweden and in the area of green technology with Iraq. 

During the program, the partners have published several market reports in areas of importance for developing countries like lifestyle products and agribusiness, as well as report on green technology and regional trade. 

Environmental issues, including environmental technologies in the energy sector, but also widely linked to sustainability, has been a central part of our program, both as a part of the industrial development interventions and the special trainings with AWAN&#x2019;s green ambassadors. 

Energy efficiency, sustainable industrial production, etc. have been key elements in the program that led to several companies strengthened their environmental work. A major result is also the green technology investment made by the Ethiopian flower farmers as a result of EHPEA&#x2019;s training on composting and treatment of waste water. 

Proactive work on leadership and Ethics as part of the trainings has resulted in several of the BMO&#x2019;s and individual businesses taking pro-active action. One example is the Zambian Chamber of Commerce, which has developed and adopted a Code of Good Conduct for Ethics, which immediately had a positive impact for their board and general assembly. 

CTS broad-based capacity building program for the private sector in developing countries provides a unique method of cooperation and outreach by partnering with established business member organizations (BMOs) to reach the local business community.These BMOs provide the bottom-up base and the boots-on-the ground needed to effectively reach the business community and promote real change and development. 

By using a Train the Trainers model, the programme has built capacity with the BMO partners and with the local stakeholders that will remain sustainable when development assistance is not available.

The program has specifically focused on small and medium sized businesses, especially women run businesses, which form an effective way for aid to impact sustainable economic development to reduce poverty. The model has showed on an efficient way to push for reforming local structures and removing barriers which impede local sustainable development and growth. 

The program has also showed that co-creation, in both program design and implementation is efficient, since it creates the local ownership needed for long-term sustainable change. The co-creation process also ensures that the most significant gaps and barriers are focused on when designing and implementing the program. 

The program engaged hundreds of Swedish business representatives (including diaspora businesses), both through networking activities in Sweden and in the onsite implementation of the program in the partner countries (many of them on pro bono time).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="54050257" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
