<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5411004501-GGG-14010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Resources Group 2015-2017</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Water Resources Group 2015-2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">2030 Water Resources Group &#xE4;r ett unikt samarbete mellan offentliga, privata och civila organisationer. WRG faciliterar inkluderande och strukturerade processer genom sk nationella multi-stakeholders platforms i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nder och tillv&#xE4;xtekonomier f&#xF6;r att driva fram reformer och &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder inom vattenresursf&#xF6;rvaltningen. I dessa plattformar ing&#xE5;r beslutsfattare, f&#xF6;retag och representanter fr&#xE5;n civila samh&#xE4;llet som katalyserar h&#xE5;llbara, rationella l&#xF6;sningar p&#xE5; vattenproblem.  M&#xE5;let &#xE4;r att st&#xE4;nga gapet mellan efterfr&#xE5;gan p&#xE5; vatten och tillg&#xE5;ng till vatten innan &#xE5;r 2030.

WRG finansieras och styrs av IFC, som &#xE4;r v&#xE4;rd f&#xF6;r WRG, World Economic Forum, UNDP, IBRD, AfDB, ADB, Global Water Partnership, the Swiss agency for development and cooperation (SDC), Global Green Growth Institute och privata f&#xF6;retag (Nestl&#xE9;, PepsiCo, Coca Cola och Grundfos), V&#xE4;rldsnaturfonden WWF och BRAC, en Bangladeshisk NGO med global verksamhet.

WRG arbetar f&#xF6;r n&#xE4;rvarande i &#xE5;tta l&#xE4;nder samt tv&#xE5; indiska delstater; Bangladesh, Indien, Kenya, Tanzania, Mexiko, Mongoliet, Peru, Sydafrika, Karnataka och Mahrastra. De &#xE5;terupptar f&#xF6;rn&#xE4;rvarande &#xE4;ven sitt avbruta arbete i Jordanien.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second phase of core support to Water Resources Group (WRG) a         public-private-civil society partnership that helps governments to    accelerate reforms for sustainable water resources management. WRG    was initiated by World Economic Forum and is now hosted by IFC.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ultimate goal of WRG is to reduce the water gap and to improve water resource management in the countries in which WRG operates as well as on a global scale. Intended outcomes from their work in respective country/state are:- Increase in coordinated and collaborative action to resolve water issues and strengthen water policies and governance, informed by appropriate data analytics- Preparatory arrangements for implementation of proposals formalised by third party- Projects, programs, policy reforms and financing mechanisms under implementation by third party- Investments into infrastructure and technologies by third party</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFC/International Finance Corporation/The World Bank Group</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1423605.7561126072</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1053001.053001053</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1423605.7561126072</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1053001.053001053</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-01">2491310.073197</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">1423605.7561126072</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-28">1053001.053001053</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delivering on the ultimate goal of 2030 WRG&#xA0; to reduce the water gap and to improve water resource management, at an aggregated scale, 61 new projects, programs, policy reforms and financing mechanisms&#xA0;have been&#xA0;developed under&#xA0;the country-level Multi Stakeholder Platforms (MSPs). This has resulted in over 444 million USD&#xA0;of financing facilitated and approximately 385 million cubic meters/year less water&#xA0;being used. The later&#xA0;distributed on 152 million cubic meters less fresh water abstracted and 233 million cubic meters untreated waste/polluted water not&#xA0;being discharged.&#xA0;Furthermore an additional 14 000 cubic meters per year of water in increased cost-effective storage have been created.
The model adopted by 2030 WRG of Analyse-Convene-Transform (ACT) has been tested in 14 countries and states with operational MSPs in 11 geographies with satisfactory result. 2030 WRG has acted as a&#xA0;catalyst&#xA0; delivering on the indented outcomes in different ways described below under each of the four stated outcomes:
Increase in coordinated and collaborative action to resolve water issues and strengthen water policies and governance, informed by appropriate data analytics
- Conducting hydro-economic analyses &amp; research on critical water issues
- Monitoring progress and resolving issues through MSP discussions
A stakeholder survey was conducted in three countries (Mongolia, Bangladesh and Peru) in order to evaluate improvement in awareness levels connected to 2030 WRG activities. In general the survey showed a high level of awareness between 76-94 percent of the respondents.&#xA0;
Preparatory arrangements for implementation of proposals formalised by third party
- Convening government, private sector, &amp; civil society in structured MSPs with an apex body, thematic workstreams, and time-bound task forces to support workstreams
The number of proposals, as well as the value of budgets allocated or reallocated, for implementation by third party was 58 and USD 15 million respectively.&#xA0;
Projects, programs, policy reforms and financing mechanisms under implementation by third party
- Providing secretariat support to MSPs by developing concepts and proposals for implementation of&#xA0;solutions
During the years 87 concept notes have been approved by MSP partnership to a funding value of 6.87 million USD.
Investments into infrastructure and technologies by third party
- Identifying third-party implementers and mobilizing financing for project implementation, including innovative financial mechanisms&#xA0;
A total number of 642 partners from private, public and civil society participated in 46working groups that developed 66 final program proposals during the year. Of these, 61 is under&#xA0;implementation.
Some examples over the years from the different regions are:
Asia
World&#x2019;s largest community-based drip irrigation project at Ramthal in Karnataka covering 24,000 ha, with PPPs for micro irrigation and market linkages, part of a larger Drip-to-Market Agro Corridor approach to link drip irrigated areas with market opportunities.
Water pollution fee guidelines, based on Polluter Pays principles with a new water pollution tariff, adopted by Government of Mongolia
Africa
Establishment of Kilimanjaro Water Stewardship Platform (KWSP)&#xA0;and Mount Kenya Ewaso Water Partnership (MKEWP) in Tanzania and Kenya as catchment level forums to mitigate conflicts over water resources and develop initiatives to address water security risks.
Establishment of a Mine Water Coordinating Body (MWCB) in South Africa, bringing together companies, government and civil society and development and implementation of mine water for irrigation project pilot to reuse mine water for irrigation.
Latin America
Groundwater Management and Monitoring tariffs, Peru &#x2013; a new levy, proposed and designed by 2030 WRG and validated by the MSP for implementation, is being raised by utilities in Lima and Trujillo from industrial groundwater users to protect aquifers in water stressed areas.
Strengthening the planning and programming capabilities of the National Water Commission (CONAGUA), Mexico - 2030 WRG provided technical assistance to develop a prioritization system for capital investment in water infrastructure projects.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="54110045" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
