<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5410000201-GGG-43082</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBELICS Africalics Capacity Building Initative</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Globelics-Africalics kapacitetsbyggande initiativ</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Globelics is a global network of researchers working with an innovation systems approach to studies of development. Sida&apos;s support in this program is focusing on the Innovation Academies which provide support to PhD students from developing countries to attend research  courses on innovation systems. Support is also to the annual          scientific conference - where approx. 200-300 papers are presented.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Globelics &#xE4;r ett n&#xE4;tverk av forskare som anl&#xE4;gger en innovationssystemsansats i sin forskning och som ser p&#xE5; innovation kopplat till vidare strukturer f&#xF6;r kunskap och l&#xE4;rande i olika l&#xE4;nder. Sida har st&#xF6;tt Globelics verksamhet sedan 2006 och gick 2013 in i ett samarbete med det regionala n&#xE4;tverket Africalics. Sida&#x2019;s st&#xF6;d fokuserar p&#xE5; att st&#xE4;rka deltagandet (globalt och i Afrika) av juniora forskare fr&#xE5;n l&#xE5;ginkomstl&#xE4;nder p&#xE5; de &#xE5;rliga vetenskapliga konferenserna och forskarskolorna (akademier) och att p&#xE5; olika s&#xE4;tt st&#xE4;rka antalet och forskningskvalit&#xE9;n hos desamma. 

Sida har god erfarenhet av samarbetsparterna och det p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende programmet. En f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngning &#xE4;r n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;ndig f&#xF6;r att organisationerna som skall ta &#xF6;ver programmen f&#xE5;r tillr&#xE4;cklig kapacitet f&#xF6;r detta och f&#xF6;r att Sida skall hinna utv&#xE4;rdera dessa innan en ny fas kan beredas. Den beredning som ligger till grund f&#xF6;r denna f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngning &#xE4;r fortfarande relevant och ligger till grund f&#xF6;r denna bed&#xF6;mning. Beredningen har uppdaterats d&#xE4;r s&#xE5; varit n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;ndigt. Under 2016 ber&#xE4;knas en ny full beredning att &#xE4;ga rum inf&#xF6;r en potentiell ny fas av programmen.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aalborg University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aalborg University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">188775.1957097947</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">339789.3306150187</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">852115.703494442</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1195352.7019344305</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">928724.8051439621</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">592473.5581137148</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">188775.1957097947</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">339789.3306150187</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">852115.7034944419</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1195352.7019344307</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">928724.8051439621</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">592473.5581137148</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-07-01">4649725.698082</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-12-28">188775.1957097947</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-08-28">339789.3306150187</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-09-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-07-28">790701.9590984462</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">61413.7443959958</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-06-28">1195352.7019344305</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">928724.8051439621</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-28">514988.6051539765</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">77484.9529597382</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: Sida supported this program &#x201C;Globelics Research Capacity Building initiative on Innovation Systems &amp; Economic Development for Africa 2011-2015&quot; with an overall purpose of the program to promote the understanding of how innovation processes contribute to economic development. This program targets three main objectives to implement during 2011 - 2014 (extended to 2016):

1. build research capacity in the field of Innovation and Economic development in less developed
countries with special emphasis upon the least developed countries,
2. contribute to capacity building in the field of innovation and development policy in these countries,
3. Contribute to the knowledge base for donor-policies that aim at promoting economic development through support to innovation and capacity building.

Hence, the overall outcomes of this program has contributed to the set of three main objectives: Young research from LMICs globally and Africa region specifically have been able to participate in capacity building initatives as well as in international research activities, building networks and setting up potential future partnerships. 

Results and highlights for the Globelics/Africalics Capacity Building&apos;s whole project period 2011 - 2016:

- Globelics annual international conferences were organised as a global platform for scholars to develop research and networks. The annual conference often a great success with over 350-450 submitted papers of which between 150-180 were selected to present at the conference. Sida&apos;s funds have been specifically used to taget support on travel grants to young researchers and scholars from LMICs, enabling them to participate and deepen their knowledge and contribute to innovation research in the field of development. Over the entire period of this program, more than 3000 scholars have attended the Globelics Conference, which has travelled around the world and between the continents. The Globelics Website has had more than 4 million visits and there are 2,000 registered users. At conferences and in other contexts Globelics engages in dialogue with donor organisations, policy makers, NGO&#x2019;s and business managers on how to use the insights produced within the network. Thematic reports on natural resources and health systems, low carbon innovation have reached its goals, an average of 1000 download per report two years after publication, and 60+ physical reports have been sent to policy makers and donors.

-  Globelics as organisation/network has moved proactively towards gender balance both in terms of governance and acitivties. The President of Globelics and the Presidents of three of the four major regional Lics are women. The participation rates for female scholars in conferences and research training varies between 30-50%. Currently 8 out of 18 members of the Globelics Scientific Board are women while the new constitution has been designed so that it guarantees 50% for each gender in the Globelics Scientific Board. In terms of Sida travel support, grants have been made to make Globelics conference participants increased from 50% young female researchers during the early years in the program to 60-70% during the last two annual conferences.

- The initiation of the regional network Africalics in 2012 and Sida&apos;s support begining in 2013 has gone well on track to build institutional capacity for Africalics in Nairobi focusing on similar objectives of the Globelics but in regional context: capacity building for a new network of young researchers from LMICs in Africa in innovation systems and development, and increase the use of insights from improved research on innovation and deveopment by policy makers at national and regional level of Africa. Africalics has developed its programs on annual conference, Africalics academy for research skills training, visiting fellowship program as well as interactions with policy making by the support of Globelics secretariat in AAU. The positive result is now that Africalics has graduated from the Globelics and runs on its own capacity by the Africalics secretariat at ACTS in Nairobi.

- At the end of 2016 the Globelics Scientific Board unanimously agreed on a Globelics Constitution. The aim is to move towards a membership-based organisation and to give scholars who are active in the Globelics network the opportunity to become Members of Globelics and through voting procedure to influence the composition of the Globelics Scientific Board. With the beginning of 2017 the function as Secretariat has moved from Aalborg, Denmark to Rio de Janeiro, Brazil making the goal of Globelics a south-based network into actual effects. The network has moved to the next step from an open network to a more consolidated global network and organisation, connecting as an umbrella all the regional-LICS network on central issues and acitivities as well as widen impacts of the network.

Some highlights of the results in 2016:

- Globelics 2016 annual conference in Indonesia received 207 out of 353 submitted papers (59 %) came from participants from Low and Lower middle income countries. Out of the 150 accepted papers and posters 75 (50 %) came from Low and Lower middle income countries.

- 74 young scholars received research training in &quot;how to get your research published&quot; begun to be implemented in 2015 at both Africalics and Globelics academies in 2016.

- During 2016, Globelics focused on promoting open access activity. A total of 18 Globelics papers have been made available as open access. Globelics has also utilised Sida&apos;s fund  in 2016 to get subsidized open access with Elsevier to research policy for up to 300 Globelics members for 2 years ad on 100 e-books of relevant theories on development.

- Africalics have been running in all three primary activities: 
1. Annual conference: The last one in Kigali Rwanda centred around the theme of unpacking systems of innovation for sustainable development in Africa had 220 participants from 35 countries working on innovation and development in Africa. 140 papers were submitted, of these 57 papers and 9 posters were accepted to present at the conference that included thematic sessions, learning and teaching sessions; 
2. Africalics annual academy in 2016 with 20 junior researchers accepted from 57 applicants (of which 50% came from low-income African countries). This is lower numbers than expected as the academy was targeted French speaking countries; 
3. Training of PhD supervisors with around 20 PhD supersivors were trained on innovation research areas and invited to AAU to meet and exchange with their PhD students&apos;s supervisors at AAU. The purpose was to improve ways of supervising and facilitating PhD students&apos;work;
4. Visiting Fellowship Program and PhD training for African students at AAU. During 2016, 5 PhD students from Kenya, Ghana, Tanzania and Nigeria were accepted to this AAU PhD fellowship program and received research training; 
5. To increase the size and effectiveness of the Africalics researchers through a vibrant online community: Africalics website as a knowledge bank has hit 380,144 visitors, 5963 numbers of downloads, and public seminars: over the last 2 years Africalics has organised 7 public seminars with 243 participants, opened to all with an interest in STI and their implications for Africa.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="54100002" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1140102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0.0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <title>Research cooperation 2015-2022</title>
    <titleSV>Forskningssamarbete 2015-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
