<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5410017104-GGG-12182</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">WHO Forskningsst&#xF6;d 2020-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WHO Research support 2020-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">De tre f&#xF6;ljande WHO-baserade forskningsprogrammen har ans&#xF6;kt om fortsatt st&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n Sida: 
i) The UNICEF-UNDP-World Bank-WHO Special Programme for Research and Training in Tropical Diseases (TDR);  
ii) The UNDP-UNFPA-UNICEF-WHO-World Bank Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction, (HRP); 
iii) Alliance for Health Policy and Systems Research (AHPSR). 

Det f&#xF6;reslagna st&#xF6;det &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning p&#xE5; tidigare avtal 2016-2019. Det totala beloppet &#xE4;r 307,8 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r perioden 2020 &#x2013; 2022, varav 138,8 MSEK till TDR, 99 MSEK till HRP och 70 MSEK till AHPSR. St&#xF6;det &#xE4;r i huvudsak icke &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt. 

TDR:s aktiviteter kommer under avtalsperioden att ha tyngdpunkten p&#xE5; forskning om hinder f&#xF6;r effektivt genomf&#xF6;rande av befintliga kontrollprogram f&#xF6;r fattigdomsrelaterade infektionssjukdomar. HRP:s inriktning innefattar forskning om en bredd av fr&#xE5;gor relaterade till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och r&#xE4;ttigheter (SRHR), bland annat migranters behov av SRHR, ungdomars behov av SRHR och kvinnors st&#xE4;rkta m&#xF6;jligheter till s&#xE4;ker abort. AHPSR kommer att fokusera ytterligare p&#xE5; att genom forskning om h&#xE4;lsosystem och policies tillsammans med beslutsfattare bidra till att fattiga l&#xE4;nder kan nyttja sina resurser f&#xF6;r h&#xE4;lsosektorn p&#xE5; ett s&#xE5; effektivt s&#xE4;tt som m&#xF6;jligt.

Ut&#xF6;ver icke &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt st&#xF6;d ing&#xE5;r fyra komponenter med s&#xE5; kallad &quot;mjuk &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkning&quot;: en global h&#xE4;lsoforskningskonferens (genom AHPSR), n&#xE4;tverket ESSENCE, initiativet f&#xF6;r social h&#xE4;lsoinnovation, och st&#xE4;rkt WASH-integrering (de tre senare genom TDR). Totalt uppg&#xE5;r denna mjuka &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkning till 8% av insatsens budget.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The following three WHO-based research programmes have applied for continued support from Sida:
i) The UNICEF-UNDP-World Bank-WHO Special Programme for Research and Training in Tropical Diseases (TDR); 
ii) The UNDP-UNFPA-UNICEF-WHO-World Bank Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction, HRP; 
iii) Alliance for Health Policy and Systems Research (AHPSR). 

The proposed support is a continuation of the previous agreement 2016-2019. The total amount is SEK 307,8 million for the period 2020 - 2022, of which SEK 138,8 million to TDR, SEK 99 million to HRP and SEK 70 million to AHPSR. The contribution support is essentially unearmarked

During the agreement period, TDR&apos;s activities will focus on research on barriers to effective implementation of existing control programs for infectious diseases disproportionally affecting people living in poverty. HRP&apos;s focus includes, amongst many areas related to sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR), research on migrants&apos; needs for SRHR, on adolescents&#x2019; need for SRHR, and women&apos;s enhanced opportunities for safe abortion. AHPSR will focus further on researching health systems and policies together with policy makers to help low- and lower middle-income countries use their resources for the health sector as efficiently as possible.

In addition to undesignated support, there are four components with so-called &quot;soft earmarking&quot;: A Global Health Research Conference (through AHPSR), the ESSENCE Network, the Social Health Innovation Initiative, and enhanced WASH integration within the TDR (the three latter through TDR). In total, this soft earmarking amounts to 8% of the total support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Three WHO-based research programmes are proposed for continued support:
i) The UNICEF-UNDP-World Bank-WHO Special Programme for Research and Training in Tropical Diseases, TDR; ii) The UNDP-UNFPA-UNICEF-WHO-World Bank Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction, HRP; and iii) Alliance for Health Policy and Systems Research, AHPSR, or &quot;the Alliance&quot;.
Sida/Sweden is a long-standing supporter of TDR since its creation in 1974. TDR is one of the earliest examples of a Global Health Partnership and has repeatedly received good reviews by external evaluators because of its relevance to both health and development. TDR is the 2011 recipient of the Gates Award for Global Health. With its long history of support, Sida is well familiar with the achievements of the programme. TDR helps facilitate, support and influence efforts to combat diseases of poverty, with the mission to &quot;support effective and innovative global health research, through strengthening the research capacity of disease-affected countries, and promoting the translation of evidence into interventions that reduce the burden of infectious diseases and build resilience in the most vulnerable populations&quot;. TDR main areas are i) Research for policy; ii) Research for implementation; iii) Research for innovation; and iv) Research for integrated approaches.   
Sida/Sweden is an as long-standing supporter of HRP, even since a couple of years before its creation in 1972. As such, Sida is equally familiar with the HRP&apos;s achievements. HRP is the main instrument within the United Nations system for research in human reproduction, bringing together policy-makers, scientists, health care providers, clinicians, consumers and community representatives to identify and address priorities for research to improve sexual and reproductive health. The mission of HRP is &quot;the attainment of all people of the highest possible level of sexual and reproductive health. HRP strives for a world where all womens and mens rights to enjoy sexual and reproductive health are promoted and protected, and all women and men, including adolescents and those who are underserved and marginalized, have access to sexual and reproductive health information and services&quot;. 
AHPSR is a younger programme than TDR and HRP and recently celebrated its 20th anniversary. Sweden was one of the drivers of the creation of AHPSR and has been actively involved since then, leading to good insights into their activities. AHPSR work to improve the health of those in low- and middle-income countries by supporting the generation and use of evidence that strengthens health systems. Together with organizations around the world, the AHPSR aims to i) provide a unique forum for the health policy and systems research community; ii) support institutional capacity for the conduct and uptake of health policy and systems research; iii) stimulate the generation of knowledge and innovations to nurture learning and resilience in health systems; and iv) increase the demand for and use of knowledge for strengthening health systems.
&#xA0;
HRP and TDR are special programmes of WHO which gives them an independent status in relation to WHO. They are co-sponsored by a number of UN-agencies (UNICEF, UNDP, World Bank and WHO are co-sponsors of both TDR and HRP, and additionally, UNFPA is co-sponsor of HRP). As a WHO-hosted partnership, AHPSR is also guaranteed its independence. The difference between the two set-ups used to be the co-sponsorship of the special programmes, although today the definitions are being discussed at WHO. The future format of AHPSR is described later in this appraisal.
When the special programmes were created in the early 1970s WHO did not actively engage in research, but as a number of member states could see the importance of producing research of relevance (in this case tropical diseases and human reproduction), TDR and HRP were created. Over the years, the importance of producing evidence to feed into policies and guidelines was increasingly recognized and other UN agencies joined the effort as co-sponsors.
Similarly, the areas of health policy and systems research were neglected and in the late 1990s a group of global health leaders, including senior scientists, policy makers and representatives of various agencies and programs with a stake in health policy and systems research agreed on the need to create a body that would address these areas, and AHPSR was created as a hosted partnership at WHO.
Being based at WHO and having a close interaction with the co-sponsors provides the research programmes with a unique opportunity to accelerate translation of research results into policies and guidelines. Through country and regional offices and their close relation to a countys Ministry of Health, the possibility for implementation at this level is also improved. As WHO is now putting more emphasis into the country and regional offices, this is expected to play an even more important role in the coming years. The importance of research and evidence is even more clear now that WHO has assigned a first Chief Scientist and a Science Division, and one can foresee a closer interaction between the research programmes and WHO at all levels.
Over the years, as the world changes, the areas of research addressed as well as the ways to address the need of evidence and implementation have changed in the three programmes. The research programmes show an embedded ability to adapt their activities to changes in global health and to take leading roles in the global research agenda.
There are still pertinent questions to be addressed in the programmes respective areas. For example, there is presently a strong focus on implementation research and interaction with decision-makers, as well as strengthening research capacity in LMICs and ensuring that high quality research is done in countries. 
As the bulk of Sida&apos;s support to the programmes is given as undesignated funding, the results of the upcoming phase are expected to contribute to the attainment of the respective missions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41143" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WHO/World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41143" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WHO/World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="121" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health, General</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12182" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical research</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3 - By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.3 - Senast 2030 utrota epidemierna av aids, tuberkulos, malaria och f&#xF6;rsummade tropiska sjukdomar samt bek&#xE4;mpa hepatit, vattenburna sjukdomar och andra smittsamma sjukdomar.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">443050.5194184379</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">443050.5194184379</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">738351.955003</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">325743.509560572</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-28">443050.5194184379</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_AmendmentWHO2021signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1st amendment WHO research programmes, 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_WHO_Researchamendment2signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2nd amendment research programmes at WHO</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_WHOagreement_Supporttoresearchpg2020-2022.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WHO agreement_ Support to research pg 2020-2022.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_BeslutominsatsWHOForskningsstod2020-2022.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats WHO Forskningsst&#xF6;d 2020-2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_DecisiononAmendmentofContributionWHO2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om &#xE4;ndring av insats WHO forskning juni 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/forsk/54100171_DecisiononAmendmentofContributionWHOadditionalfunds2021_signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on 2nd Amendment of Contribution to research programmes at WHO</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alliance for HPSR
The biggest news 2021 are the adoption of the new Strategy 2021-2025 which was discussed extensively by both the Board and the Scientific and Technical Advisory Committee (STAC) before approval. There was an impressive process to get input from both implementing organisations (such as Ministries of Health and global health organisations) and WHO at national, regional and HQ levels. While the &quot;six building blocks&quot; of health systems are still in focus, this strategy also looks beyond them. This means integrating additional perspectives, such as climate change, inequalities and other determinants of health. In addition to Ministries of Health, other ministries such as education, finance and environment may be involved in future activities of the Alliance. 

Connected to the new Strategy, a new set of indicators has been developed. These were reported on for the first time in 2022 (referring to 2021) showing interesting progress. Some indicators are overachieved (such as number of collaborations within WHO and with other partners, 22 of the 25 predicted for the 5 years), whilst other have some way to go (such as number of methods, tools and frameworks developed, 1 out of 5-8 expected in 2025). A deeper insight into what each of the indicators really means and how adequate they are would be interesting, and Sida takes part of the Boards work group on monitoring and evaluation. 
- The report shows that 2021 was one of the most productive years in the Alliance&apos;s history. 208 grants were provided by Alliance in 2021, in 59 countries around the world. 38% of the 107 peer-reviewed journal articles were led by female authors, and 38% are from LMICs. A large number of virtual events took place, and more than 70% of registrants were based on LMICs.
- A flagship report was published in 2021, and launched with a very popular webinar: &quot;Learning Health Systems&quot;. 
- A new website for the Alliance went live in 2021, and a new online community platform was opened (the Alliance Hive). 
- The Alliance-supported journal articles have increased substantially (44 to 74 to 91 2019-2021) although there were fewer female lead authors as well as LMICs lead authors from 2020.
- It&apos;s been clear that too little research on health systems is performed in francophone Africa and renewed efforts are planned. In 2021, 10 young researchers were selected for the Alliance fellowship programme. 

Selected research results:
- The Alliance together with UNICEF undertook more than 50 embedded implementation research studies focusing on immunization across 16 countries. The studies spotlight challenges and bottlenecks for improving vaccination coverage, and they identify and test strategies to address immunisation service delivery constraints. 
- An online course on gender and intersectionality was developed consisting of nine modules, using case-based learning. It&apos;s been piloted and is ready to be launched in 2022.
- Participatory research studies were performed in two slums in Kampala to identify priority issues related to the impacts of Covid-19 lockdowns, and to co-create strategies to overcome them. The communities were put at the center of the decision-making right from the start of the process, and as a result they were empowered to find long-lasting solutions that worked for them. One challenge is food security, and instead of (only) focusing on direct food distribution, backyard gardening was initiated and helped in subsequent lockdowns. 
___________________________________________________________________________________________

HRP

2021 was both a challenging and successful year for HRP. At a general level, the backlash to SRHR is challenging, especially as some activities are complicated to implement, in particular at country-level. The backlash is also an opportunity, as certain donors show an increased will to support HRP activities. In 2021, the Covid-19 pandemic still affected HRPs work, both challenging the implementation of ongoing projects and bringing in opportunities such as research connected to the pandemic and its consequences. In addition to this, new initiatives were initiated, such as a stronger emphasis on decolonisation/historical power imbalances and the connection between climate change/environmental degradation and SRHR.  

In March 2021 the current HRP Director announced his retirement but agreed to stay on until December 2021. In March, the process of recruiting a new Director was initiated, resulting in a final decision early 2022. The new Director will be in office from July 1st 2022. Recruitment is generally a long process at WHO and positions at country and regional level are favoured. HRP is still understaffed (25% in 2021) but some improvements have been possible (20% in 2022), including two critical positions: a gender advisor and a human rights advisor with expertise in SRHR. These two advisors presented their initial thoughts at the online intersessional meeting in November. The intersessional meeting was the second one of its kind. Having such a meeting decreases some of the pressure from the annual Policy and Coordination Committee (PCC) meeting (HRP&apos;s Steering Board) by providing information on various processes and allowing for discussions amongst the PCC members. The intersessional meeting also keeps a certain momentum and interest, and provides members with updated information to be shared in member countries/donor organisations. Sida has been instrumental in initiating these meetings. In 2021 the intersessional meeting included an updated financial report and analysis, a technical session on HRPs work on gender and human rights, and an update on HRP results and activities so far.

The highlight of the year is usually the PCC meeting, and the Conclusion on Performance is usually written in connection with this meeting. At PCC all reports are presented and discussed for final approvals.  

PCC35 and some highlights
This 35th PCC meeting 27-28 April 2022 was all virtual for the third time, and even more smoothly carried through than previous years. There were participants from all over the world, as far as Tonga. Prior to PCC there were three technical webinars: one on HRP participation on Covid-19 response and how local researchers were crucial in the response; one on rights and gender, and one on the integration of digital tools and self-care in national health systems. The webinars allowed for online discussions which were summarised and further discussed for potential recommendations at PCC. There were presenters from country-level and different actor groups in the webinars, and even the Minister of Health of Burkina Faso gave a presentation. As Chair, Sweden had an active role in the session on rights and gender. 

The reports were shared with Sida as preparations of the PCC meeting, and all reports were sent on time this year (as opposed to last year). 

Selected results from HRP in 2021:
- 88 projects were supported by HRP, of which 38% are headed by partners in AFR.
- 211 articles were published in peer-review scientific journals, and of non-WHO papers 42% had a lead author from AMR (mainly Brazil) and 25% from AFR. 67% are published by an institution in a LMIC. 60% have a female lead author. Most publications (35%) are related to maternal and perinatal health. 
- 34 systematic reviews were published in 2021, where the great majority (52% of those excl WHO reviews) were published by an institution in AMR (mainly Brazil) and 66% in LMIC. Also here the majority is related to maternal and perinatal health. 
- The co-sponsors of HRP (UNFPA, WHO, UNDP, UNICEF and WB) are important partners to HRP, especially as they can effectively get an impact of research results produced by HRP. The number of collaborations with co-sponsors and other UN partners has increased much the past years, and in 2021 there were 121 ongoing projects. Most are with UNFPA and WHO, and mainly within the areas of family planning and contraception, and health systems, including self-care and digital innovations. Collaboration take place both at country-level and international level (more details can be found in the dashboard linked to above). One example is the development of new guidelines, the WHO&apos;s Digital Adaptation Kits (DAKs) which were pioneered by HRP. The DAK for Family Planning (developed together with WHO, UNFPA and other partners) provided a new tool for countries implementing the WHO recommendations in their digital systems. 
- In 2021, 1 173 individuals (60% female) were trained as a result of HRP Alliance activities, a doubling compared to 2020. The HRP training hub in Brazil, CEMICAMP, was very active and trained 627 of them. Only 15 were trained by APHRC in Nairobi, who also get support from Sida/Sweden directly (both from the research strategy, and from the regional SRHR strategy). Most courses were short, but there are a few PhD students (5) and Masters students (17). Most (44%) of the individuals trained come from AFR. 87 scientific articles were published within the HRP Alliance initiative. 
Since inception five years ago, 92 individuals have completed their MSc degree and 35 their PhD. A mentorship programme with early career female researchers was initiated in 2020 with 13 mentor-mentee pairs. This programme is to be scaled in 2022. 
- Each day, about 800 women and girls die from complications related to pregnancy or childbirth, most of which are preventable or treatable. 99% occur in LMICs, and the highest risk of maternal death is for adolescent girls under 15 years. HRP is addressing research and evidence needs from different perspectives, including the use of &quot;living guidelines&quot; to respond to new, important evidence as it emerges. This way, the latest evidence and recommendations reach health workers worldwide as quickly as possible. In 2021, nine recommendations were updated related to maternal health. 
- An HRP-led study involving 17 countries shed light on the severity of abortion-related complications and their clinical management. Data was collected from 20 000 women, and evidence showed that women in Africa are twice as likely to have a potentially life-threatening complication, or nearly died, than in Latin America and the Caribbean. 
- In 2021, the &quot;WHO preferred product characteristics&quot; (PPCs) for gonococcal vaccines were published. PPCs are supposed to encourage innovation and development of vaccines. Vaccination for gonorrhoeae is crucial, as resistance to the existing antibiotics is hindering treatment. 
- New recommendations for screening for cervical cancer were developed, including a DNA-based test for human papillomavirus (HPV) which increases availability. The new guidelines include specific recommendations for women living with HIV, who have a six-fold risk of cervical cancer. 
- WHO and HRP published a series of country profiles to summarise data on key issues for adolescent sexual and reproductive health and rights (ASRHR). This gives an accurate picture of ASRHR issues for 50 different countries, and bring together relevant data on ten different areas, including sexual activity, child marriage, gender-based violence and menstruation. 
- HRP coordinated with partners across the world to produce guidance on digital health. This innovative digital tools aim to connect decision-makes with health systems, and health workers with high-quality evidence-based WHO guidance. HRP also conducts research on self-care innovations.
- HRP launched the &quot;SRHR Policy Portal&quot;, to improve access to the most up to date global, regional and country data for policies and indicators related to SRHR. 
- Aspects of historical power imbalances (incl decolonisation) are increasingly included throughout HRP activities. 

_______________________________________________________________________________________________

TDR
The COVID-19 pandemic has shown the critical importance of research to the lives and livelihoods of people across the world, it has also been a challenge for execution of plans and programmes at all levels. In general terms, while the pandemic response demonstrated what many call a miracle of science, it has failed to ensure equitable access to the benefits of that science. The distribution of life-saving products to the worlds highest-risk and most vulnerable populations thus remains a major challenge. TDR has been placing equitable access at the centre of its approach to implementation research, with a focus on tackling neglected tropical diseases, tuberculosis, malaria and other vector-borne diseases. Given the negative impact of the pandemic on such devastating diseases, TDRs wide range of research activities has been critical in sustaining these various disease control programmes. As an example, the pandemic has created many barriers to TB treatment and care. This prompted TDR and several partners to launch an implementation research initiative to help countries in West and Central Africa evaluate new and adapted strategies to ensure the continuity of TB care. This demonstrates the power of implementation research as an essential tool to mitigate the impact of COVID-19 on other disease control efforts. Strengthening capacity to conduct such research remains more important than ever, and TDRs training programmes have been innovative in their partnerships with institutions in LMICs. In particular, the Clinical Research and Development Fellowship programme has built an impressive cadre of scientists who are now making a real difference as research leaders in their countries.

At the latest Board meeting, participants welcomed the agility and flexibility of various activities that are responding well to the changes, including successful virtual capacity building activities, laser-focused research in support of public health and disease control implementation, as well as the increased global visibility of TDRs role in global health through the highly successful Global Health Matters podcast.

Selected results from TDR in 2021 as per strategic areas of work 
1) Research for implementation: Key achievements from 2021 
- 11 studies completed on strategies to mitigate the impact of COVID-19 on TB control in West and Central Africa
&#x2022; 4 case study projects selected to test TDRs framework on a multisectoral approach to vector-borne diseases in Latina America, Asia and Africa
&#x2022; One Health approach for tackling vector-borne diseases is being piloted by 4 research teams in Africa.

Important Example: 
Improving the impact of an innovative malaria control tool for remote Amazon populations
In collaboration with TDR, the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria, and the Pan American Health Organization (PAHO), scientists are conducting research to support implementation of a promising malaria self-diagnosis and self-treatment kit for hard-to-reach populations in Suriname, Brazil and French Guiana.
While Suriname is now very close to achieving elimination of malaria, foci of transmission of the disease persist among illegal migrant workers crossing the borders with Brazil and French Guiana. These populations are often traveling to and from gold mines in the Amazon rainforest and have very little or no access to health services.
To address this challenge, an innovative self-diagnosis and self-treatment kit called Malakit was developed through a collaboration between three scientific centres: the Centre dInvestigation Clinique Antilles-Guyane (Cayenne Hospital in French Guiana), the Oswaldo Cruz Foundation in Brazil and the Foundation for the Advancement of Scientific Research in Suriname.
Published results of a tri-national pilot trial show that Malakit was used correctly by 72% of the 223 persons who reported using it. The intervention appears to have accelerated the decline in malaria incidence in the study sites by 43%.
This encouraging result has prompted the research team and Surinames Ministry of Health to include the kit in their routine tools against malaria and to evaluate the potential for further deployment. Following discussions between the Global Fund, TDR and the respective ministries of health and research teams, a research project has been developed to improve the impact of this Malakit intervention
&#x2022; 35 operational research studies from countries in Asia and Africa on AMR completed and published
&#x2022; New SORT IT training module piloted to strengthen researchers communication skills and enhance uptake of research findings

2) Research Capacity Strengthening: Key achievements from 2021
Postgraduate Training Scheme:
&#x2022; With more than 400 masters students trained in IR since 2015, seven universities in LMICs selected for second phase of training programme (20222026). Example: The Gambian Ministry of Health is conducting IR to explore new approaches to eliminating schistosomiasis
&#x2022; TDRs MOOC on IR guiding development and design of this research
&#x2022; 46 students from French-speaking countries in West Africa selected to study at Cheikh Anta Diop University in Dakar, Senegal

Updates to flagship training tools:
&#x2022; MOOC on IR now available in all six UN languages
&#x2022; New module on gender and intersectionality developed for IR toolkit

Clinical Research and Development Fellowship:
&#x2022; 18 fellows selected to be placed at nine training partner organizations

3) Global engagement: Key achievements from 2021
&#x2022; As a member of the COVID-19 Clinical Research Coalitions data sharing working group, TDR has contributed to the review of COVID-19 data sharing platforms
&#x2022; 2 new research tools for social innovators published:
o Social Innovation in Health Monitoring &amp; Evaluation Framework
o Research checklist for social innovation
&#x2022; Small Grants Scheme with WHO regional offices tackled new topics, e.g. health and migration and implementation of International Health Regulations
&#x2022; Women in Science compendium featuring 15 women global health leaders from TDR Global community launched on International Womens Day
&#x2022; Practical guide on Public engagement and crowdfunding in health research published

4) Promoting gender responsive interventions for infectious diseases
Expansion of intersectional gender research projects to combat infectious diseases, including on social innovation:
 - Promoting and recognizing the importance of intersectional gender analysis.
 - Exploring how vulnerability to disease, exposure, experiences of disease, health-related decision-making, responses to treatment and discrimination and unequal access to health care are experienced differently by different groups.
- Consolidated training courses on gender-based analysis of VBDs and climate change
 Institutionalized in public health programmes of selected African Institutions.
-  Upcoming MOOC module to be offered in parallel

Summary of TDRs contributions to the COVID-19 response effort
&#x2022; Supporting IR to mitigate the impact of the pandemic on disease control efforts for TB, malaria, NTDs
&#x2022; Supporting postgraduate trainees to conduct IR on COVID-19-related issues in their countries
&#x2022; As a member of COVID-19 Clinical Research Coalition, contributing to review of COVID-19 data sharing practices
&#x2022; Developed a training course to strengthen COVID-19 vaccine safety monitoring systems in African countries
&#x2022; Leading COVAX/ACT workstream on biomanufacture workforce development</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="54100171" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1180302" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="7100000000.0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <title>Global strategy on socially sustainable development 2018-2022</title>
    <titleSV>Global strategi f&#xF6;r socialt h&#xE5;llbar utveckling 2018-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
