<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5410016801-GGG-41082</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">KVA SSEESS St&#xF6;d 2014-2016, Swedish Secretariat for Earth System Sciences</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KVA SSEESS support 2014-2016, Swedish Secretariat for Earth System Sciences</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">I samarbete med fyra stora statliga myndigheter f&#xF6;r forskningsfinansiering (Formas, Forte, Vetenskapsr&#xE5;det, Vinnova) har sedan 2009 vid Kungl. Vetenskapsakademien (KVA) uppr&#xE4;ttats ett sekretariat f&#xF6;r Milj&#xF6;- och Resursfr&#xE5;gor (Swedish Secretariat for Environmental Earth System Sciences - SSEESS) i syfte att arbeta med internationella klimat och Milj&#xF6;fr&#xE5;gor. Med avsikit att forts&#xE4;tta samarbetet inom ramen f&#xF6;r SSEESS avser Sida och Parterna att b&#xF6;rjar ett nytt avtal f&#xF6;r perioden 1 januari 2014 t o m 31 december 2016 (fas II) enligt ett uppdaterade m&#xE5;len och strategin.

SSEESS &#xE4;r ett program inom KVA som syftar till att bygga nya allianser och tv&#xE4;rvetenskapliga initiativ f&#xF6;r att bem&#xF6;ta de utmaningar som tornar upp sig p&#xE5; milj&#xF6;, resurs och klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar. Detta skall ske i form av samarbete med svenska forskare och med International Council for Science (ICSU), dess Regional Office for Africa (ICSU ROA) och med andra internationella organisationer.

Programmet skall underl&#xE4;tta f&#xF6;r svenska forskares deltagande i internationella forskningsprogram inom omr&#xE5;det globala milj&#xF6;f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar och h&#xE5;llbar utveckling, samt att vara en p&#xE5;litlig k&#xE4;lla till information om dessa fr&#xE5;gor f&#xF6;r svenska beslutsfattare.

Sidas st&#xF6;d till programmet i form av en sekundering baseras p&#xE5; regeringens strategi f&#xF6;r Sidas st&#xF6;d till forskningssamarbete 2010 med syfte att st&#xE4;rka kunskaps- och forskningskapaciteten i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nder. SSEESS ska i samarbete med Sida fr&#xE4;mja deltagande av forskare fr&#xE5;n utvecklingsl&#xE4;nder i globala forskningsprogram och globala avtal i samband med milj&#xF6; och klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndring, och att &#xF6;ka m&#xF6;jligheten f&#xF6;r svenska &apos;global environmental change&apos; (GEC) forskare att interagera med forskarsamh&#xE4;llet inom h&#xE5;llbar utveckling och bist&#xE5;nd p&#xE5; global, regional och lokal niv&#xE5;.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to the Swedish Secretariat for Global Environmental Earth     System Sciences (SSEESS), Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences, KVA,     namely a Sida financed research adviser, networking and conference    support for strengthening research and research capacity in Global    Environmental change sciences.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kungliga Vetenskapsakademien</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College Research Other</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="41082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental research</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">380909.3427017887</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">312718.7310927361</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">309822.9416233273</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">380909.3427017887</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">312718.7310927361</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">156722.9591538596</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">-164403.7674037674</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1151620.28601</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-28">380909.3427017887</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-28">312718.7310927361</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-02-28">156722.9591538596</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-28">-164403.7674037674</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: Results and highlights for the whole project period 2014 - 2017:

- SSEESS has strengthened its strategic work on creating further collaboration between Swedish and international researchers within the ICSU, ISSC, SDSN and FE programs, partly through different forms of direct support to researchers and the other through strategic cooperation with the international programs. SSEESS has succeeded in the nomination of several Swedish researchers to different international expert panels.

- The focus has been to strengthen Swedish research network as well as communication through different channels, promoting Swedish interests and approaches in research collaboration (north-south focus) as well as transdisciplinary research in global environment-climate change and sustainable development.

- External evaluation of the SSEESS program in 2016 highlighted an essential role played by the organisation in the setting up of the office of the Future Earth hub in Stockholm that serves as a platform for collaboration between Swedish and international researchers around crucial research themes and networks for the SDGs. 

- Under Sida&#x2019;s specific objectives through the contribution to fund SSEESS Research Links and SSEESS North-South Travel Grants, SSEESS was able to focus on creating research links and facilitating collaboration between Swedish and researchers from the global south. During 2014 &#x2013; 2017 The yearly scholarships and travel grants focusing on research collaboration with countries in Africa, Asia and Latin America have constituted 59 research groups from 16 different Swedish universities. This made it possible for their research projects acrossed multiple disciplines to be developed together with researchers from 55 countries, mostly in Africa and Asia and Latin America.

- During the project period, SSEESS has been able to facilitate and create a resource pool of 60 Swedish experts to be nominated in different international organisation and research councils through travel support for them to network and present at various high-level panels and group meetings on environment and climate change, the global change towards sustainability. This was a capacity strength that SSEESS has been able to contribute in the network and interactions between researchers and decision makers in Sweden and globally.

- SSEESS has been initial to establish a Committee for Global Environment Change at KVA with committee members representing multidiscipline and universities in Sweden. Many of them are member of the global and regional collaborative networks with researchers in the global south.

Results and achievements during 2016, the final year of this contribution:

- Organised several thematic workshops on &#x201C;Animal Movements &#x2013; Ecosystems and societal impacts&#x201D;, &#x201C;On Time: Dimensions of marine and coastal global environmental change&#x201D; as well as the launching workshop for the ISSC&#x2019;s World Social Science Report 2016 at KVA. 

- SSEESS also organised scientific seminars and information disseminations together with RIFO, SOLAS, IHOPE, Riksdagen, Future Earth, ISSC, European Alliance.

- SSEESS played also a crucial role to the SDSN Northern Europe office to be hosted at G&#xF6;teborg&#x2019;s Environmental Science Center (GMV) inaugurated in April 2016.

- SSEESS joined Sida in Amedalsveckan in Visby 2016 for joint-presentations on environment/climate change and the needs for cooperation and research development. 

-  Open calls for North-South Travel grants and research links were opened with special focus on research collaboration with researchers from low-income countries. Other special calls were arranged in collaboration with ISSC and SDSN.

- SSEESS actively participated in international collaboration to work on open calls within the Belmont Forum as well as in the board decision-making process.

- During 2016, a great deal of initial plans could not be carried out on full-scale due to the decision of closing down the secretariat made by a joint decision by the four financiers (predominantly by VR and FORMAS, and Sida and FORTE). 

- Open calls for funding Research Links and North-South Travel Gateway specifically funded by Sida were launched during 2016. Research Link scholarships, created to foster research collaboration between Swedish researchers and partners in developing countries, were granted to 5 global research groups IMBER, UGEC, IHOPE, EcoHEALTH and the Earth System Governance Project. The North-South Travel Grant fund, grounded to fund GEC-research collaboration and for researchers from the global south to participate, received under 2016 5 applications and three of them were granted for travel support to Uppsala/SWEDESD and researchers from 6 African countries; Uppsala University/Center for Biology Diversity with researchers from Bolivia; and Lund university/Center for Sustainability Studies and researchers from Uganda, Tanzania and Kenya.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="54100168" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1140102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0.0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <title>Research cooperation 2015-2022</title>
    <titleSV>Forskningssamarbete 2015-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
