<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5404012201-GGG-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association Prevention of Torture 2011-2016</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Association Prevention of Torture 2011-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core funding to the Association for the prevention of Torture (APT).  The organisation is working against torture and builds global         capacity for torture prevention.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Verksamhetsst&#xF6;d till Association for the prevention of Torture (APT.   Organisationen arbetar mot torty och bygga global kapacitet f&#xF6;r att  f&#xF6;rhindra anv&#xE4;ndandet av tortyr.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">APT/Association for the Prevention of Torture</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">385255.5014485607</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">369336.2289293681</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">460603.0829699687</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">364436.7993702532</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">296584.5325234599</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">350610.6468766435</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">385255.5014485607</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">369336.2289293681</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">460603.0829699687</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">364436.7993702532</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">296584.5325234599</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">350610.6468766436</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-07-01">2465635.20927</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-07-28">385255.5014485607</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-04-28">369336.2289293681</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-05-28">460603.0829699687</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-08-28">364436.7993702532</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-28">296584.5325234599</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-28">350610.6468766435</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: The Association for the Prevention of Torture (APT) has played a vital role in the global work  against all forms of torture during many years. During the agreement period 2011-2016, the  APT has continued be crucial in the process of enhancing the global prevention of torture,  through advocating for ratification of the OPCAT (Optional Protocol to the UN Convention  against Torture), providing support to the ratification processes and supporting the designation and effectiveness of NPMs (National Prevention Mechanisms). APT&amp;apos;s strategy to fulfil its commitment to the elimination of torture have included the empowering of partners through a combination of advocacy, national debates, support and advice, capacity strengthening workshops and development of practical tools. The strategy has proven to be effective and sustainable. NPMs are becoming a reference for torture prevention in the institutional landscape and together with the Subcommittee on Prevention of Torture (SPT), APT has formed a system that has contributed to an improved protection of the rights and dignity of all person deprived of liberty.    In 2016, which was the final year of the agreement, the APT has continued to deliver toward  the overall goal to enhance the global prevention of torture. Since the initiation of the agreement, the APT has had three different, consecutive, strategic plans. To clarify the progress made, the APT has in their Completion Report gathered and re-clustered results according to their main  orientations for the whole contribution period instead of reporting against the results framework provided at the time of application or the key objectives identified in the Sida appraisal process which was based on the strategic plan for 2011-2012. Reporting against main orientations is assessed by both Sida and APT to provide the clearest picture of the achievements. The three main strategies, i) strengthening the legal and policy frameworks, ii) improving capacities and practices of torture prevention actors and iii) strengthening monitoring and transparency, has remained closely aligned throughout the three strategic plans. Thus, achievements within the three orientation areas will be presented below.    1. Strengthen legal and policy frameworks, including through increasing adherence to a  culture prevention  By 2016, 83 States had ratified or acceded to the OPCAT and 64 of them had developed a  National Preventive Mechanism (NPM). Since the beginning of the agreement period  between Sida and the APT in 2011, 27 states have ratified the OPCAT. The APT was  engaged and influential in 13 OPCAT ratification processes, of which it had decisive  contribution into 6 processes (Ghana, Mauritania, Mongolia, Morocco, Panama and Tunisia).  2016 marked the ten years anniversary of the Optional Protocol to the UN Convention  against Torture (OPCAT), and APT organised a campaign to further promote the ratification  and effective implementation of the treaty. Many NPMs also took the opportunity to organise  events and other activities to raise awareness about the treaty and their work.  During 2016, the APT supported the initiation of 4 NPMs in the Middle East and North  Africa (Lebanon, Mauretania, Morocco and Tunisia). Not yet fully operational, it is still a  positive step towards functional NPMs in the region. During the agreement period, the  number of designated NPMs has increased from 32 to 65. The APT has been engaged and  had impact on 12 NPM designation processes, with a certain crucial role in Argentina, Brazil,  Mauritania, Panama and Tunisia. In the same period, through ongoing expert advice and  written submissions, the APT has contributed to the drafting of 8 anti-torture legislations in  Uganda (2012), Maldives (2013), South Africa (2013), Chile (2016), Mexico (2017), Thailand  and Indonesia (process still ongoing). In 2015, the advocacy efforts by APT also resulted in  that the issue of torture prevention was included in the EU Human rights guidelines.  APT has also collaborated with the regional networks of NHRIs in Africa and in Asia-Pacific  to utilise and strengthen their role as powerful actors of change through two multi-year  projects, involving approximately 50 NHRIs in the two regions. The cooperation has  contributed to raise the issue of torture prevention on their agendas, and in 2015 both  network&#x2019;s biennial conferences focused on torture prevention. The APT has also played a key  role as facilitator to increase cooperation between SPT, NPMs and State parties.  In 2016, the results from an independent academic research project that the APT commissioned in 2011 was published. The aim was to assess the effectiveness of torture  prevention measures between 1984-2014. The study shows that investigating and prosecuting  torturers, as well as having independent monitoring of places of detention, make important  contributions to preventing torture and that the risk of torture falls substantially when preventive mechanisms are in place, especially when proper detention safeguards are practiced. Since the study was presented, references to the research and the results has been made by NPMs, academics and international bodies (e.g. statement of CAT Chair at the 2016 UN General Assembly).    2. Improve capacities and practices of torture prevention actors  Through the support from the APT, NPMs have been empowered to be key drivers of change  on torture prevention. Between 2011-2016, the APT has contributed to capacity building on  torture prevention in approximately 20 countries, including detention monitoring, strategic  planning, and follow-up of recommendations to state authorities. In 2016 a particular priority  has been to raise awareness about the risks faced by persons with mental disabilities and of  LGBTI people in detention. During the year, the APT organised a symposium for NPMs  which focused on exchanging experiences and challenges when monitoring psychiatric  institutions and gathered representatives of NPMs from all regions and experts from diverse  backgrounds.    To improve the capacities and practices of torture prevention actors, the APT has also  developed practical tools during the contribution. The Guide on Anti-torture Legislation  developed in 2016 intends to assist lawmakers in drafting specific legislation or in revising  existing domestic laws. In addition, guides on monitoring police- and immigration detention  has been developed to be used as reference tools, and the number of downloads from APT&#x2019;s  website shows that they are regularly used. In 2016, the APT launched the database &#x201C;Detention  Focus&#x201D;, which offers information on existing standards international and regional standards as  well as general information on prison issues and groups in situations of vulnerability. The  database also provides practical information to be used in the monitoring process. The database has since the launch had 20-40 visitors per day. During the contribution period, the APT also trained hundreds of people, including judges, parliamentarians, police officers and staff in regional or international organisations on detention monitoring and other key aspects of torture prevention.    3. Strengthen monitoring and transparency, including through NPM effectiveness  Through the OCPAT system, the APT has contributed to make an increased number of  NPMs operational and effective. Examples of positive development is in Senegal, Tunisia and  Mauretania, where implementation of the NPMs preventive mandate has been initiated and  strengthened during the last few years. Although, in Africa, the region with the largest number  of OPCAT states parties after Europe and Central Asia, enforcement is still very limited.    The level of implementation of NPM and SPT recommendations by states have been slow,  but has regularly been increasing. Also the quality of the recommendations made by NPMs and LPMs has been slower than anticipated, but is gradually improving.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="54040122" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
