<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6105005701-GGG-41010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SwedBio extension 2014-2015</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">SwedBio f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngning 2014-2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">SwedBio-programmet genomf&#xF6;rs av Stockholm Resilience Centre och ska   fr&#xE4;mja h&#xE5;llbar och demokratisk f&#xF6;rvaltning av ekosystem och d&#xE4;rigenom bidra till fattigdomsminskning och m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter. SwedBio     arbetar med policy- och metodutveckling, utbildning och kommunikation och st&#xF6;djer och samverkar med partnerorganisationer i Syd som &#xE4;r      verksamma inom samma omr&#xE5;den.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SwedBio/ The Resilience and Development Programme at Stockholm        Resilience Centre works for sustainable management and democratic     governance of ecosystems in order to support poverty reduction and    fullfillment  of human rights.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stockholms universitet</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University, college or other teaching institution, research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2973804.2828612663</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2360812.87888674</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2973804.2828612663</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2360812.87888674</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">-10228.4812715479</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">5874721.205848</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-03-28">2040846.0764734182</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-11-28">932958.2063878482</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-28">1660873.3821313751</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-28">699939.4967553653</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-28">-10228.4812715479</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: International policy and methods development: Swedbio has been able to directly influence a range of international policy- and methods development processes related to biodiversity and ecosystem services for poverty alleviation. These include among others the UN process of developing the SDGs, UNFCCC, the Convention on biological deversity (CBD), the Intergovernmental science-policy platform on biodiversity and ecosystem services (IPBES).  Through the Collaborative programme, SwedBio&amp;apos;s partner organisations can apply for grants but also carry out activities together with SwedBio. The supported programmes have contributed to advancing the understanding, management and governance of social-ecological systems with specific focus on biodiversity and ecosystems as a base for poverty reduction.  The final report provides extensive accounts on the activities, processes and their effects through summaries and &amp;quot;storylines&amp;quot;. The material is very rich and reading of the report itself is recommended for more comprehensive insights. Storyline 7. on the Quito dialogue tells the story about how a seminar dedicated to a specific issue in the CBD negotiations managed resolve a point of conflict where negotiations got stuck. This was a major achievement in itself, but also the &amp;quot;birth&amp;quot; of a successful concept for tailor-made dialogue seminars, further developed by SwedBio and its partners during the programme period.   There are 19 &amp;quot;Story lines&amp;quot; on the following subjects: 1. SwedBio and Agenda 2030 2. The Convention on Biological Diversity &#x2013; the Conferences of the Parties and outcomes related to SwedBio&amp;apos;s performance 3. Collective action in biodiversity conservation 4. High-Level Panel on Global Assessment of Resources for Implementing the Strategic Plan for Biodiversity 2011-2020 5. Biodiversity for poverty eradication and sustainable development 6. Biodiversity financing and safeguards: lessons learned and voluntary guidelines adopted at COP12 in South Korea 7. The Quito Dialogue - A multi-actor dialogue on scaling up biodiversity finance 8. The Multiple Evidence Base approach 9. Resilience Dialogues in Mexico and Ethiopia 10. SEARICE work with Farmers in Mainstreaming Participatory Plant Breeding and On-Farm Agricultural Biodiversity Conservation 11. Urban Natural Assets for Africa 12. Customary Sustainable Use 13. Developing indicators: links between ecosystem services and human wellbeing, and traditional knowledge 14. Community Based Monitoring and Information Systems (CBMIS) &#x2013; a tool for community governance, monitoring of biodiversity indicators and assertion of rights to resources at multiple scales 15. SwedBio e-learning on Resilience Assessment and SRC Massive Open Online Course (MOOC) on the Planetary Boundaries 16. System audits of collaborative partners&#x2019; administrative routines and internal control 17. Gender in SwedBio collaborative programme and policy work 18. Indigenous peoples and climate change: Conference contributing to COP21 in Paris 19: Communities Self-Assessing Resilience  EXAMPLE OF STORYLINE (final report p 82) &amp;quot;Storyline indicator 14. Community Based Monitoring and Information Systems (CBMIS) &#x2013; a tool for community governance, monitoring of biodiversity indicators and assertion of rights to resources at multiple scales:  Community-Based Monitoring and Information Systems (CBMIS) refers to the bundle of monitoring approaches related to biodiversity, ecosystems and other resources, as well as human well-being, used by indigenous peoples and local communities as tools for management and documentation of their resources. Some CBMIS tools have been continuously used and developed as part of indigenous governance and management systems over a long time, whereas others have been included in response to emerging needs in recent times, in particular to document external threats, to assert claims to territory, and to plan for the future. Several of SwedBio&#x2019;s partners among Indigenous peoples and local communities are developing and practicing monitoring tools. For example, ABN uses ecocultural mapping and ecocultural calendars as their method, and FPP partners are mapping their territories with GPS as a base for land recognition. As a result of the increasing demand for global monitoring, such as for the Aichi Biodiversity targets and their indicators, and the REDD+ safeguards, a rising interest has emerged among Indigenous organizations, working from local to global scale, to systematize the monitoring and search for opportunities to scaling up data from local monitoring to globally meaningful aggregations, that can support their rights to resources, locally for legal claims, but also at national level, and in support for their international policy objectives.  This is how the concept of Community Based Monitoring and Information Systems (CBMIS) was born. Tebtebba Foundation and Forest Peoples Programme, as leading the IIFB working group on Indicators, have been developing these methods together with communities. Besides piloting their methods for the CBD, Tebtebba has also been coordinating a global programme on Indigenous peoples and REDD+ (supported by NORAD) and leading in systematizing Indigenous peoples&amp;apos; monitoring methods under the umbrella of CBMIS. The work of these organizations through the IIFB working group on Indicators contributed substantially to the indicators for traditional knowledge for the Aichi target 18. (See storyline 13.) During 2013, a series of workshops and side events was held and involved SwedBio partners FPP, ABN and IIFB. SwedBio was invited as co-convener and part of the Planning and Strategy Group for the Global workshop on CBMIS that was held in two steps. The conveners group consisted of Tebtebba, FPP, Indigenous Peoples&#x2019; Partnership on Climate Change and Forests, International IIFB Working Group on Indicators; Customary Sustainable Use and Rights on Protected Areas (10c) Partners, SwedBio and the SCBD. The sponsors of the event were NORAD, Climate Land Use Alliance, Tamalpis Foundation, EED (Evangelischer Entwicklungsdienst, now Brot fur die Welt) and Rights and Resources Group. The role of CBMIS as a strategically important tool for monitoring was re-confirmed at the CBD WG 8(j) 8 meeting, and one year later, at the COP12, Parties to the CBD warmly welcomed the CBMIS initiatives and contributions, and it was acknowledged that CBMIS can fill the gap of information that is caused by difficulties among international agencies such as FAO, UNESCO and ILO to produce global statistics on issues like traditional occupations or changes in land use. CBD requested data to include bottom-up monitoring from Indigenous peoples and local communities in Global Biodiversity Outlook 4 and FPP, with support from SwedBio, compiled selected cases documented from IIFB members. This work has been much appreciated, and a &#x201C;Local Biodiversity Outlook&#x201D;, with many more cases covering all aspects of the Aichi 2020 targets, was launched as a draft in November 2015 at SBSTTA19. However, CBMIS will in essence remain an important tool for communities in their governance planning, and assertion of their rights to resources, also when data can be made available on scales beyond local; thus it remains useful for all actors involved.  Conclusions, in summary: At local level, CBMIS brings the community together and provides a basis for self-determined development planning and decision making. In addition, it can contribute to better decision making by government. At national level, the contributions of CBMIS to national information systems can make indigenous peoples and their issues more visible to policy makers, and lead to better policies and decisions regarding biodiversity governance and management. Participating in national and local data generation encourages communication between indigenous peoples and researchers, creating opportunities for learning on both sides. The challenge is to develop simple frameworks and toolkits that serve the community&#x2019;s information needs, but can also feed into national and global processes. The frameworks must address the needs, not only of strong communities, but also those of communities under threat: those suffering human rights violations, in remote areas, with fewer links to sources of support.&amp;quot;</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="61050057" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
