<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6105016401-GGG-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PMNCH 2016-2018 Partnership for Maternal, Newborn,Child and Adolescent Health</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">PMNCH 2016-2018 Partnership for Maternal, Newborn,Child and Adolescent Health</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PMNCH is a global partnership for promotion, alignment and harmonisation of global support for women, children and adolescents   and is linked to the Secretary Generals new Global Strategy for       Maternal, Child and Adolescent health. Sweden sits on the Board       during 2015 and 2016. The PMNCH strategy stretches from 2016 to 2020  but Sida&apos;s support until 2018 only.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Partnerskapet f&#xF6;r m&#xF6;dra- nyf&#xF6;dd- och barnh&#xE4;lsa, PMNCH (ibland endast Partnerskapet) &#xE4;r ett omfattande internationellt partnerskap som syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra m&#xF6;dra- barn och ungdomsh&#xE4;lsan i v&#xE4;rlden. PMNCH skapades 2005 i syfte att &#xF6;ka f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningarna f&#xF6;r v&#xE4;rldens fattiga l&#xE4;nder att uppn&#xE5; millenniem&#xE5;len 4 och 5 i en tid d&#xE5; resurser och politiskt engagemang f&#xF6;r m&#xF6;dra- barn och ungdomsh&#xE4;lsa inte stod h&#xF6;gst p&#xE5; den globala dagsordningen. Idag omfattar partnerskapet &#xF6;ver 700 medlemmar som representerar utvecklingsl&#xE4;nder, givare, multilateraler, akademiska institutioner, privata akt&#xF6;rer, civilsamh&#xE4;llsorganisationer samt yrkesprofessionella organ. PMNCH har ett mindre sekretariat som huserar hos WHO i G&#xE9;n&#xE8;ve. F&#xF6;rutom att st&#xE4;rka partnerskapet kring huvudfr&#xE5;gorna &#xE4;r sekretariatets uppgift att samordna arbetet i partnerskapet med ett fokus p&#xE5; ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande, p&#xE5;verkansarbete och ett &#xF6;kat landengagemang. Kopplingen till FN:s globala strategi f&#xF6;r kvinnors, barns och ungdomars h&#xE4;lsa 2016-2030 &#xE4;r institutionaliserad genom att PMNCH f&#xE5;tt ett s&#xE4;rskilt ansvar fr&#xE5;n FN:s generalsekreterare att f&#xF6;lja upp genomf&#xF6;randet av den globala strategin och arbeta fram indikatorer f&#xF6;r detta &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;l. En sj&#xE4;lvst&#xE4;ndig panel, Independent Accountability Panel, har tillsatts som &#xE5;rligen rapporterar p&#xE5; efterlevnad av l&#xE4;nders &#xE5;taganden och m&#xE5;luppf&#xF6;ljning. Sida sitter i PMNCHs styrelse sedan 2015 och driver s&#xE4;rskilt fr&#xE5;gan om ett ut&#xF6;kat fokus kring SRHR inklusive r&#xE4;tten till s&#xE4;kra aborter. Sida och Sveriges roll i partnerskapet &#xE4;r central med anledning av Sveriges starka engagmang och h&#xF6;ga finansiering av SRHR globalt.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention has four strategic objectives with four clear high level strategic results to be achieved by 2020:1) Multistakeholder platforms and processes align all stakeholders and most affected communities in on-going inclusive dialogue and planning to shape priorities, policy, financing; programme decision-making in countries and places with the highest burden and need.2) Unified, independent and mutual accountability processes and platforms hold all partners to account for results resources and rights, building accountability by duty bearers to rights holders, and driving advocacy and action for impact.3) Programmes, policies and financing deliver health and well-being outcomes for women, newborns, children and adolescents, especially the marginalized, excluded and those lagging behind, sustaining their needs and rights at the centre of the development agenda. 4) Collective action to drive effective policies, programmes, financing and accountability draws on the strenghtened balance and inclusive engagement of diverse and committed partners.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="4" type="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WHO/World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">292175.5390638696</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">292500.2925002925</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">292175.5390638696</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">292500.2925002925</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">584351.078127</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-28">292175.5390638696</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-28">292500.2925002925</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida has supported PMNCH&apos;s strategic plan (2016 - 2020) through the business plan (2016 - 2018) with a total of 9 750 000 MSEK during the period 20160101 - 20190630. The financial support started initially in 2010 and has since then been renewed twice (2013 - 2015 and 2016 - 2019). Sweden had a seat on the Board 2010 - 2012 and then became an alternate in 2013 until returning to the Board in 2015 - 2018. During the period 2019-2020 Sweden is alternate to Canada. The Swedish Ambassador for Global Health is the Chairperson for the Strategy and Finance Committee for the same period, so he will in this capacity remain in the Board. In the Board, MFA holds the seat (through the Amb. for Global Health) and Sida support and manage the grant. The joint work has focused on advocating for strategic investment in SRMNACH; good governance, alignment and harmonisation of the global (SRMNACH) health architecture; as well as keeping an extra focus on the work pillar of SRHR (in which Sida has been very active). Sida considers PMNCH to be a strategic partner as it has the potential capacity to deliver on the broad SRMNCAH agenda and bring together a variety of partners. The Partnership also provides a good opportunity to inform and discuss the global discourse on SRMNACH and the global initiatives such as the Global Strategy 2.0, the Global financing facility (GFF), SDG3 action plan, UHC, etc.&#xA0; The achievements over the period include facilitating consultations and helping to secure global agreements of 192 UN Members States (e.g. the SDGs; the Every Newborn Action Plan), tracking the progress of US$ 45 billion of commitments from over 650 partners to the Every Woman Every Child Global Strategy (EWEC) thus promoting accountability. The partnership has been able to provide significant visibility for the SRMNCAH and has succeeded in bringing key stakeholder and partners across the continuum of care together, around a common agenda. The Partnership provides access to knowledge and information as well as a platform for discussion and sharing of information, being an added value. Further, PMNCH has played a significant role in political advocacy. Achievements&#xA0;in 2018 included among others; the Partnership&apos; successful Partners&apos; Forum attended by 1600 participants from 85 countries. 19 commitments were made during the Forum, led by Indian Prime Minister, Mr. Modi, who announced a USD 7 billion for WCAH in India by 2025. During the Forum, the BMJ launched its special series on multisectoral work coordinated by PMNCH, who had developed 12 country case studies selected from over 300 responses to its global call for proposals. Main findings from the evaluation of the Partners&apos;s Forum are summarised below: &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;  Under its work on SRHR, the PMNCH intensified its role in the global promotion of SRHR for ex. was an active member of the Guttmacher - Lancet Commission on SRHR and issued a call for action on SRHR in UHC. PMNCH launched a global consensus statement on Meaningful Adolescent and Youth Engagement, which over 170 organisations have endorsed. A Nurturing Care Framework for Early Childhood Development was developed and launched at the World Health Assembly in 2018. PMNCH established a working group on Humanitarian and Fragile Settings, which is currently conducting an in-depth mapping and analysis to better understand gaps and duplications to identify how PMNCH could address these challenges. PMNCH also tracked progress in the implementation on the Global Strategy and released three reports during the year: commitments to the Global Strategy; commitments in humanitarian and fragile settings and commitments for adolescent health and well-being. Furthermore a joint technical working group for tracking of financial resources were established and developed an improved method of estimating official development assistance for WCAH, &quot;Muskoka 2&quot;. This is to be piloted in 2019. In the first six months of 2019, PMNCH attended WHA 72 in May 2019 in Geneva and WomenDeliver conference in June in Vancouver. During WHA 72, PMNCH co-organized 9 side events, which includes among others launching a call for action to ensure SRHR remains central in universal health coverage; launching a call for action and webpage on Aligning women children and adolescents&#x2019; health in humanitarian and fragile settings; launching a New Knowledge Brief series for the Health and Well-being of women, children and adolescents on the move; and launching a Background paper, Adolescents: the missing population in universal health coverage At Women Deliver 2019, PMNCH organized 40 bilaterals with partners, 14 concurrent sessions /events; facilitated 50 partners speaking in various concurrent sessions/events and disseminated 500 materials in the booth. PMNCH&#x2019;s social media presence during these two events were as follows: &#x2022;206 tweets (increase 1,960%) &#x2022;221 K tweet impressions (increase 935%) &#x2022;5,774 profile visits (increase 430.7%) &#x2022;1,193 mentions (increase 295.0%) &#x2022;23.9 K followers (increase 353 followers) For more discussion on results pls see the recent CoP (March 2019).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="61050164" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
