<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6107014701-GGG-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDA (2020-2023)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IDA (2020-2023)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDA&apos;s overall objective and long term goal that the intervention aims to contribute to is that &quot;The rights of persons with disabilities are advanced by Member States, the UN and international cooperation stakeholders across human rights, development, peace and security agendas, in partnership with and through meaningful engagement of Organisations of Persons with Disabilities technically equipped to frame, deliver and monitor policies and programmes that affect their lives.&quot;
The purpose of the intervention is to ensure that &#x201C;Capacities and commitments of Member States, the UN and international cooperation stakeholders are strengthened, and their investment in and meaningful engagement with Organizations of Persons with Disabilities (OPDs) is increased, resulting in higher OPDs capacities to represent the diversity of persons with disabilities, to technically advise as well as hold all stakeholders accountable on the realization of the rights of persons with disabilities&#x201D;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen avser ett k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till organisationen International Disability Alliance (IDA) om totalt 44 MSEK under en fyra&#xE5;rsperiod 2020-2023. IDA &#xE4;r en global allians av organisationer av personer med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning (OPDs) som uppskattningsvis representerar en miljard m&#xE4;nniskor v&#xE4;rlden &#xF6;ver som lever med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning. IDAs &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att arbeta f&#xF6;r att skydda och fr&#xE4;mja m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter f&#xF6;r personer med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning (PwD) samt st&#xE4;rka genomf&#xF6;randet av konventionen om r&#xE4;ttigheter f&#xF6;r personer med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning (CRPD). 

F&#xF6;r 2020-2023 har IDA utvecklat sin strategi med fokus p&#xE5; sex omr&#xE5;den med f&#xF6;ljande m&#xE5;l:
1) P&#xE5;verka FNs processer f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter samt ansvarstagare f&#xF6;r effektiv implementering av CRPD.
2) P&#xE5;verka h&#xE5;llbarhetsagendan och det humanit&#xE4;ra arbetet f&#xF6;r att inkludera behov och prioriteringar av PwD. 
3) P&#xE5;verka internationellt utvecklingssamarbete f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka kapacitet och resurser f&#xF6;r r&#xE4;ttigheter f&#xF6;r PwD. 
4) Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttigheter f&#xF6;r underrepresenterade grupper av PwD. 
5) Bygga kapacitet f&#xF6;r aktivister med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning och OPDs f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka m&#xE5;ngfalden inom den globala r&#xF6;relsen f&#xF6;r PwD. 
6) &#xD6;ka den kollektiva kapaciteten av den globala r&#xF6;relsen f&#xF6;r PwD.

Total budget f&#xF6;r perioden &#xE4;r cirka 450 MSEK. Sidas st&#xF6;d uppg&#xE5;r till 44 MSEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The International Disability Alliance (IDA) is a global alliance of organizations of persons with disabilities, representing the voice of the estimated one billion persons with disabilities worldwide. The overall goal of IDA is to develop and strengthen its work to promote the implementation of the Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities (CRPD) through the enabling of political dialogue, the creation of cooperation and capacity development at national, regional and global levels.

IDAs strategic plan for 2020-2023 has six objectives with the following corresponding goals: 
1) Influencing UN human rights standards and processes. This entails that OPDs are able to utilise and engage in human rights monitoring mechanisms and processes to hold their governments accountable for effective CRPD implementation.
2) Influencing sustainable development and humanitarian action frameworks. This entails that the priorities of PwD are included in the review of the SDGs and that increased evidence on this progress is available, in addition to ensuring that the needs and priorities of PwD&apos;s are addressed and included in humanitarian responses.
3) Influencing international cooperation stakeholders. This entails that relevant stakeholders have increased their political will, technical capacity and resourcing towards disability inclusive development, in addition to IDA and its constituencies having continued engagement and influence over relevant Agenda 2030 processes and mechanisms.
4) Promoting the rights of underrepresented groups of persons with disabilities. This entails continued diversity of PwD represented in the governance and work of IDA, including underrepresented groups e.g. psychosocial disabilities and persons with deafblindness, in addition to increased representation, leadership and advocacy of women and indigenous persons with disabilities.
5) Building technical capacities of disability activists that form the diversity of the disability rights movement. This entails the continuation and scaling up of the Bridge CRPD-SDG training initiative as a cornerstone of a wider capacity development strategy and investment in the technical and advocacy capacity, as well as diversity of the movement. Additionally, IDA will work towards developing advanced training resources to support OPDs and PwDs in their advocacy towards governments, UN actors, donors and other relevant stakeholders.
6) Growing the collective capacity of the disability rights movement. This focuses on the importance of expanding the movement with a bottom-up approach, in addition to strengthening the range and diversity of PwD that IDA represents.

The total budget for the four-year period is around 450 MSEK. Sidas contribution for this period amounts to 44 MSEK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDA/International Disability Alliance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDA/International Disability Alliance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.2 - By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.2 - Till 2030 m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra och verka f&#xF6;r att alla m&#xE4;nniskors, oavsett &#xE5;lder, k&#xF6;n, funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, ras, etnicitet, ursprung, religion eller ekonomisk eller annan st&#xE4;llning, blir inkluderade i det sociala, ekonomiska och politiska livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.3 - Ensure equal opportunity and reduce inequalities of outcome, including by eliminating discriminatory laws, policies and practices and promoting appropriate legislation, policies and action in this regard.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.3 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika m&#xF6;jligheter och minska f&#xF6;rekomsten av oj&#xE4;mlika utfall, bland annat genom att avskaffa diskriminerande lagstiftning, politik och praxis och fr&#xE4;mja lagstiftning, politik och &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder av l&#xE4;mpligt slag i detta h&#xE4;nseende.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">868649.358828192</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1165922.419522205</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">932737.935617764</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">2098660.355139969</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">868649.3588281919</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1165922.419522205</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">816145.6936655435</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">2098660.355139969</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">4777571.473555</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-28">868649.358828192</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-28">453288.0178152946</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-28">712634.4017069105</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-28">233184.483904441</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61070147_61070147_021246-20GrantAgreementbetweenSidaandInternationalDisabilityAlliance(IDA),2020-2709579_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant agreement between Sida and IDA</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61070147_61070147_019020-20Beslutominsats,InternationalDisabilityAllianceIDA,2020-2023,(62070147)2698349_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The  coronapandemic has of course impacted the work of IDA during the reporting period. The pandemic demanded  adaptation of IDA activities as well as immediate response and re-prioritization of its advocacy work.  IDA initiated, at the start of the pandemic, a working group with its membership and partners to deliver on the advocacy required with a focus on health-care and specifically anti-discrimination in the provision of emergency health care. Also access to education has became an prioritized topic for IDA.

IDAs response was initially addressed towards WHO and the larger UN system, which then transformed to production of recommendations and formulation of a resource webpage. The response also included collection of data and formulation of a global service to monitor the impact of COVID-19 on persons with disabilities. Finally, this also led to adaptations of ways of working and priority activities to the long-lasting impact of the crisis, preparing for the second wave of the pandemic and post-crisis resumption of activities.

Advancements towards the objective of IDA has been achieved this year, both in the sense of advancement in the core advocacy objectives of IDA and strengthening the capacities of IDA secretariat and its members. IDA continued to engage with the human rights agenda by securing inclusion of the perspectives of OPDs (Organizations of persons with disability) in the CRPD in the Human Rights Council; successfully campaigning for diversity of the CRPD committee; strengthening the partnership with WHO, UNHCR and other UN agencies, and advocating the Third Committee of the UN General Assembly.  IDAs advocacy work resulted in that a Human Rights Council resolutions included relevant references to persons with disabilities while the Third Committee requested the UN to include persons with disabilities in COVID-19 response.

IDA, with its partners managed to organize a briefing between the UN Security Council and persons with disabilities from Yemen, the first one since the adoption of resolution 2475. This is an important milestone to ensure the long-lasting commitment of the UNSC to the protection of the rights persons with disabilities in conflict.

IDA collectively with its members produced two national and three regional reports on the SDGs from the CRPD perspectives, a historical Global Report on Inclusive Education, as well as report of the first IDA Global Survey on OPD participation in development policies and programs.  It took several decades to the disability rights movement to agree on the position on inclusive education a  collective achievement of the movement. Similarly, the results of the first Global Survey on OPD participation will define a new form of advocacy and accountability of OPDs towards governments and other stakeholders.

IDA, being a standing co-chair of GLAD, supported this network to deliver during the coronapandemic. It organized meetings of the network, produced a call to action  A Call to Rebuild a Future Inclusive of All which is endorsed by 202 organizations, as well as held a High-Level Roundtable on disability and COVID-19 with presence of four ministers, UN Deputy Secretary-General, WHO Assistant Director General and others. Sida participate in GLAD working groups on; gender (Social), education (Tema) and steering committee (Tema).

During the year, IDA developed new partnerships and signed several memorandums of understanding with the International Paralympic Committee, the Valuable 500, and UN High Commissioner for Refugees, as well as explored collaboration with numerous organizations active in health and food security sectors. IDA is making a conscious attempt to broaden its partnerships outside of the scope of the UN and other multilateral organisations. Partnering with private sector and alos increase the focus on the general public is a shift in IDAs operations. 

During the reporting period IDA also saw a incresed investment in recruitment in the IDA secretariat, especially in the areas of  Advocacy, Capacity Building and Program Units.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="61070147" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1070103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0.0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <title>Human rights, democracy and the rule of law 2018-2022</title>
    <titleSV>M&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, demokrati och r&#xE4;ttsstatens principer 2018-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
