<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6105008801-GGG-33113</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Standards and Trade Development Facility 2015-2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Standards and Trade Development Facility 2015-2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">STDF bildades 2001 och &#xE4;r ett partnerskap mellan FAO, OIE, WHO, WTO samt V&#xE4;rldsbanken d&#xE4;r sekretariatet och programmet hanteras och administreras av WTO. Syftet &#xE4;r att st&#xE4;rka utvecklingsl&#xE4;nders uppbyggnad av kapacitet inom SPS-relaterade fr&#xE5;gor (sanitary and phytosanitary). St&#xF6;det &#xE4;r i huvudsak avsett att st&#xE4;rka och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra l&#xE4;nders exportm&#xF6;jligheter och marknadstilltr&#xE4;den inom handel med livsmedel och jordbruksprodukter f&#xF6;r att p&#xE5; sikt bidra till fattigdomsminskning, tryggad livsmedelsf&#xF6;rs&#xF6;rjning samt st&#xE4;rkt milj&#xF6;skydd och biologisk m&#xE5;ngfald. STDF har genom sammans&#xE4;ttningen av medlemsorganisationer samt deltagande experter och intressenter en unik position och kompetensbas vad g&#xE4;ller SPS-omr&#xE5;det. N&#xE5;gon motsvarighet att genomf&#xF6;ra ett liknande uppdrag finns inte.

STDF fyller tv&#xE5; huvudsakliga funktioner. Dels att samordna och sprida kunskap kring SPS-fr&#xE5;gor och goda erfarenheter av kapacitetsutveckling inom omr&#xE5;det samt att finansiera och st&#xF6;dja utvecklandet av projekt eller projektf&#xF6;rberedande analyser f&#xF6;r SPS-fr&#xE5;gor.

Sedan starten har tre oberoende externa utv&#xE4;rderingar genomf&#xF6;rts (den senaste avslutad i januari 2014). Slutsatsen i samtliga dessa visar p&#xE5;  att STDF genom sitt uppdrag n&#xE5;r goda resultat p&#xE5; ett kostnadseffektivt s&#xE4;tt. 

Sverige har via Sida finansierat STDF sedan 2005. STDFsekretariatet har nu till Sida inkommit med en beg&#xE4;ran om st&#xF6;d p&#xE5; 40 MSEK &#xF6;ver fyra &#xE5;r. Det inneb&#xE4;r en viss &#xF6;kning av det svenska st&#xF6;det. Totala budgeten f&#xF6;r STDF &#xE4;r ungef&#xE4;r 5 MUSD/&#xE5;r fr&#xE5;n 8-10 givare. Andra st&#xF6;rre givare &#xE4;r Finland, Danmark, EU och Nederl&#xE4;nderna.En del av st&#xF6;det ska anv&#xE4;ndas f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka sekretariatets arbetet med kommunikation och resultatstyrning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Standards and Trade Development Facility (STDF) is a joint        initiative in capacity building and technical cooperation aiming at   raising awareness on the importance of sanitary and phytosanitary     (SPS) issues, increasing coordination in the provision of SPS-related assistance, and mobilizing resources to assist developing countries   enhance their capacity to meet SPS standards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">The Standards and Trade Development Facility is a global partnership that helps developing countries to gain and maintain access to markets by tackling sanitary and phytosanitary (SPS) gaps, and promoting food safety, animal and plant health. It works to support sustainable economic growth, poverty reduction, food security and environmental protection. STDF objective is to be&#xA0;be a knowledge hub, sharing available know-how, tools and good practice to build on what exists and&#xA0;create synergies and promote innovative and cross-cutting approaches in SPS capacity building.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="45001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WTO/World Trade Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="45001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WTO/World Trade Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Policies &amp; Regulations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2372676.260187679</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.17000117</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2372676.260187679</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.1700011694</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-01">3559014.390281</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-28">1170001.17000117</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sida has supported the STDF in implementing its SPS strategy for the period 2015-2019. The total amount of Swedish support&#xA0; during that period amounted to 50 MSEK.&#xA0; The agreement with the WTO in support of the STDF exprired in June 2019.&#xA0; &#xA0;The STDF has supported capacity development in a number of countries as well as contributing to global knowledge. The STDF has also supported a number of regional programmes, in Africa, Asia and Latin America. The&#xA0; summary of results given below covers the period of the agreement between Sida and the WTO.
The STDF has delivered inclusive, safe trade solutions in key SPS areas through 97 projects since 2004, most of them in the poorest countries. Across Africa, Asia-Pacific and Latin America and the Caribbean the STDF has helped to set up partnerships across the public and private sector, connecting government agencies to small businesses. It has championed the latest technical know-how on SPS solutions, and built up people&#x2019;s skills across agricultural value chains, facilitating safe trade to regional and international markets, that generates benefits for people in developing countries. Promoting women&#x2019;s access to, and participation in, agriculture and trade can support economic growth, reduce poverty and boost food security in developing countries. Women play a vital role in agriculture, food production and agricultural trade in developing countries. Yet, women face more challenges when it comes to benefitting from agricultural production and trade. They are less able to access agricultural inputs, services and markets, face higher transaction costs crossing borders as informal traders, and are less likely to be exporters and importers. Many STDF projects directly target, benefit and empower vulnerable and disadvantaged women involved in diverse agricultural value chains, from shrimp and prawns in Bangladesh, to ginger in Nepal, vegetable production in Nicaragua, cinnamon peeling and processing in Sri Lanka, fruit and vegetables in Thailand and Viet Nam, sesame in Sudan, smoked fish in Mali, and spices in India. Three stories highlighting the results of STDF projects are shared below. Additional stories describing the results of STDF projects are provided in the 2018 STDF Results Book, STDF annual reports and on the STDF website, including short films on STDF&apos;s YouTube channel.
Results from West Africa: women take the lead on standards in artisanal fisheries
The fisheries sector employs over three million people in West Africa, most of them in artisanal fisheries, and fish production and trade have an important impact on food security and poverty reduction. Supporting the sector can promote livelihoods and market opportunities. Under an STDF project in C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire, Guinea, Mauritania, and Senegal, led by UNIDO from 2015-18, small-scale fisheries received support to tackle hygiene and food safety challenges in fishery products. Women sell 80% of fish and seafood in the region, and the project supported women in the countries with skills training on good hygiene practices and sanitation to play a more active role in the sector. More than 400 small businesses learned about food safety requirements, and over 1,000 people were trained to use better practices to dry, smoke and store fish. This helped exports to expand into regional markets. The project also had important environmental benefits, as food safety management systems used less energy, meaning less reliance on scarce wood resources and reduced air pollution. An improved smoking centre in Guinea, for example, meant that small producers had more efficient ovens and enjoyed better working conditions. In C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire, there was less waste as producers used newly-introduced insulation boxes, which need less ice to conserve fish.
Results from Myanmar: food safety promotes oilseed exports and farmers&#x2019; livelihoods
In Myanmar, sesame, mustard and sunflower seeds account for around 20% of production in agriculture, which employs over half of the workforce. As one of the world&#x2019;s largest oilseeds producers, the crop is a vital source of export revenue and income generation for farmers. Under the STDF-funded project, led by ITC with the public and private sector from 2015-2019, actors across the oilseed value chain received targeted training to meet food safety standards. This improved export capacity and competitiveness. From farm to market, in-depth food safety training reached 900 farmers, collectors, and processors, alongside 20 national extension officers. The programme covered how to grow crops, use pesticides, and collect, store and process seeds safely. It shared food safety and quality manuals with over 480 farmers, and tools and guidance for collectors and processors. Close to a quarter of all project activities engaged women across the oilseeds sector, while women made up over half of trainees in technical areas from processors to the government. To date, 150 farmers have obtained national GAP&#xA0; (good agricultural practices) certification and seven processors received internationally recognized HACCP&#xA0; ( hazard analysis critical control points) certification. Select local buyers have also put in place a 2-4% price premium for farmers who adopted GAP with support of the training. The value-chain approach has continued to strengthen links from farmers, collectors, processors and advisers to each other and to final buyers. After a number of companies engaged in the World Export Development Forum and business-to-business meetings in Europe and China, the sector&#x2019;s profile and buyer network is expanding. The reported increase in annual export sales in the oilseeds sector looks set to continue, with an expected impact on revenue generation to follow. The Department of Agriculture has committed to using the project materials in future training. Based on the results achieved, the oilseeds sector was included as a priority sector for the 2019-2023 &#x20AC;8 million EU-funded Arise Plus project in Myanmar, which is being led by ITC.
Results from regional projects in Africa, ASEAN and Latin America: plugging pesticide data gaps to facilitate trade&#xA0;
Pesticides often cause trade concerns for tropical fruits and vegetables from developing countries, as exports face being rejected. Few Maximum Residue Limits (MRLs) exist for these crops and they can differ from Codex standards or for different trading partners. There are gaps in residue data, plus high costs in generating data and registering new pesticides. Three regional STDF projects, implemented from 2012 to 2017, connected public and private sector across Africa, Asia and Latin America to pilot and learn from a collaborative model to expand residue programmes and help to meet Codex standards. This led to coordinated pesticide residue studies, as well as 62 field trials, supporting farmers to use new-generation pesticides, with added benefits for agricultural productivity, the environment and consumer safety. As a result, seven new Codex MRLs were developed by 2019 with three more due by 2022, 13 countries have registered low-risk pesticides, and over 160 scientists and government officers have new expertise on pesticide residue data, supporting more active participation in Codex and other fora. A 2019 independent evaluation found that the projects achieved to a great extent their objectives, and that &#x201C;the STDF contribution had clear value-added&#x201D; and is promoting regional harmonization. The projects played a key role in promoting collaboration across government authorities from agriculture, health, environment and trade, and with the private sector.&#xA0;
Making safe trade inclusive and protecting the environment
Building capacity to meet international standards for food safety, animal and plant health helps farmers, processors, traders and governments in developing countries to access markets for food and agricultural goods, where they can have a comparative advantage. This creates opportunities to add value across supply chains, in turn generating employment, increasing incomes and securing people&#x2019;s livelihoods.
STDF has been suporting both&#xA0; women and men farmers, processors and traders to export safe agricultural and food products to regional and high-value markets. By contributing in&#xA0; improving SPS capacity the STDF contributes in addressing the environment challenges . STDF&apos;s knowledge and project work on cross-cutting issues connects STDF partners as well as different stakeholders from across agriculture, health, trade and development, and the environment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="61050088" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
