<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6105001801-GGG-41010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IUCN 2013-2016</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IUCN 2013-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IUCN&#x2019;s Programme builds on the vision &quot;A just world that values and conserves nature&quot;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Internationella naturv&#xE5;rdsunionen (IUCN) &#xE4;r v&#xE4;rldens ledande,         demokratiskt drivna organisation f&#xF6;r naturv&#xE5;rd och h&#xE5;llbar utveckling med &#xF6;ver 100 medlemsorganisationer. IUCN har observat&#xF6;rstatus i FN.   Sida har gett organisationsst&#xF6;d till IUCN sedan 1991 och denna insats g&#xE4;ller organisationsst&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r perioden 2013-2016.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The International Union for Conservation of the Nature (IUCN) is the  leading global organization for nature conservation and sustainable   development. It has more than a shousand member organizations and has observer status in the UN. Since 1991 Sida has provided core support  to IUCN. This contribution concerns the core support for the period   2013-2016.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="30011" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IUCN/International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="30011" role="4" type="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IUCN/International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">5373702.634649634</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">3644367.9937025323</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">3559014.390281518</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">2921755.390638696</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">5373702.634649634</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">3644367.9937025323</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">3559014.390281518</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">2921755.390638697</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">17656451.513848</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-11-28">5373702.634649634</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-28">1822183.9968512661</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-09-28">1822183.9968512661</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-03-28">1779507.195140759</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-28">1779507.195140759</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-02-28">1753053.2343832175</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-28">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specific examples of relevant IUCN results during 2013-2016. 
- Increased global knowledge: In the autumn of 2016, the IUCN released the world&apos;s most comprehensive research overview so far about how the global warming is directly affecting humans with already significant effects, including impacts on fishery resources and catches, more extreme weather events and increased risk of waterborne diseases. The news gained widespread dissemination in social and traditional media and appears to have changed views on the&#xA0;magnitude of the climate change impacts on the seas.
- Tools and standards: &quot;Key biodiversity areas&quot; is a new international standard developed by IUCN&#xA0;to identify areas of global importance for the conservation of biodiversity, including marine areas. The standard will be tested in 2017-2019. In 2015, IUCN also developed guidelines for evaluation and assessment of the effectiveness of protected areas.
- Work to establish&#xA0;a Natural Resource Governance Framework was&#xA0;initiated during the period as a means to more systematically promote rights-based governance of natural resources. Funding to the project was earmarked within Sida&apos;s core-support. See contribution 61050073, IUCN-NRGF.
- Protected areas: Over the last decade, the total of protected ocean area has increased significantly, from just over 4 million square kilometers in 2006 to nearly 15 million square kilometers 2016 (almost the same as Russia). The IUCN has contributed to this with knowledge and policy impact, including contributions to the establishment of the world&apos;s largest marine reserve of Antarctic the Ross Sea in October 2016.
- Policy impact: Nature-based solutions for disaster risk reduction: The lUCN, in cooperation with other parties, ensured that the Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction 2015-2030 addresses the importance of prosperous ecosystems to protect human life from disasters.
- Method development and implementation: Mangroves For the Future/ Resilient Coasts (MFF) is an initiative that operates in 11 countries in Asia and the Indian Ocean and covers more than 75,000 square kilometers of coast in the member states. In 2015, the MFF strengthened resilience and decisionmaking in local communities through the introduction of Resilience Analysis Protocols (RAP) in the countries and paid $ 825,000 in the form of 170 grants to strengthen resilience.
- Private sector engagement: In recent years, IUCN has established partnerships with large-scale corporations in order to encourage more sustainable practices. Corporations with heavy environmental impact have been targeted. For instance, 46 private sector users (including financial investors such as IFC and ADB) are paying IUCN for the IBAT service (integrated Biodiversity Assessment Tool) which helps them meet international reporting commitments. The IBAT draws upon the Red List of Threatened Species (IUCN&apos;s most well-known and widely used&#xA0;knowledge product).
Results regarding organizational development:
- The IUCN world conservation congress was held in Hawaii in September 2016. More than 10,000 participants from 176 countries attended the event which is IUCN&apos;s highest decision making body and is held every 4 year. The IUCN programme for 2017-2020 was approved, including a lot of reference to the SDGs, and the Hawaii committments were adopted.
-One of the more important decisions of the recent congress was the new category of membership for Indigenous peoples&#x2019; organisations, adding to IUCN&#x2019;s former two categories of NGO and state/government agency members. It is the first time in IUCN&#x2019;s history that a new membership category has been established.
-The new IUCN Programme and Project Portal was launched in 2016 to allow for better management, monitoring and reporting on the project portfolio and its contribution towards results and the SDGs. This is also part of a the long-term process of coordinating and aligning all IUCN projects with the overall framework programme.
- Cross-cutting issues: More than 1,500 staff from member organizations, including environmental-sector ministries and agencies, as well as CSOs, were trained on gender and environment issues, including through processes to mainstream gender into National Biodiversity Strategies and Action Plans (NBSAPs) in Mexico, Brazil and Uganda; in the development of national Climate Change Gender Action Plans (ccGAPs) in Zambia and Dominican Republic; and through Forest Landscape Restoration processes in Brazil and Malawi.
- Facing a steep decline in core-funding in relation to project funding, the IUCN secretariat initiated an organisational change process during 2016 to ensure long-term financial stability and effective program implementation. A participatory analysis among staff guided the process.
- During the period, IUCN&#xA0;became accredited agency for both Global Environmental Fund GEF and the Global Climate Fund GCF. This required further development of standards and routines for cross-cutting issues such as gender equality.
- A series of actions in response to recommendations from the external mid-term review and the external review of IUCN governance were undertaken.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="61050018" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
