<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6107010401-GGG-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWID 2018-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">AWID 2018-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWID is an international feminist member-based organization that aims to create a strong women&apos;s rights movement that is equipped to work effectively and inclusive with women&apos;s rights. AWID&apos;s members work in a global network that, through impact work, capacity building and research and communication work for women&apos;s rights. Sida has provided support to AWID since 2007.

According to AWID&apos;s strategic plan for 2018-2022, the organization aims to create a strong women&apos;s rights movement, fully equipped to work effectively and inclusively for women&apos;s rights. The strategic plan consists of four performance areas that will govern the business over the next five-year period, which are: 1. supporting feminist movements to develop; 2. to curb the forces that oppose universal rights; 3. To create, with other actors, feminist environments, and; 4. To continue to strengthen AWID as an organization to fully equip itself to work effectively and inclusive for women&apos;s rights.

Gender equality is one of Sweden&apos;s strategic priorities, and Sida believes that AWID&apos;s strategic plan for the new five-year period is in line with the objectives of both the Strategy for Sweden&apos;s Development Cooperation on Human Rights, Democracy and the Principles of the Rule of Law (2018-2022) and also the objectives of the strategy for Sweden&apos;s development cooperation for global equality and women&apos;s and girls&apos; rights 2018-2022.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">AWID, Association for Women&apos;s Rights in Development, har ans&#xF6;kt om fortsatt k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r perioden 2018-2022 i enlighet med dess strategiska plan f&#xF6;r 2018-2022.

Sida har gett st&#xF6;d till AWID sedan 2007. AWID &#xE4;r en internationell feministisk medlemsbaserad organisation som har som m&#xE5;l att skapa  en stark kvinnor&#xE4;ttsr&#xF6;relse som &#xE4;r utrustad f&#xF6;r att arbeta effektivt och inkluderande med kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter. AWID&apos;s medlemmar arbetar i ett globalt n&#xE4;tverk som genom p&#xE5;verkansarbete, kapacitetsuppbyggnad samt forskning och kommunikation arbetar f&#xF6;r kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter.

Enligt rapportering och de utv&#xE4;rderingar som har gjorts (Merit Partnership 2017-02-06 och KPMG 2017-11-16) framg&#xE5;r det att AWID &#xE4;r en v&#xE4;l fungerande organisation som lyckats v&#xE4;l med att p&#xE5;verka givare och andra akt&#xF6;rer som bl.a. resulterat i att kvinnoorganisationer och kvinnor&#xF6;relser &#xE4;r b&#xE4;ttre resurssatta nu &#xE4;n tidigare f&#xF6;r sin uppgift att leda och samordna arbetet med att fr&#xE4;mja kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter p&#xE5; olika niv&#xE5;er. 

J&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet &#xE4;r en av Sveriges strategiska prioriteringar och Sida bed&#xF6;mer att AWID&apos;s strategiska plan f&#xF6;r den nya fem&#xE5;rsperioden st&#xE4;mmer v&#xE4;l &#xF6;verens med m&#xE5;len i strategin f&#xF6;r Sveriges utvecklingssamarbete avseende m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, demokrati och r&#xE4;ttsstatens principer (2018-2022) samt med m&#xE5;len i strategin f&#xF6;r Sveriges utvecklingssamarbete f&#xF6;r global j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och kvinnors och flickors r&#xE4;ttigheter 2018&#x2013;2022.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The new plan is the result of a yearlong participatory process that included internal reflection and analysis as well as extensive input from partners, members, and feminist movements. The plan presents AWIDs core outcomes and impacts&#xA0;for 2018-2022.

Outcomes and&#xA0;objectives are found in the Strategic Plan under the heading &quot;What we aim to achieve&quot;. There are three principal strategies (or objectives 1-3)&#xA0;at the centre of AWID&apos;s vision to work for the period 2018-2022. These are: 1. Supporting feminist movements to thrive; 2. challenging anti-rights agendas; and; 3. co-creating feminist realities and narratives. Three overarching outcomes follow.

Outcome 1. &quot;Feminist women&apos;s rights and gender justice movements are thriving, with stronger collective power to challenge patriarchy and advance feminist agendas. Three objectives are attached:
1. Strengthened connectivity and collaboration across and within feminist women&apos;s rights and gender justice moments.
2. Feminist women&apos;s rights and gender justice movements have more and better access to diverse resources for their work, and:
3. Feminist women&apos;s rights and gender justice activities and movements&#xA0;are better equipped and networked to maintain and enhance their holistic protection, security,safety and well-being. These objectives are also reflected in the Result Framework (RF).

Outcome 2. &quot;Feminist, women&apos;s rights and gender justice movements are better able to challenge, disrupt and delegitimize the consensus and influence of actors promoting&#xA0;patriarchy in connection with corporate power, fascism and fundamentalism within international spaces and systems.&#xA0;&#xA0;Three objectives are attached:
Objective 1: Increased understanding among feminist, womens rights and gender justice movements of the ways in which different actors uphold patriarchy in connection with corporate&#xA0; power,&#xA0;fascism and fundamentalism
Objective 2: Increased understanding among, and sharing between, feminist, womens rights and gender justice movements of strategies to effectively challenge, disrupt,delegitimize and dismantle the systems, actors and institutions upholding patriarchy in connection with corporate power,&#xA0;fascism and fundamentalism.

Objective 3: Feminist, women&apos;s rights and gender justice movements develop and deploy joint strategies to challenge, disrupt,&#xA0;delegitimize and dismantle the consensus and influence of actors promoting patriarchy in connection with corporate power,&#xA0;fascism and fundamentalism
Outcome 3. Feminist realities, proposals and narratives flourish, are amplified and become increasingly influential.Three objectives are attached:
Objective 1: Knowledge that puts forward feminist realities and narratives is co-created,shared and built among feminist, women&apos;s rights and gender justice movements.
Objective 2: Increased visibility of feminist realities, proposals and norms in intergovernmental spaces and&#xA0;as well as within and across feminist and other movements, and in society as a whole.
Objective 3: Re imagined existing and new joint agendas that reflect feminist realities, proposals, and narratives are collectively and successfully advocated for by feminist movements and allies.
AWID&apos;s&#xA0;programmatic work is organised into initiatives to achieve their goals. One of the important initiatives relates to the International Forum. Held every four years (the most recent held in 2016 in Brazil), the Forum draws up to 2,000 feminists from around the world. This initiative contributes to making visible feminism in practice, inspiring exchange and joint action and the process is co-created with members and partners. Some other examples of activities include the development and dissemination of knowledge and communication products, sharing feminist knowledge, practices and agendas.

The plan also puts an emphasis on maintaining and building organisational sustainability and resilience as well as sharing lessons and experiences with other organisations. Their work in this area includes, for example financial management, IT, human resources and organisational development, monitoring and evaluation; financial sustainability and governance
In our previous support to AWID, AWID has managed to&#xA0;support feminist movements to thrive. It is&#xA0;believed that the objectives set forth in the current&#xA0;plan will continue toward&#xA0;achieving this goal, by&#xA0;challenging anti-rights agendas, and co-create feminist realities and narratives as explained&#xA0;in the Strategic Plan under the heading &quot;what we aim to achieve&quot;. Furthermore they underline their commitment to continuing to build a bold and resilient feminist organization that can deliver on their ambitions to serve as a resource for others.&#xA0;

In&#xA0;summary, &#xA0;what&#xA0;is expected to be achieved by the end of this support&#xA0;is to strengthen the power of feminist movements, as a critical force in challenging the causes of the problems.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWID/Association for Women&#x2019;s Rights in Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWID/Association for Women&#x2019;s Rights in Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.2 - Eliminera &#xF6;vergrepp, utnyttjande, m&#xE4;nniskohandel och alla former av v&#xE5;ld eller tortyr mot barn.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.2 - End abuse, exploitation, trafficking and all forms of violence against and torture of children.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1265764.5217711497</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1163294.8740997685</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">760068.188974668</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1836327.8107474728</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1265764.5217711497</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1163294.8740997685</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">760068.188974668</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1836327.8107474728</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">5149360.213568</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">1265764.5217711497</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-28">634524.4767816919</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">760068.188974668</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-28">1836327.8107474728</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61070104_AmendmentNo1totheAgreementoncoresupport2018-2021betweenSidaandAWID.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment to the agreement between Sida and AWID 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61070104_AvtalmellanSidaochAssociationforWomen&apos;sRightsinDevelopment(AWID)2018-2022.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Avtal mellan Sida och AWID 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61070104_Beslutominsats,AWID2018-2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats AWID 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61070104_Beslutomandringavinsats,AWID2018-2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om &#xE4;ndring av insats AWID 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the 2020, AWID has contributed to the debate on COVID-19 responses, by placing feminist realities with focus on e.g. feminist and women&apos;s rights, labor and in-formalized work, LGBTQI, indigenous peoples&apos; rights, climate, disability and racial justice at the centre of discussions through activities such as sense-making discussions with organizations and partners as well as their #feministbailout campaign that reached over 5000 engagements.

In addition, AWID contributed to expand resources and enable long-term pressure to include feminist and women&apos;s rights in global dialogue for feminist organizations through the Equality Fund and other international forum. Throughout the year AWID has also produced several publications, arranged workshops, webinars and videos.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="61070104" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1070103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0.0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <title>Human rights, democracy and the rule of law 2018-2022</title>
    <titleSV>M&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, demokrati och r&#xE4;ttsstatens principer 2018-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
