<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6105005901-GGG-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICPD/UNFPA 2013</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ICPD/UNFPA 2013</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Genom en FN-resolution har UNFPA f&#xE5;tt i uppdrag att g&#xF6;ra en &#xF6;versyn   av Kairoprogrammet (ICPD) inf&#xF6;r 2014 d&#xE5; programmet funnits i 20 &#xE5;r.   &#xD6;versynen syftar till att utcv&#xE4;rdera vad som har uppn&#xE5;tts under dessa &#xE5;r samt vilka utmaningar som &#xE5;terst&#xE5;r och kommer att presenteras vid  Generalf&#xF6;rsamlingens m&#xF6;te i septmebre 2014.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through a UN resolution, UNFPA was given the mandate to conduct an    overview of the ICPD programme of action which, in 2014, has been in  place for 20 years. The overview will loo at achievements and         remaining challenges and be presented at the UN Assembly in September 2014.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41119" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA/United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41119" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA/United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">767671.8049499477</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">767671.8049499477</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-01">767671.804949</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">767671.8049499477</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA beslutade att g&#xF6;ra en uppf&#xF6;ljning av ICPD&#xA0;Programme of Action, Adopted at the International Conference on Population and Development, Cairo, 5-13 September 1994 - den s&#xE5; kallade ICPD Beyond 2014 Global Survey. 
Highlights:
- 176 member states and 7 territories provided responses to the global survey questionnaire.
- Country Implementation Profile
&#x2013; CIP agreed and database on ICPD related indicators with information on all member states concluded and made available.Finished coding of the global survey on the status of implementation of the ICPD.
- Analysis of the global survey completed and made available for the ICPD Global Review Report.
- Mapping in collaboration with the Program Division of good practices in terms of the role Country Offices played in ensuring that the Global Survey on the ICPD Review Process could be properly implemented.&#xA0; Due to this initiative, Programme Division and the ICPD Secretariat were able to assess the diligent and innovative work conducted by UNFPA in all regions in mobilizing authorities and building channels for civil society engagement in the national responses to the global survey.&#xA0;
- Assessment and systematization of various complementary sources for the ICPD Global Review Report.
- Mechanism for writing the Global Outcome Report in place.
- Thematic groups for the drafting of the Global Outcome Report established.
- Draft Committee for the ICPD Global Review established and leading the writing of the ICPD Review Report.
- Conclusion of the unedited version of the ICPD Review Report: Framework of Actions for the follow-up to the Programme of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development Beyond 2014 and of the SG Summary Report.
- The ICPD Beyond 2014 Review website served as a major information source for CSO and the use of social media has generated continuous interest and engagement of youth networks on the ICPD Review.
- Briefing to all member states on the ICPD Review Process in general and on the initiatives as needed.
- A broad budget plan for the entire ICPD Beyond 2014 process covering the period of 2012-2015 was designed and revised to anticipate resource mobilization needs putting in place a pool funding logic in support for the ICPD Review.
- Contribution from some particular donors, notably: the Netherlands, Switzerland, Denmark, Sweden and Norway and small contributions from other partners: Ford Foundation and Gates Foundation.
- Conceptual note on the Human Rights Conference developed in collaboration with OHCHR, the Government of Netherlands and several UN agencies, including UN Women, HABITAT and UNDESA.
- Conceptual note on the Women&#x2019;s Health Meeting was formulated in collaboration with Technical Division and negotiations with potential host countries for the meeting started in 2012.
- ICPD Beyond 2014 Review International Thematic Conference on Human Rights Conference successfully organized in partnership with the Netherlands, OHCR and other UN agencies.
- ICPD Beyond 2014 Review International Thematic Conference on Human Rights report made available to feed into the ICPD Global Review Report.
- ICPD Beyond 2014 Expert Meeting on Women&#x2019;s Health, Empowerment and Social Determinants hold in Mexico.ICPD Expert Meeting on Women&#x2019;s Health, Empowerment and Social Determinants report made available to feed into the ICPD Global Review Report.
- Interagency meeting on ICPD Indicators with UN stakeholders in China.

Lessons learned:
- The ICPD Beyond 2014 process demands contributions and active engagement from UNFPA various divisions and units including Regional Offices and Country Offices. The experience of the Regional Population Conferences demonstrated that working with the capitals through UNFPA presence is strategic for reinforcing commitment around the ICPD and a forward looking perspective.
- The fact that ICPD beyond 2014 was considered by UNFPA as a corporate priority contributed for the engagement of units in different ways: time allocation of staff in activities related to the ICPD Review, resources mobilized for the Regional Conferences to support for delegates to attend thematic meetings, regional population conferences and advocacy initiatives.
-&#xA0;Continuous dialogue with stakeholders about the ICPD Review and its outcomes proved to be needed not only in the course of the conferences and consultations, but as a regular exercise to brief Member States and CSOs &#x2013; reinforcing commitment around the ICPD and using evidence to demonstrate the relevance of the agenda and its implications, not only for the upcoming CPD and UNGASS, but also for the Post 2015.
- Investments by UNFPA and contributions by donors were absolutely critical to implement activities to generate the evidence needed as mandated by General Assembly resolution 65/234 and that can genuinely serve as a policy tool to advocate for the ICPD agenda, presenting realistic recommendations for action across the globe and to become a building block for the post MDG framework discussions.
- It became evident that the outcome report should serve as the major reference point for discussing, implementing and monitoring population and development policies and programmes beyond 2014 taking into account new and emerging issues, best practices and lessons learned, and including a monitoring framework for the ICPD agenda.
- Expanding the ICPD community, including reaching out to young people, using social media and demonstrating the relevance of the agenda to the wider global society have been critical in order to generate political support for actions required for the full achievement of the ICPD goals.
- The regional reviews ended with negotiated outcomes in four regions and in the case of the UNECE region, a negotiated Chairman&#x2019;s Summary. The outcomes of those reviews have largely resolved all the contentious and divisive issues that remained unresolved in Cairo in 1994, Beijing in 1995, and subsequent intergovernmental negotiations, including:Promotion and protection of human rights and non-discrimination;Access to sexual and reproductive health and rights for all persons;Recognition and non-discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity;Access to safe abortion, including compassionate post abortion care; Access to contraception and a wide range and modern methods of family planning, including emergency contraception;Enactment and enforcement of laws against harmful practices, violence and forced and child/early marriage, as well as hate crimes on the basis of sexuality;Gender equality and women&#x2019;s empowerment;Comprehensive sexuality education/mainstreaming sexuality into the rights and development agenda;Keeping in school or re-admitting pregnant adolescents, who have had babies;Removing restrictions on access to SRH services for adolescents and young people and providing information and SRH services for young people;It also includes progressive language on women and girls in the work place, the demographic dividend, ageing, urbanization, data, marginalized groups and sustainability.
----------------
It was a fruitful report&#xA0;that showed what has been done (and not done) since 1994 and the remaining challenges in SRHR.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="61050059" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
