<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6105008501-GGG-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNSDG/HRM MDTF - Mainstreaming Human Rights 2015-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNSDG/HRM MDTF - Mainstreaming m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter  2015-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Syftet &#xE4;r att FN:s utvecklingsgrupp (UNDG) arbetar f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja och st&#xE4;rka agendan f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av de m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheterna inom FNs utvecklingsarbete, b&#xE5;de normativt och operativt. UNDG - HRM &#xE4;r en mekanism som verkar globalt, regionalt och lokalt och som &#xE4;r kopplad till en multigivarfond (MDTF) vilken administreras av UNDP. Det &#xE4;r en strategisk och katalytisk insats f&#xF6;r att driva svenska prioriteringar f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter i FN-systemet. 

Ut&#xF6;ver policyp&#xE5;verkan best&#xE5;r en stor del av arbetsplanen i att bist&#xE5; med MR-r&#xE5;dgivare till FN:s regionala och lokala landteam, ge ledarskapsutvecklingsst&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r residence coordinators och kapacitetsutvecklingsinitiativ f&#xF6;r Human Rights Based Approach till FN:s landteam. Aktiviteterna syftar till att l&#xE4;gga grunden f&#xF6;r l&#xE5;ngsiktigt genomslag f&#xF6;r de m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheterna i FN:s utvecklingsarbete. 

M&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter &#xE4;r en av de tre pelare som FN grundades p&#xE5; och n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;nding f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5; utveckling och fred. Trots denna centrala plats i FN:s mandat har m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter inte historiskt f&#xE5;tt samma resurser som pelarna fred och utveckling. Arbetsgruppen under UNDG &#xE4;r  en permanent arbetsgrupp och m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter erk&#xE4;nns d&#xE4;rmed som en av de centrala pelarna av UNDGs arbete. St&#xF6;det till fonden &#xE4;r b&#xE5;de strategiskt och katalytiskt genom att det driver svenska prioriteringar fram&#xE5;t inom FN-systemet, vilket f&#xE5;r genomslag f&#xF6;r det svenska FN-st&#xF6;det i stort och &#xF6;vriga FN-processer som Sverige driver.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDG Human Rights Mainstreaming Multi Donor Trust Fund</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">2223002.223002223</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.130093839</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554785</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">2223002.2230022224</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">4626718.707365</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-28">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">2223002.223002223</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61050085_020096-15AddendumNo2totheStandardAdministrativeArrangementbetweenSidaandUNDG-H1581621_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addendum No 2 to the Standard Administrative Arrangement between Sida and UNDG- HRM Trust Fund</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61050085_033442-17Addendum3Signed2017-11-30-0923462162016_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addendum No 3 to the Standard Administrative Arrangement between Sida and UNDG- HRM Trust Fund</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61050085_039555-18Paskrivetaddendum4tillSAAskickatelektroniskttillUNDP_MPTFO2379672_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addendum No 4 to the Standard Administrative Arrangement between Sida and UNDG- HRM Trust Fund</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61050085_038291-19AddendumNo5_totheStandardAdministrativeArrangement_betweenSidaandUNDPr2584896_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addendum No 5 to the Standard Administrative Arrangement between Sida and UNDG- HRM Trust Fund</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61050085_043561-20SignedbySida-AddendumNo6-2021-11-302823849_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addendum No 6 to the Standard Administrative Arrangement between Sida and UNDG- HRM Trust Fund</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61050085_018533-15Beslutominsats-UNDG_HRWGUNHumanRightsWorkingGroup2015-20171571732_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61050085_025953-16StandardAdministrativeArrangementbetweenSidaandtheUNDGHumanRightsMains1888732_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Standard Administrative Arrangement between Sida and UNDG HRM Multidonor Trust Fund</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61050085_033363-17Beslutomavtalsandring,UNDG_HRWGMainstreamingmanskligarattigheter2014-20172139378_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om avtals&#xE4;ndring</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61050085_037504-19Beslutomandringavinsats,UNSDG_HRMMDTF-MainstreamingManskligaRattighete2581387_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om &#xE4;ndring av insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61050085_038443-18Beslutomandringavinsats,UNDG_HRMFOND-MainstreamingManskligarattigheter2374324_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om &#xE4;ndring av insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61050085_043054-20Beslutomandringavinsats-UNSDG_HRMMDTFMainstreamingManskligaRattigheter2821439_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om &#xE4;ndring av insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relevant strategic framework development
The work has been taken forward through the standing UNSDG human rights mainstreaming structures as they have evolved over time. In 2018, the UNSDG Task Team on Leaving No One Behind, Human Rights and the Normative Agenda (hereafter the Human Rights Task Team), was established under the Strategic Results Group on SDG Implementation, carrying on the long-standing functions of previous mechanisms for human rights mainstreaming. The preceding mechanisms include: the UNDG-Human Rights Mainstreaming Mechanism, the UNDG Human Rights Working Group (UNDG-HRWG) and the UNDG Results Group: Give Voice to Common Values and Norms (RG VVN).&#xA0;
The Human Rights Task Team is now the standing senior level inter-agency coordination mechanism responsible for taking forward the UNSDG&#x2019;s Human rights mainstreaming work. As with the preceding mechanisms, the Human Rights Task Team is co-chaired by the OHCHR and UNESCO, with WHO joining as a third chair. The Human Rights Task Team sets the strategic vision and priorities of the UNSDG and the UNDG-HRM Fund in terms of human rights mainstreaming activities.
Progress highlights
In May 2018, the UNDG reconstituted as the UN Sustainable Development Group (UNSDG). The UNSDG (previously UNDG) continued its work, in 2018, under the chapeau of the 2030 Agenda, responding to its strong focus on human rights, leaving no-one behind (LNOB) and reaching those furthest behind first. A key focus has been to continue supporting the UN at country-level to address human rights in the context of implementation of UN reform and to ensure that the new development system will be able to fully integrate human rights into the support provided to member states, in line with the 2030 Agenda.
In 2018, the demand from the field for human rights support continued to grow. This is in part due to the UN secretary-General&#x2019;s Human Rights up Front initiative and the strong focus on Prevention as a cornerstone of development results underlining the importance of the UN system in fulfilling its human rights responsibilities. The Human Rights Task Team built on previous achievements and the new UNDS mandates and structures to scale-up policy and operational support in the new era of development.
The programme of work in 2018 was in line with the objectives of the contribution and built on earlier priorities relating to: principled leadership and rights-based programming and advocacy capacities at country level, including through scaling up the deployment of Human Rights Advisers (HRAs); development of operational guidance for UN Country teams (UNCTs); and the facilitation of communities of practice for peer exchange and knowledge management.
Examples of activities implemented, and results achieved:
- In 2018, the UNSDG and Human Rights Task Team contributed to integration of human rights into the policies, frameworks and structures established in 2018 to implement and institutionalize the UNDS reform priorities. This included, for example, contributing to the revision of the guidance for new UNDAFs as the primary instrument for more coherent and effective programming at the country level. These inputs helped UNCTs integrate human rights, gender equality and women&#x2019;s empowerment and the principle of leave no one behind.
- In response to demand for support on integration of human rights at country level, the Human Rights Task Team published an Operational Guide on Leaving No One Behind for UNCTs which responded to demand from the field for clear guidance on how the UNDS can support the implementation of the 2030 Agenda&#x2019;s commitment to LNOB and reach furthest behind first. This Operational Guide is now the primary system-wide tool of the UNSDG for UNCTs in taking forward the pledge to LNOB and is referenced in key documents relating to UNDS reform including the new Cooperation Framework Guidance, the Joint SDG Fund first call for concept notes, and the Report of the Secretary General on implementation of the QCPR.
- To strengthen UN Leadership on Human Rights, the UNSDG continued to implement the three-pronged approach of Visionary Thought Leadership, Principled Leadership and Communities of Effort developed at the 2016 Human Rights Frontiers Forum. This is highlighted by the implementation of the first Regional Human Rights Dialogue for Resident Coordinators in the Asia Pacific Region (May 2018 Bangkok). It is a platform for identifying tactics and strategies for human rights leadership and was convened by UNDP, OHCHR and UNDCO with support from the Asia-Pacific regional UNSDG.
- The deployment of Human Rights Advisors (HRAs) was scaled up in 2018. Together with funding from other sources, a total of 34 HRAs were in place in 2018, up from 24 in 2017. 6 of the additional HRAs were funded from the UNDG-HRM Fund. HRAs continued to support RCs and UNCTS with additional technical assistance and capacity building, and support governments and a range of other national partners to better integrate human rights norms, standard and principles into country level activities. The UNDG-HRM Fund supported HRAs in 16 countries including Argentina, Bangladesh, Barbados, Belarus, Brazil, Ecuador, Jordan, Madagascar, Malaysia, The Philippines, Papa New Guinea, Peru, Rwanda, Timor-Leste, Uruguay and Zimbabwe.
- Throughout 2018, capacity development and advisory services for UN actors and partners continued. A highlight is, for example, the advice and support on human rights-based approach to data collection and use of human rights-based indicators. A result of this is seen, for example, in Zimbabwe where the HRA conducted technical briefings on the use of human rights indicators for members of the inter-agency UN Programme Management Team (PMT). This briefing served to inform the joint planning and programming processes under the Zimbabwe UN Development Assistance Framework for 2019.
Conclusion
The above analysis of the results achieved, and the growing demand for human rights support, indicate that the UNDG-HRM Fund contribution provides a good tool to ensure that RCs and UNCTs have the human rights capacities and that requisite supportive policies, tools and structures are in place and functioning.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="61050085" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
