<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5404018601-GGG-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP Disability Fund 2012-2014</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNDP Disability Fund 2012-2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Fondens &#xF6;vergripande syfte &#xE4;r att utveckla kapaciteten hos nationella akt&#xF6;rer, s&#xE4;rskilt myndigheter och organisationer som arbetar f&#xF6;r      r&#xE4;ttigheter f&#xF6;r personer med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, samt effektiv      implementering av konventionen f&#xF6;r personer med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning  (CRPD).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the fund is to develop the capacities of     national stakeholders, particularly governments and organizations of  persons with disabilities, for the effective implementation of the    CRPD, including through promoting disability-inclusive                internationally agreed development goals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">738672.4578587363</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">738672.4578587363</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-08-01">738672.457858</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-09-28">738672.4578587363</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: After foundational work was carried out in 2011-2012 with a focus on the mobilization of resources and the development of a strategic framework for the Partnership, the UNPRPD moved into a more operational phase in 2013. Since the signing of the agreement between Sida and UNDP, two funding rounds have been held. In the first round, initiated in 2012, support was given to Mozambique, Togo, South Africa, Palestine, Tunisia, Indonesia, Pacific Islands, Viet Nam, Moldova, Ukraine, Costa Rica. The second UNPRPD funding round was launched in March 2014, and implementation began in the last quarter of 2014 or early 2015.  The countries receiving support through the second round was Ethiopia, Uganda, Egypt, Sudan, China, India, Armenia, Tajikistan, Bolivia and Mexico. 

The initiative &#x201C;KnowUNPRPD&#x201D; programme has also received support through the fund and implemented by the UNPRPD Technical Secretariat in collaboration with the Centre for Global Health (CGH) of Trinity College Dublin and with certain funding from the Irish Government. The programme, launched in 2013, has had three overall objectives: to strengthen relevant technical competencies of staff involved in the implementation of UNPRPD-funded joint UN programmes; to foster exchange of experiences among projects; and to document lessons learned in the context of work carried out by the Partnership at the country level. A range of modalities was used to achieve the objectives, including intensive training workshops, learning circles and coaching. In addition, a help-desk service was provided for applicants to the second UNPRPD funding round, which made available technical assistance based on learning from Round 1.  In addition, the programme has encouraged country-to-country initiatives to support and exchange knowledge and practice. The programme has also stimulated some unanticipated spin-offs, such as the development of EquIPP, a tool for assessing and promoting equity and social inclusion in policy processes. Since the launch of the programme, three KnowUNPRPD sessions has been held for Round 1 UNPRPD countries and 2 sessions has been held for Round 2 UNPRPD countries. 

UNDPRPD have a three-dimensional focus on global, regional and national level implementation. The country programmes  has been and remain the main focus of the Fund, while the global and regional activities serve to strengthen the implementation of the CRPD at the country level. On a global level, the UNPRPD has engaged in strengthening the disability rights dimension in the Agenda 2030 framework, co-organising two regional conferences, one in Africa and one in Latin America. The conference organised together with the nternational Disability Alliance (IDA) and The International Disabiity and Development Consortium (IDDC) in Nairobi in 2014 resulted in a comprehensive political document highlighting African priorities in relation to disability rights in the context of the post-2015 development agenda and had a significant impact on the African Group of Member States in the post-2015 negotiations. The conference organised in Sao Paulo, Brazil in 2015 was organised in connection to the adoption of the 2030 Agenda and focused on UN CRPD implementation and strategic, coordinated and co-operative work amongst DPOs, UN agencies, governments and other civil society stakeholders.  Another intervention on a global level is the project &#x201C;One UN Approach to Disability Statistics, which was funded to enable various UN agencies to synergize and further develop disability data collection tools which will support governments in meeting their commitments under Article 31 of the CRPD. A number of joint expert group meetings between UN agencies, IDA and IDDC has been held, resulting in an advancement in individual data collection tools. For example, ILO completed the preparation of a draft module on employment and UNICEF has developed a module on Inclusive Education. Both modules were tested in 2016. 

On a regional level, the fund has focused on supporting both the establishment and development of regional forums and networks.  Through support from the fund, the Africa Disability Forum has been established with members from over 20 African countries. The organization is the only recognized Pan-African Disabled Person&apos;s Organization (DPO) membership organization in Africa. Since its establishment, it has also been accepted as a full member of the IDA. The fund has also supported the Pacific Enable, a network working to coordinate and strengthen the capacity to coordinate and align the work in the region to strengthen CRPD implementation. 

The UNPRPD has proven to be a successful mechanism for strengthening capacity at the country level for the implementation of the CRPD. In particular, it provides the means by which States Parties, UN entities and organizations of persons with disabilities can collaborate to operationalize the recommendations and General Comments of the CRPD Committee across a wide range of areas. UNPRPD projects have carried out innovative and impactful work on issues such as the exercise of the right to equal legal capacity through supported decision-making, application of universal design and accessibility principles, disability inclusive budgeting and strengthening of disability statistics among many others. Below are some examples of achieved results from the two UNPRPD funding rounds. 

Some examples of structural transformation achieved during UNPRPD R1: 
- In Moldova, broad systemic changes affecting the circumstances of persons with intellectual disabilities were initiated, including the introduction of justice oversight of existing psychiatric institutions, the adoption of an adult deinstitutionalization strategy and a reform of the legal guardianship system.
- In South Africa, CRPD compliance of the national disability policy architecture was significantly strengthened with the adoption of a White Paper on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities, the introduction of a comprehensive disability rights monitoring system and the development of a framework for disability-sensitive budgeting.
- In Tunisia, formal political commitment to the realization of disability rights was secured at the highest level of political leadership and across the entire political spectrum through the development and adoption of the Tunisian National Charter for the Rights of Persons with Disabilities.
- In Indonesia, a Network of Inclusive Cities was established, bringing together municipalities committed to the promotion of disability rights. As a result, several policy changes were triggered at the local level as well as significantly closer collaboration between municipal administrations and persons with disabilities.
-  In Costa Rica, the membership of the Network of Inclusive Businesses was more than doubled, and its capacity taken to a considerably higher level. This in turn led to a much broader and deeper private sector commitment to the realization of disability rights, supported by high level political institutions. 

Some examples of results achieved during UNPRPD R2: 
- In Tajikistan, the UNPRPD project has been supporting extensive advocacy, consultations and technical analysis to support the ratification of the CRPD. As a positive step forward in this direction, the Government supported the recommendation related to the ratification of the CPRD issued following the Second Cycle of Universal Periodic Review of Tajikistan. Furthermore, the Presidential Decree regarding Tajikistan&#x2019;s joining the CRPD is under consideration and are expected to sign the CRPD in 2017. 
- In Uganda, the UNPRPD project supported the development of accessible learning materials for persons with disabilities using Information and Communication Technology solutions. In parallel, the project has put in place the process for development of several important policy documents that are critical for an enabling policy architecture that bridges ICT, education and disability to create an appropriate eco-system for access to information and learning materials. Such an interface was missing prior to the UNPRPD project. With support from the Fund, policies within several areas has been developed: ICT and disability, ICT and education and inclusive publishing. A Policy Annex has been finalized on ICT and disability. This is to be added to the draft policy on Inclusive Education.
- In Armenia, the UNPRPD has supported the transition to a disability assessment model based on the International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health (ICF). As such, the UNPRPD project has contributed significant technical support and assisted in the creation of appropriate functional structures to advance an ongoing reform process.
- In Bolivia, the UNPRPD Project is designed to strengthen disability statistics across 3 sectors &#x2013;education, health and justice with the aim of strengthening the monitoring of services for persons with disabilities. With UNPRPD support, the Ministry of Education integrated disability related indicators from the Regional Education Information System on Students with disabilities (SIRIED) within the Bolivian national information system on education (SIE). In 2015, as part of this process, the project had evaluated the status of data generation and the information availability about students with disabilities. The findings confirmed the use of incomparable classification systems on students with disabilities and the absence of systemic and periodic indicators about the access, retention and completion rates of learners with disabilities. In 2016, 60 percent of indicators from the Regional Education Information System on Students with disabilities (SIRIED) were fully integrated in the educational information System.
- In China, the UNPRPD project has made significant efforts to shift attitudes, knowledge and practice of key stakeholders with respect to the rights of persons with disabilities. Disability Equality Trainings (DET) have begun to bring about spin off results. After DET, many of the participants launched collaborative efforts to reduce the barriers in the policy and social environment. For example, after attending DET, the Family Association in Guangzhou united to advocate with the Guangzhou City government for the development of polices on supported employment and the government responded by making a plan on SE.
- In India, the UNPRPD project is supporting actions at federal and provincial levels to strengthen inclusive education. These include the establishment of a coordination mechanism at the federal level on inclusive education in the form of an Inter-Agency Working Group with representation from a number of ministries and other government institutions. 
- In Mexico, the UNPRPD project is supporting the Secretariat of Social Development&#x2019;s (SEDESOL&#x2019;s) early childcare programme to become inclusive of children with disabilities. The programme is part of a social protection strategy to make available childcare to working mothers from the poorest households in Mexico. With UNPRPD assistance, SEDESOL is strengthening the quality of care and inclusiveness of services provided in the childcare facilities. Based on a census and comprehensive literature reviews, three products-manuals and tools were developed in 2016 to support the operationalization of the model for creation of inclusive environments in the childcare facilities. 
- In Egypt, based on a baseline study of labour markets conducted in 6 selected governorates to identify skills requirements, 5 training packages were developed and led to institutional collaboration with Microsoft, CISCO Academy, Ministry of Vocational Education as well as several community-based NGOs to provide vocational training services in the 6 governorates. A total of 616 persons with visual and physical disabilities (39 percent are female) were trained on vocational skills such as basic IT; vocational IT for PC; laptop and computer networks maintenance; graphics design; entrepreneurship and managerial skills; and customer services and call centres. In addition, 43 staff members (19 female and 24 male) of the NGOs in the governorates are now trained to conduct vocational trainings in an inclusive manner. At the same time, in order to support the project trainees to find jobs and internships, the project is currently preparing to follow up with 96 companies and job fairs have been organized whereby 131 persons with disabilities had access to companies and to apply for vacancies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="54040186" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
