<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-20/DDA-3558/SA1/H/NGO/17071</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support emergency referrals for secondary health care services.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ongoing crises in Syrian are highly affecting the life aspects of population in Hassakah governorate And Al-Raqqa . Where thousandth of families have become IDPs and thousands of families lost their income sources. Lack of basic utility services including electricity, fuel, safe drinking water and basic sanitation services have increased the vulnerability to disease outbreaks.

Hundreds of the health centers become out of service. Medicine and health services prices rise dramatically more than doubled. Not to mention the obstacles of providing medicines and medical devices (the only way of providing them is by air with high costs). IDPs , returnees  and affected families from local community in Raqqa governorate are suffering from difficult living conditions, which include the medical shortage, health issues that are caused by malnutrition, spreading of epidemics and diseases, and the rarity of health centers in some districts besides. The desperate need for clinics and dispensary, the high prices of surgeries, low individual income level and lost the income sources and scarcity of transportation to the capital to conduct some surgeries unless by airlines which is highly expensive.
There will be a joint committee from the project and the local community, and the committee will be responsible for setting clear criteria for working and selecting cases, and there will be a complaint box that is opened on a daily basis and responding to complaints.



Will be Coordinate with health directorates, the Health Organization and any partner in the health sector to benefit from current data and any monitoring and awareness systems, or similar data and systems.
- The sector concerned with the proposed activities and the mechanism for implementing the project was consulted


The above situation led to deprived many people to conduct life-saving surgeries and medical treatment because of their inability to afford the high costs. Thus many people lost their lives and many become disabled.

Al-Ihsan association one of the main partners fot UNICEF,UNFPA ,WHO and UNHCR in the health sector and implemented many health projects in the HTR areas in Raqqa and Hasakeh governorate , with very good expert staff.

As we will provide life-saving services that will enhance the people life, gender equality will be respected by implication in terms of the project will provide services to all those in need regardless of gender.

Al-Ihsan through this project aims to cover all expenses of lifesaving surgeries and treatment for people in needs healthcare services, Al-Ihsan will target all IDPs and affected people of local community in Raqqa governorate
2,824  people will have benefited from the project services

To insure that the service provided is life-saving, Al-Ihsan will use the referrals system to ensure that an appropriate diagnosis of patients and understand their medical status. The referrals system will include diagnose the patients and laboratory tests. Depending on the recommendations of Al-Ihsan&apos;s doctors and specialist doctors and, the patient will referred to the hospitals for surgeries or treatment of needed. Al-Ihsan will cover the cost of surgical operations, treatment and medicines. Al-Ihsan will follow up and monitor the patients&#x2019; situation through the monitoring system to insure that, the required actions and the best medical results have been achieved.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Ihsan Association in Tal Hamis</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Ihsan Association in Tal Hamis</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Ihsan Association in Tal Hamis</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdullah Abdullah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0994938569</telephone>
   <email>slam44@hotmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ar-Raqqa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.95307500 39.00606200</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-16">247919</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-17071">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-16">247919</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Ihsan Association in Tal Hamis</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304928109-110">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-20">198335.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Ihsan Association in Tal Hamis</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305194328">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-14">49583.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Ihsan Association in Tal Hamis</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
