<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5203004401-IRQ-33112</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNIDO/Swedac, Kvalitetsinfrastruktur, 2011-2015</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIDO/Swedac, Qualityinfrastructure, 2011-2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet &quot;Strengthening the National Quality Infrastructure to Facilitate Trade and Enhance Consumer Protection in Iraq&quot; syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra Republiken Iraks handelskapacitet och resultat och fr&#xE4;mja integration i det regionala och multilaterala handelssystemet. Projektet genomf&#xF6;rdes av UNIDO, FN: s industri- och utvecklingsorganisation med de irakiska nationella motsvarigheterna; Ministeriet f&#xF6;r planering, Centralorganisationen f&#xF6;r standarder och kvalitetskontroll och det irakiska ackrediteringssystemet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &quot;Strengthening the National Quality Infrastructure to Facilitate Trade and Enhance Consumer Protection in Iraq&quot; aims to enhance trade capacities and performance of the Republic of Iraq and fostering integration into the regional and multilateral trading system. The project was implemented by UNIDO, United Nations Industrial and Development Organization with the Iraqi National counterparts; Ministry of Planning, the Central Organization for Standards and Quality control and Iraqi Accreditation System.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &quot;Strengthening the National Quality Infrastructure to Facilitate Trade and Enhance Consumer Protection in Iraq&quot; aims to enhance trade capacities and performance of the Republic of Iraq and fostering integration into the regional and multilateral trading system. The project was implemented by UNIDO, United Nations Industrial and Development Organization with the Iraqi National counterparts; Ministry of Planning, the Central Organization for Standards and Quality control and Iraqi Accreditation System.&#xA0;
The specific objective of the project was to upgrade the national quality infrastructure (Standards, Testing, Metrology and Conformity Assessment) following international best practices, for creating the enabling environment needed for better trade performance and consumer protection. The implementation of the support followed the stipulation of the trade agreements under WTO (namely the technical barriers to trade and the sanitary and phytosanitary agreements). Project was set up to include various training activities, technical assistance and capacity building with support from international experts to achieve following six outcomes:
Outcome 1: Adapted to the new principles of the international trade regime, the Iraqi quality system (i.e. legal framework and infrastructure) is effective in promoting trade and in improving consumer protection, and national institutions competent in advocating and managing the national quality system.
Outcome 2: Conformity assessment services (i.e. testing, certification, inspection) accredited by a regionally and internationally recognized independent Iraqi Accreditation Body are offered on the market.
Outcome 3: Enhanced national trade policy framework fostering progress in the WTO accession process.
Outcome 4: Effective coordination and management of the project.
Outcome 5: Effective Monitoring, Evaluation and Governance of the project, including Security Support.&#xA0;
Outcome 6: Adapted to international best practices, the Iraqi food control system is effective.
The project started up as a quality infrastructure support under the&#xA0;Strategy for development cooperation with Iraq during July 2009 &#x2013; December 2014 and was added on with food control components.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41123" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIDO/United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIDO/United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Policies &amp; Regulations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">2511865.8694446157</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">2659220.8482914506</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">3377755.94177977</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2360812.87888674</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">2511865.8694446157</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">2659220.84829145</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">3377755.94177977</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2360812.87888674</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-12-01">11742587.684152</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-12-28">2511865.8694446157</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-10-28">2659220.8482914506</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">3377755.94177977</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-03-28">2360812.87888674</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall achievements of the interventions under the project &quot;Strengthening the National Quality Infrastructure to Facilitate Trade and Enhance Consumer Protection in Iraq&quot; resulted in both a new governmental structure of quality infrastructure institutions as well as new legislations. The activities were evaluated and was assessed with good results according to the plan, however the food control system was set up as an integrated part of the quality infrastructure project and was therefore not enabling to achieve the same positive changes on food safety systems as the quality infrastructure outcomes.
Several policy committees and functions were established under the policy level of the project. Each of them with specific tasks to assess and implement the overall policy level structures. Following structures was set up:
- a high-level multi-stakeholder committee,
- National policy manager team was coached and exposed to international best practices,
- National Regulatory and Quality Policy, NRQP in line with WTO agreements and the principles of the multilateral trade regime, developed and complemented by a strategic implementation roadmap.
- NRQP submitted by the Ministry of Planning and approved by theCouncil of Ministers at the end of 2017.
- Set of complementary second-level policy/regulatory reforms (i.e. bylaws, systems, procedures, organizational structures).
- National curriculum/certificate programme on quality infrastructure finalized and training of 16 tutors.  Establishment of accreditation, IQAS Iraqi Accreditation System. The project support resulted in:
- 30 laboratories accredited (i.e. food, medical, construction material, calibration)
- National accreditation law fully approved and published
- Quality management system/ISO/IEC17011 &#x2013; fully automated IT solution
- Staff number increased - trained and qualified
- Equipped with a pool of lead and technical assessors
- Capacities as training provider &#x2013; training programmes running- Fully recognized by ARAC
- International recognized by ILAC/associate member and engaged in 4 technical committees
- Cooperation agreement with the Tunisian Accreditation council (TUNAC), and a technical twinning arrangement with SWEDAC.  Accreditation &#x2013; Support to Conformity Assessment Bodies and development of Proficiency Testing (PT) scheme resulted in:
- 6 testing laboratories (i.e. food, construction and paints) - 7 calibration laboratories - 6 medical testing laboratories upgraded towards accreditation
- 1 inspection body &#x2013; 1 product certification body &#x2013; 1 management system certification body upgraded towards accreditation
- Conformity Assessment Bodies staff trained and qualified
- Policy framework and operational procedures for a national PT scheme
- First national Proficiency Testing schemes implemented
- Specialized PT and inter-laboratory comparison software
Standardization and Market Surveillance was implemented under the project and resulted in:
- Organizational re-structuring of COSQC&#x2019;s Standards Department
- QMS in line with ISO/IEC 9001:2015 - pool of 12 internal auditors qualifiedin line with ISO 9001 and ISO 19011 requirements &#x2013; state of the art IT solution
- Standards Governance System developed &#x2013; 34 re-activated TechnicalCommittees (TCs) with 44 conveners &#x2013; 78 newly published national standards
- Memberships and collaboration with reg./int. standards bodies/institutions such as ISO, BSI, TSE, KOWSMD, and AIDMO.
- COSQC&#x2019;s standards Department staff trained and qualified
- Benchmarking and roadmap for upgrading of the Iraqi Market Surveillance finalized
- Technical Regulations guidelines and law developed- in line with the NRQP
Metrology, structure support resulted in:
- Quality manual for COSQC&#x2019;s Metrology Department and all relevant labs
- 7 calibration laboratories upgraded towards accreditation &#x2013; 4 accredited (i.e. mass, dimensional, force and electrical measurement) 
- Calibration of existing equipment at an int. recognized NMI and traceability policy developed 
- Metrology department&#x2019;s staff, and laboratories&#x2019; personnel trained 
- Review of the national metrology law
- COSQC fully recognized by BIPM as full member and is participating in theCIPM MRA. 
Trade and WTO accession support, aiming to link the quality infrastructure to the references of the agreements under the WTO resulted in:
-National WTO accession negotiation team reinforced and trained
-Draft initial offer on market access for trade in goods finalized &#x2013;transposition to the latest version of HS codes required
-Draft initial offer on market access for trade in services finalized
-Iraq&#xB4;s Memorandum on Foreign Trade Regime (MFTR) updated and finalized for its submission to the WTO &#x2013; informal meeting of the revived working party 
-Partnership with other agencies such as ESCWA, UNDP, FAO, and the WTO and acquaintance with accession experiences of Arab countries (i.e. Jordan, Oman, Saudi Arabia and Yemen)
Food Safety, component resulted in targeting upgrades of the Iraqi system:
-Upgrading of 5 selected food testing laboratories, and of the food inspection system of 2 selected border crossing points in the Al-Basra Governorate, from 3 different Ministries
-Knowledge and skills of COSQC and other stakeholders&#x2019; personnel strengthened, labs, inspection, sampling and transportation
-Food inspection and sampling manual developedGap analysis of 13 food processing enterprises against HACC requirements in different governorates of Iraq
-Knowledge and skills of COSQC&#xB4;s and of food processing enterprises personnel strengthened in the area of food quality and safety
-Upgrading of 6 selected food-processing enterprises towards HACCP &#x2013; 5 HACPP and 1 FFSC 22000 certified</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52030044" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
