<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SDN029</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian protection response to vulnerable South Sudanese Refugees and Host Communities in Kosti</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operational support for the Protection services project will focus on prevention of Sexual and Gender Based Violence (SGBV) and child protection. Services will include identification and support to SGBV survivors through psychosocial and counselling support; establishment of 1 Women Centre (which will be supported with facilities and commodities to facilitate activities at the centre), 3 Children&#x2019;s Clubs in schools and 5 Community Based Protection Networks (CBPNs); trainings for 50 CBPN members, 45 teachers and 45 pupils on psychosocial and counselling support; training on Safe Accessible Dignified and Inclusive (SADI) programming framework for project partners (CAFOD and GAH), and undertaking of a 16-day activism and celebration of International Women&#x2019;s Day.

In the project, integration of gender and protection of women, girls and other vulnerable categories of people in the community will be through analysis (data gathering and analysis using sex, age disaggregated tools), targeting and adaptation to the diversity of needs, identifying potential negative effects, and introducing prevention or mitigating measures, community engagement, information sharing, setting up of complaints and feedback mechanisms and coordination with other actors/stakeholders.

Catholic Agency for Overseas Development (CAFOD) is the lead partner in the consortium involving Global Aid Hand (GAH). Project activities will directly be implemented by GAH, with CAFOD providing project management and technical support on the focus sector of the project. The project duration is 8 months.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SDN029" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SDN029" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SDN029" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-08-01">2629.062</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="53666">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-26">2629.062</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
