<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-18/DDA-3558/AR/FSA/UN/10953</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency agricultural assistance to targeted drought affected households in Al-Hasakeh, Ar-Raqqua, Aleppo, Deir-Ez-Zor, Hama Governorates in Syria Arab Republic.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The United Nations estimates number of people in need of humanitarian assistance in Syria at 13.1million.This includes overall 10.5million of people estimated to be food insecure and at risk of food insecurity. Consecutive FAO/WFP comprehensive food security assessments (CFSAM) have found a decrease in food production and that people are adapting negative copying mechanisms involving reduced number and quality of meals which is the main reason for the increasing  number of people who are food and nutrition insecure. CFSAM 2018, indicates the lowest wheat production, 1.2 million tons, which is the lowest since 1989 and about 30 percent of the pre-conflict average of 4.1 million tons (2002-2011). Syria Arab Republic was effected by the worst drought since 1972. The weather during the 2017/18 cereal cropping season was described by farmers in several areas, and especially in Hasakeh which provides about 45 percent of the country&#x2019;s wheat, as bad as that of 1972/73. There was a generally late start to the rains, most pronounced in the east, which delayed planting for as much as two months. When the rains eventually arrived they initially looked promising, but a prolonged dry spell which desiccated much of the rainfed crop at the critical time of heading and flowering. The continuing crisis and the consequent import sanctions imposed on Syria have resulted in a substantial reduction in the availability and quality of farm inputs. Prior to the crisis, the Government used to provide inputs to farmers either free of charge or at highly subsidized prices. Before the crisis, the Government through the General Organization for Seed Multiplication (GOSM)  used to provide farmers with more than 300 000 tons of certified seed. In 2012, GOSM was able to purchase some 280 000 tons of wheat seed from out-growers, but since then the amounts purchased annually have declined dramatically. For 2018 planting season, GOSM approximately distributed 36 500 tons of wheat to farmers which is less than 10 percent of the seed that would have been required for the 1.8 million hectares that were planned for wheat production. Faced by drastic shortage of wheat seed in the country, most farmers for 2018 season will have to rely on purchasing seed of unknown sources or on using grain saved from their own harvest. In general subsidized wheat seed is distributed to farmers who were able to pay their debt with GOSM. Vulnerable farmers with limited or no resources are left out of the distribution scheme. FAO support for wheat production in Syria has been focusing  on the vulnerable farmers to  ensure their access to quality seed for their own food production. The impact of the 2018 drought has added another layer of challenges to the already fragile agriculture sector, affected by more than seven years of crisis, leading to an over low record of wheat production, 1.2 million tons, just about 30% of the pre crisis average of 4 million tons. The registered low wheat production is likely to increase the number of food insecure people and push up the food price on local market if no external intervention is provided. The Government has measured the degree of gravity of the situation and has decided to launch procurement of 1.5 million tons of wheat on international market.  Considering that about 19 millions people inside Syria, the country own production of wheat (1.2 million tons) and international procurement (1.5 million tons) will make up 2.7 millions of wheat thus leaving a gap of 1.1 million tons of wheat to cover either by international aid organizations and private imports. FAO emergency response to support vulnerable farmers wheat production  in cooperation will WFP which will provide food assistance is aiming to build synergies in supporting more long lasting approach of food security. The objective of the proposed action is to reduce vulnerability of newly displaced, returnees and over burdened host communities to food and nutrition insecurity through life-</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Agriculture and Agrarian Reform</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mike Robson</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAO Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0933 212025</telephone>
   <email>mike.robson@fao.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY08">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Hasakeh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.50537500 40.74289900</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ar-Raqqa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.95307500 39.00606200</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY09">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deir-ez-Zor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.33188500 40.14607100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hama</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.13374200 36.76129100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">267806.27</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">1732193.73</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400301291">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-25">7702.8</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-10953">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">2000000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303699715">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-04">2000000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
