<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="RWF" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>RW-RGB-114-RGB-RGO-2013-XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000001218</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="RW-RGB-114-RGB-RGO-2013" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Legal Aid Forum</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using ICT to Provide Legal Services to Rwandan Population</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project targets Women, youth, People with disabilities , the unemployed, Remote and rural communities Teen mothers, generally all Rwandans but mostly focusing vulnerable population in Rwanda.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The wide use of mobile technology in Rwanda allows LAF to provide legal information and advice to vulnerable populations in Rwanda, free of charge. While the project aim at increasing access to legal aid through mobile phone engagement, the project has two phases. Phase one focused on developing the content for and promoting the use of existing 845 services within MTN and phase two consists of establishing the supplemental legal helpline at the LAF premises, the Call Centre. The project assists state and non-state legal service providers to raise citizen awareness of their rights and the laws that affect large portions of the population. This service is important to both state and non-state legal service providers, such as MAJ, Mediation Committees knon as &apos;Abunzi&apos;, courts and non-state legal aid providers like NGOs, and legal aid clinics of both public and private Universities. Legal aid information on LAF ICT Platform (845 service) is designed to provide various types of information including general procedural information about how to access courts, how to deal with SGBV, how to have judgments enforced, or how to file documents with the courts and aid on particular issues that service seekers may express.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is implemented by The Legal Aid Forum (LAF) and is funded by the Embassy of the Kingdom of the Netherlands in Rwanda. The wide use of mobile technology in Rwanda will allow LAF to provide legal information and advice to vulnerable populations in Rwanda free of charge.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="4000001218" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="4000001218" ref="RW-RGB-114/08.11" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Legal Aid Forum</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The available funding for the project is for three years. Activities run from 1st March 2018 up to 28th February 2021.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Legal Aid Forum (LAF)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Management</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Me Andrews Kananga</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+250788307174</telephone>
   <email>legalaidrwanda@gmail.com</email>
   <website>http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O.Box 5225 Kigali - Rwanda</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Legal Aid Forum (LAF)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programmes</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jean Paul Ibambe</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+250788668164</telephone>
   <email>jpaul@legalaidrwanda.org</email>
   <website>http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O.Box 5225 Kigali - Rwanda</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="50">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda is located in Africa, member of East African Community.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="50" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda is located in Africa region</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location ref="RW">
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="250" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda has a population estimated at 11.4 million people. Women account for 52% of the population. Outside of the capital city of Kigali, the majority of the population lives in rural areas. The rural nature of the country makes access to basic services difficult. As of 2014, the average distance most people have to walk to reach basic services such as food and medical services is one hour. Literacy in Rwanda is limited. The national literacy rate for people in Rwanda aged 15 and above is 68.3%. Urban areas have higher literacy rates than rural areas, with Kigali having some of the highest literacy rates at 89% of the population aged 15 and above. However, literacy rates do vary by gender. The national literacy rate for women is 68% compared to that of men at 77%. Literacy rates are generally lower in groups with overall lower incomes. Rwanda still struggles heavily with poverty. Long-term development plans such as the Vision 2020 and Economic Development and Poverty Reduction Strategy (EDPRS) have been focused on development and poverty reduction. As of 2014, 39.1% of the total population was living below the poverty line of 159,375RWF per person per year. The Rwandan context creates a need for innovative solutions to deliver justice that are easily accessible to the most vulnerable sections of the population.</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x201C;Using ICT to Provide Legal Services to the Rwandan Population - 845 project&#x201D; is a joint partnership between Legal Aid Forum (LAF) and Viamo. The project is funded by the Embassy of the Kingdom of the Netherlands. The project came up following a study conducted by LAF in 2017 on citizen perception of justice and legal services in Rwanda. As per the findings, the distance Rwandans have to travel to reach legal aid providers represent an access problem. This is because in Rwanda, most state and non-state legal aid services rely primarily on vis-&#xE0;-vis consultations between service seeker and provider. In most cases, legal assistance and advice-seekers must travel to offices and wait for a moment to meet an advocate or a paralegal in person, regardless of the nature of the case or the services they are seeking. Out of the 5,503 respondents interviewed, 34% had to walk between 30 minutes and one hour to reach the nearest legal aid provider; 20% had to walk between one and three hours; approximately 7% had to travel more than 5 hours whereas only 4% of respondents rated their knowledge of the law as &#x201C;high&#x201D;. While as of March 2019, telephone penetration in Rwanda was at a rate of 77.2% and the total number of active mobile telephone subscriptions is 9,326,267; at the same time, the overall internet penetration in Rwanda is 49.5%, with 17% of the households that have access to internet at home in 2016/17; the use of Mobile phones to reach a big number of Rwandans is the best option for LAF to provide legal information, advice and legal assistance to vulnerable populations in Rwanda if it is meant to reach wide audience. In the absence of the 845 legal services, the most common idea to deliver legal aid services was that legal aid providers should set up offices closer to the communities to avoid requiring clients to walk long distances. However, building additional offices in numerous areas of the country was not feasible. Therefore, offering individuals the option of accessing legal aid services over the phone would reduce the burden on the vulnerable and indigent of having to walk long distances to receive legal. Once put in place, the 845 platform enabled all the service seekers to access legal aid services anonymously through 845/*845# free of charge. To support the project, LAF obtained funding from the Embassy of the Kingdom of the Netherlands to Kigali and implemented the project activities.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="250" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-1 29</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="2"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="RGN"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The wide use of mobile technology in Rwanda allows LAF to provide legal information and advice to vulnerable populations in Rwanda, free of charge. The project aims at increasing access to legal aid through mobile phone engagement.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="3" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity promotes the Access to Justice</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="RWF" value-date="2020-12-31">183729793</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="4000001218">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="RWF" value-date="2020-06-16">75000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Installment</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="RW-RGB-0000000-ICT4J" type="22"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="4"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="RWF" value-date="2020-11-01">108729793</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second Installment of 2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Money was second installment of the year 2020</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="RW-RGB-114/08.11" type="22"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="4"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Citizens access education materials on their (legal) rights and Rwandan mostly used laws</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The legal messages uploaded on 845 platform are meant to educate the rwandans</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="APPLICATION/MSWORD" url="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People listen to and read legal information materials from 845 helpline and platform</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The message are accessible free of charge both in text and audio format</narrative>
    </description>
    <category code="B01"></category>
    <language code="EN"></language>
    <document-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></document-date>
   </document-link>
   <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People receive legal and human rights information during the Legal Aid Week</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outreach activities to educate citizens and to promote the project services in remote areas countrywide during the Legal Aid Week. Because of COVID19, the legal aid week was conducted via Radio and TV talk shows.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" indicator-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="30000" year="2020">
     <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
     <dimension name="People" value="Both male and female"></dimension>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2020 the Legal Aid week was conducted via Radio and TV Talkshows</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30000">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="People seeking legal aid" value="Both male and female (Unable to know numbers by gender"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The beneficiaries benefited mostly in legal education</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100000">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="Poeple" value="Both female and male"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unable to identify female from male</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People listen to legal information materials from 845 helpline</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" indicator-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="50000" year="2020">
     <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
     <dimension name="Legal Messages" value="IVR and USSD"></dimension>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50000">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="Legal Messages" value="IVR and USSD"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2038292">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="Legal materials" value="IVR and USSD"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It seems the target was underestimated</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Citizens access free legal services</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This consists of people getting legal advice from the LAF call center, referrals to relevant service providers and legal representation before courts of law on critical cases.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="APPLICATION/MSWORD" url="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">USING ICT TO PROVIDE LEGAL SERVICES TO THE RWANDAN POPULATION - 845 ( 2020 Annual Report)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The report narrates activities achieved in 2020</narrative>
    </description>
    <category code="B01"></category>
    <language code="EN"></language>
    <document-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></document-date>
   </document-link>
   <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases represented before courts of law</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Critical cases for legal representation</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" indicator-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="100 cases" year="2020">
     <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
     <dimension name="Cases given legal representation" value="Both Civil and criminal cases"></dimension>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is designed in a way that once deemed necessary, some beneficiaries are provided legal assistance by Legal Aid Forum Lawyers or by Lawyers assigned by the Rwanda Bar Association through cases referral protocol between the Rwanda Bar Association and The legal Aid Forum.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="Cases" value="Criminal and civil cases"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A number of criteria and checklist was set by the LAF secretariat for a case to be treated as critical and given legal representation. An attention is paid to poor people, minors, teen mothers, detainees and victims of gender based violence.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="148">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="Cases" value="Criminal and Civil cases"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Up to December 2020, 148 Cases were identified and handed over to lawyers for legal representation,  The remaining number of callers were either satisfied and their cases were completed after being advised by the call Centre lawyers others were referred other legal aid providers like: MAJ and other institutions, Courts, Abunzi etc.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Referrals to relevant legal aid service providers</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The referrals include cases referred to: Courts, Abunzi Committees, MAJ, other administrative institutions</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" indicator-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="500" year="2020">
     <location ref="2020"></location>
     <dimension name="People referred to other legal aid services providers" value="Both Women and Men"></dimension>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The referrals include cases referred to: Courts, Abunzi Committees, MAJ, other administrative institutions etc.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="500">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="People" value="Women and men"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1250">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="People referred" value="Women and men"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People who get legal advice from the LAF call center</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">people who are called back/ advised by the call centre lawyers</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" indicator-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="15000" year="2020">
     <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
     <dimension name="People advised by call centre lawyers" value="Men and women"></dimension>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of callbacks in 2020</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15000">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="Number of People" value="Men and women"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="41525">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="People" value="Female and male"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ICT platform is set up and operational</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This results &apos;The ICT platform is set up and operational&apos; is related to setting up the project ICT and Telecommunication infrastructure.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="APPLICATION/MSWORD" url="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">USING ICT TO PROVIDE LEGAL SERVICES TO THE RWANDAN POPULATION - 845 (Annual Report 2019)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This document constitutes the project&#x2019;s progress report. It highlights the project&#x2019;s achievements for the period between 1st January 2019 and 31st December 2019 with the focus on the results obtained and the project&#x2019;s outcomes or its short term effects.</narrative>
    </description>
    <category code="B01"></category>
    <language code="EN"></language>
    <document-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></document-date>
   </document-link>
   <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 Help line set up and running</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Helpline is connected to the IVR and allows Call centre operators to make calls</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" indicator-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="1" year="2020">
     <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
     <dimension name="Number of Platforms" value="1 Platform"></dimension>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Call Centre was set up to enable calls</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="IT" value="Equipement"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">One of the first activities under the project was the technical set up of the service and completion of the E1 set up with MTN. This E1 connection integrates a cloud-based platform with the MTN infrastructure in Rwanda. This integration pre-dated this project but is critical to the success of the project as it is the connection that is used to set up the legal aid call centre. This integration was completed in June 2018, giving partners access to a block of 1,000 MTN numbers to be used for various projects. Of these, one number was assigned as the outgoing caller ID for the call centre: +2507881260007). It is this E1 that allows subscribers to call 845 for free of charge.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="IT" value="Equipment"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Call center is equipped and ready</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Call Centre enable the operators to call back citizen seeking legal advice from lawyers through call booking option. It has designed, equipped with materials including Laptops, Mobile phones, headsets, etc. in 2019, after four months of operations, data from the project advocated for taking a number of actions including expansion of the capacity of the call centre and limiting time booking was allowed in order to tackle overwhelming number of call back requests. There was a big gap between numbers of people who booked calls from those who have been called back (11%-12%). Thus, we increased the Call Center Operators from 3 to 6. As a result, all bookings are timely served without delays. In 2020 there was one additional call centre to make them 7. It is under the support of EU for the Freedom of Expression legal content.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" indicator-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="1" year="2020">
     <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
     <dimension name="Call Centre Set up" value="Equipements"></dimension>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Call centre was set up and expanded</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="1 Call Centre" value="Equipped"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">One call centre was set up and expanded later</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="Call Centre" value="Equipped"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Set up and equipped</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Help line and call center service are advertised</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 845 platform is a unique and the first service of its kind in Rwanda and its&#x2019; importance have been highlighted. Therefore, it is of paramount importance to conduct awareness activities aimed at promoting the services for better and easy access to legal services. For the purposes of making the 845 legal services known by all Rwandans, the LAF have conducts promotional activities using different tools like: Promotion of the project during Legal Aid Week, Awareness Campaigns of the project countrywide, Participation in Umuganda with promotional materials for distribution, Design and distribution of project brochures, Raising awareness through interactions with the media , Radio and TV talk shows, Publication of articles in News Papers, Magazine and Newsletter and Bulk SMSs and MTN Promotion</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" indicator-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="25 times" year="2020">
     <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
     <dimension name="Promotional activities" value="Used different tools"></dimension>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the awareness purposes, the help line and the call centre needs to be advertised so the beneficiaries know it and how to use it. The services was in 2020 advertised even on Social media platforms.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="Adverts" value="Through different advertisement tools"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the purposes of making the 845 legal services known by all Rwandans, the LAF planned to conduct promotional activities using different tools.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="25">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="Adverts" value="Different tools"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">More than 25 adverts were conducted in 2019 using different tools including radio and TV adverts, Bulk SMS, distribution of brochures and social media platforms.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal messages are designed, translated, updated and uploaded/linked to Viamo&apos;s 845 service</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">LAF introduced the 845 service to legal aid stakeholders in a series of meetings. The first of these was held on May 10, 2018 at Marasa Umubano Hotel to introduce the project to stakeholders and agree on the themes to be covered in this project and create thematic groups to work on the messages during the content development workshop. Five themes were agreed upon during this meeting including: 1) Gender based violence and Child&#x2019;s rights, 2) Succession and Family, 3) Land and Expropriation 4) Procedural Law, 5) Jurisdiction of Courts and Abunzi Law. In January 2019 there was also development of labor related content to make the sixth theme of legal messages on 845. To develop the content, LAF consults experts from the Ministry of Justice, Office of Ombudsman, Rwanda Bar Association, Rwanda Law Reform Commission, Gender Monitoring Office and other relevant stakeholders depending on the content that is needed . After review of the messages and all corrections made, the next step is to script all messages in a dialogue format so we get content for IVR platform. When the messages are approved for recording, then it&#x2019;s time for recording. After a review, then the messages are ready of pre-testing phase. In 2019, this is the process that labor related messages underwent. Before the release of the messages, LAF captured public opinion on the messages through a pre-testing phase. The purpose of the exercise was to avail legal messages without any confusion or misunderstanding by the public audience. The pretesting of labor related messages in January 2019, was conducted with collaboration with Rwanda Workers&apos; Trade Union Confederation (CESTRAR) and its affiliated member organizations.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" indicator-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="45" year="2020">
     <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
     <dimension name="Legal messages on difference topics" value="1) Gender based violence and Child&#x2019;s rights, 2) Succession and Family, 3) Land and Expropriation 4) Procedural Law, 5) Jurisdiction of Courts and Abunzi Law and 6) Labor Law, 7) Enforcement 8) Freedom of Expression"></dimension>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In January 2019 there was also development of labor related content to make the sixth theme of legal messages on 845. In 2020 there was addition of Freedom of Expression related content.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="45">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="94 Messages" value="Related to 1) Gender based violence and Child&#x2019;s rights, 2) Succession and Family, 3) Land and Expropriation 4) Procedural Law, 5) Jurisdiction of Courts and Abunzi Law and 6) Labor Law, 7)Enforcement of Court decisions (RCN) 8) Freedom of Expression"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Additional messages were also developed</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="94">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="94 messages are on the platform" value="In 1) Gender based violence and Child&#x2019;s rights, 2) Succession and Family, 3) Land and Expropriation 4) Procedural Law, 5) Jurisdiction of Courts and Abunzi Law and 6) Labor Law, 7) Enforcement 8) Freedom of Expression"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">SMS portal set up</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The SMS portal is for the Unstructured Supplementary Service Data (USSD) legal information.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RW-RGB-0000000" indicator-uri="http://www.legalaidrwanda.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="1" year="2020">
     <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
     <dimension name="SMS Portal" value="1"></dimension>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">SMS Portal for USSD available by dialing *845#</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="SMS Portal" value="USSD"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SMS Portal enable USSD message to be accessible</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <location ref="Rwanda"></location>
      <dimension name="SMS Portal" value="USSD System"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is operating</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
