<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-10516061-ContentDevelopmentPartnerSCE</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-10516061" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cobra Collective CIC</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Content Development Partner for UN Women Second Chance Education and Vocational Training Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of the UN Women&#x2019;s Second Chance Education and Vocational Training (SCE) Programme, this project will develop, pilot and test a participatory video approach to the development and contextualisation of online courses targeting the most disadvantaged women across Cameroon, Jordan, India, Mexico, Chile and Australia, in a way that aligns with their cultural and socio-economic contexts, and ultimately catalyses improved economic and employment opportunities for them. The courses will be focused on Life/Career Planning, Digital Literacy and Financial Literacy/Entrepreneurship, and are aimed at 67,000 women and young women from Indigenous, refugee, displaced, and low-income groups in the six countries.

The online courses will have significant video content, and the Collective will be working closely with the Open University to ensure that course design aligns with video content. We will be leading the participatory video process with facilitators in each country to ensure that the courses are co-designed and women from the beneficiary communities are part of the creation and testing of the videos for the courses.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-000391" role="2" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Open University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41146" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AU" percentage="16.65"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CL" percentage="16.67"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CM" percentage="16.67"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="16.67"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="16.67"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="16.67"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11230" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-22">111600</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
