<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DE-CR-BonnVR8726-4.3.4.</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Networking, knowledge exchange with partners and allies</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IFOAM-Organics International advocacy team mapped the scene and produced a policy gap analysis of all four project countries. Strategic discussions took place with the Forum for Agricultural Research in Africa (FARA) on presenting the case of organic agriculture as a tool to address poverty, food security and nutrition in Africa at the FARA Science Week in October 2019. Knowledge exchange meetings with a view to align efforts with Agronome et V&#xE9;t&#xE9;rinaires Sans Fronti&#xE8;res (AVSF) on the &#x2018;Support Project to the Agro-ecological Transition in West Africa&apos; were organised at UNFCCC COP24. Meeting the Steering Group of the Decade of Family Farming in FAO to discuss our possible involvement including showcasing results of the OM4D project. Participation at the launch event in May 2019 and the preparatory conference in March. Networking with civil society organisations based and/or active in the 4 countries on agriculture-related issues at UNFCCC COP24 in Katowice. Preparations for UNEA-4, where governments, including to discuss issues on SDG12, i.e. responsible consumption and production, for which OM4D is of great relevance. Meetings are planned with governments as well as civil society organisations in the 4 countries to hold them accountable on their commitments towards organic farming.Networking with various organisations and donors working in projects related to agriculture and poverty alleviation at CFS46.At WAOC 2019 we exchanged views and had vibrant discussions with a broad range of stakeholders ranging from farmers and grassroots organisations to high-level policy makers in the countries, ECOWAS and the AU. It assisted us in refining our advocacy plans both at the country and the regional level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ST" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TG" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
