<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DE-CR-BonnVR8726-4.3.1.</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Identify key regional and international processes and events to influence as well as key partners and allies</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is an ongoing activity that will be implemented during the whole duration of the project. Key regional and international policy processes and events are currently being identified, with a focus on poverty, smallholders, PGS, the African context (AU, CAADP etc.) and the M4P approach. An events calendar was set up for regional and international events relevant for our advocacy efforts. The calendar is updated regularly as advocacy plans become better defined. Mapping of all possibly relevant policy processes started at the national as well as regional and African level, to be finished in Q1 Y2, in the context of the detailed advocacy plans. During Q6, the mapping of all possibly relevant policy processes at the national as well as regional and African level has been continued. Opportunities identified so far for 2019 to showcase OM4D achievements with a view to strengthen the countries&#x2019; commitments to make organic markets work for the poor were: - CAADP Partnership Platform, Rabat, 27-31 May, - Eastern Africa Conference on scaling up Agroecology and Ecological Organic Trade, Nairobi, 18-20 June 2019, - UNCCD COP14, New Delhi, 7-18 October, - Committee on World Food Security meeting, FAO, Rome, 14-18 October, - 8th Africa Agriculture Science Week, Cairo, 18-21 October, - Global Landscapes Forum Africa Regional Conference, Accra, 25-25 October. Key regional processes and events identified for end of Year 2 and the first quarter of Project Year 3 were: - the FARA Africa Agricultural Science Week which was postponed from October 2019 to an unknown date, - the West African Organic Conference taking place in Accra Ghana mid-November, - the UNFCCC COP25 in Santiago, Chile which was then moved to Madrid, Spain, early December, - the High-Level Segment of the Food Systems Dialogues organized by the World Economic Forum in Davos, January 2020. Further processes and events are being identified for 2020 on an ongoing basis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ST" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TG" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
