<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DE-CR-BonnVR8726-1.1.2.</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholder analysis (Stocktaking of institutions involved in the organic movement, including a mapping of development programmes)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity aims at stocktaking of institutions (formal or informal) that are engaged in the organic movement the four project countries. The analysis includes work processes, relations and power positions among the different relevant organisations. The methodology chosen for the stakeholder analysis was the Rapid Appraisal of the Agricultural Knowledge System (RAAKS) - a participatory action-research type of approach. RAAKS methodology allows stakeholders to map the sector by tracing functional interactions among the actors but also by developing solutions to overcome the identified challenges. The categories of actors that were analysed included producers, processors, input suppliers, service providers, technical partners, certification bodies, donors, academia, policy makers, consumers and platforms, which provided a very comprehensive view of the organic sector. In regard to the current blockages and the respective solutions, these were grouped in three categories: development of domestic market, development of the export market and the strengthening of the organic sector. For every category a sub-set of challenges was identified, together with the proposed solutions and the actors in charge. Thus, the RAAKS methodology bridged the stakeholder analysis to the NAPs that will start being developed in the second project year. Another important aspect is that many of the actions to be taken were attributed to the current or future national movements, which was also a useful exercise to reflect on the role these national institutions should play in developing the sector. As a general conclusion, there were many similar solutions to a relatively homogeneous set of challenges identified in all four project countries, but also some notable differences like for example the Ghanaian stakeholders focusing more on the strengthening of the sector, and the Togolese focusing on the internal markets. These first directions will be observed and analysed during the next stakeholders&#x2019; meetings, since they will play an important role in shaping the existing and/ or future national movements. The stakeholder analysis was finalised in all four project countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="1.1.2." ref="NL-KVK-59493593" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agro Eco</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="1.1.2." ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="1.1.2." ref="XM-DAC-7" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ST" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TG" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Factsheet-OM4D-Ghana-20190709090723.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Factsheets OM4D Ghana</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Stakeholder-analysis-BF-20190201080225.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Stakeholder analysis Burkina Faso</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Stakeholder-analysis-Ghana-20190201080206.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholder analysis Ghana</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/PGS-Feasibility-Study_Togo-20190201050236.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Stakeholder analysis Togo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
