<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DE-CR-BonnVR8726-2.1.4.</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PGS feasibility studies</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feasibility studies were carried out in Togo, Sao Tome, Ghana. For Burkina Faso no feasibility study is foreseen as PGS is already implemented successfully. In Sao Tome the study was combined with activity 2.1.4. &#x2013; the basic PGS training. Information was collected from stakeholders and many aspects related to the feasibility of PGS were discussed during the training. Additional information was collected by visiting markets, shops, hotels, NGOs working with agriculture and farms. Representatives from the government held an official opening ceremony, broadcast via radio and TV. The resulting feasibility study is finalised and attached to this activity. In Togo the study was combined with activity 2.1.4. &#x2013; the basic PGS training. Information was collected from stakeholders and many aspects related to the feasibility of PGS were discussed during the training. Additional information was collected by visiting markets, shops and some of the organic processing companies. A meeting with representatives from the government was also organised in order to complement the information already collected. The report is finalised and attached to this activity. In Ghana the study was combined with activity 2.1.4. - the basic PGS training. Information was collected from stakeholders and many aspects related to the feasibility of PGS were discussed during the training. Additional information was collected during the expert dialogue organised on 14 June and by visiting a farms, markets and shops. The report is finalised and attached to this activity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="33"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ST" percentage="33"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TG" percentage="34"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/PGS-Feasibility-Study_Togo-20190201050226.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feasibility Study Togo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-06-20"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/PGS-Feasibility-Study_Ghana--20190201050234.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feasibility Study Ghana</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
