<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DE-CR-BonnVR8726-4.1.1.</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Map existing policies, policy processes and policy issues relevant to OA in each country</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Togo: A report was finalised and is available in English and French. In the past support by the Togolese government to organic agriculture was very limited and no specific laws or institutions to support the development of the sector had existed. Recently several developments of relevance for the development of the organic sector in the country have been observed. In 2018 a new National Development Plan (2018-2022 with a vision 2030) was published which includes some provisions for the development of the organic sector in Togo. In February 2019 the Ministry of Agriculture, Animal Production and Fisheries (MAPAH) issued a &#x201C;concept note for the national conversion of the agricultural sector to organic&#x201D;, which outlines key elements of what would constitute a national organic conversion program. Later on, in May 2019, a draft version of an agricultural orientation act was shared for stakeholder input. This document includes the following articles (translated from French): &#x201C;Article 96: The State, in consultation with the other actors, draws up and implements a national policy for the development of organic agriculture. (&#x2026;) Article 136: The State encourages the use of biofertilizers and bio pesticides and other forms of natural fertilisers and creates the necessary conditions for the installation of new factories for the local manufacture of fertilisers and derivatives from available natural resources.&#x201D; These documents indicate a political will on the part of the government to genuinely support organic agriculture. The interest of the government appears to be directed towards export as the primary goal but also to build the domestic market. Sao Tom&#xE9; and Pr&#xED;ncipe: A report was finalised in October and is available in English. Although specific policies to support organic agriculture have not yet been passed, various policy documents address topics of interest that provide the lens through which organic agriculture can be seen as able to provide contributions such as: - Promoting family farming - Achieving SDG 2 - Increasing and diversifying local production of sustainable food - Public procurement for school meals (prioritising purchases from small family farmers, including organic or agroecological producers) - Climate change and Biodiversity remain relevant, overarching topics. As set out in the country&#x2019;s development strategy, &#x201C;Sao Tome and Principe Transformation Agenda 2030: The country we need to build&#x201D;, the Government aims to implement sustainable food security and nutrition programmes and policies autonomously by 2030 and has requested technical assistance from WFP. The current Minister of Agriculture, Francisco Ramos, has publicly expressed the commitment from the government to promote sustainable, local production of agricultural goods and is a strong supporter of organic agriculture. Burkina Faso: A report was finalised and is available in English. In Burkina Faso no policies to support organic agriculture have been passed to date. However the General Directorate of Plant Production has been appointed as the focal point for agroecology. Ghana: In Ghana the mapping exercise is still ongoing and the report is not finalised yet. In Ghana the support to conventional agriculture is relatively high with a strong focus of the government to increase agricultural productivity. As a consequence agriculture in Ghana over the last two decades has transformed towards broad utilisation of a variety of conventional inputs. At the same time support/a favorable attitude towards organic agriculture also has some history in Ghana. At least since 2014 organic agriculture (usually called Ecological Organic Agriculture) has been mentioned by government representatives as an area that needs to be supported and developed. As concrete measures the Ministry of Agriculture set-up an Organic Desk and has developed a Code of Organic Practices (not applied yet).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ST" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TG" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
