<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-11-3803281-Good Export Practices</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-11-3803281" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Center for Economic Transformation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Good Export Practices</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a one-year project (May 2021-April 2022) funded by the Swiss National Science Foundation (SNSF) on Good Export Practices. The Buenas Practicas Exportadoras (BPE) or Good Export Practices Program is an export capability-building program for small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs), active in a strategic sector of the economy, and producing differentiated goods. It is based on the findings of the work by Artopolous et al. (2011 and 2013) that one of the main barriers hindering firms from exporting is a lack of foreign market knowledge. The program builds upon the insight that management matters and that the diffusion and adoption of good export practices is crucial for export performance.
This project is in the initiation stage. ACET has signed an MOU with GEPA, reviewed 20 practices, and put out a TOR for a consultant. The project is a partnership between University of Applied Sciences Western Switzerland, HEG-Gen&#xE8;ve, Switzerland, Universidad de Buenos Aires, Argentina and ACET.

Q2 2021
The project is currently at diagnosis phase and training materials for Ghana have been developed and customised. Training of consultants for the technical assistance phase has been completed as well. With regards to the selection of participating firms, ACET received a total of 220 applications with 197 selected. Since it is a prerequisite to select 200 participating firms in other to complete the diagnosis phase, preparations are underway to select 3 additional firms in Q3. Training of consultants for the diagnosis of firms is ongoing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Center for Economic Transformation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="99" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="Export capability program">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is a partnership between University of Applied Sciences Western Switzerland, HEG-Gen&#xE8;ve, Switzerland, Universidad de Buenos Aires, Argentina and ACET.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">39300</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="ACET RS23-D Q2 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">1656</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated communication and publication cost for the period April - June 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET RS23-D Q2 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">26706</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost for the period April-June 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET RS23-D Q2 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">329</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated expenses incurred on lecture and workshops during the period April-June 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET RS23-D Q2 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">8209</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost for the period April-June 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
