<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-11-3803281-PSD</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-11-3803281" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Center for Economic Transformation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development- Promoting Sustainable Export Processing Zones (SEPZ)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In first-quarter 2020, ACET began project management and resource planning and stakeholder engagement, and initiated a landscape assessment and benchmarking study.To date, terms of reference (TORs) have been developed and a consultant engaged to lead this work.  The team has since completed the inception report.

In September 2020, ACET organized a Private Sector Development Strategy retreat in Ghana to review program objectives and initiate preparation towards the development of a strategic and operational plans. Present were internal and external stakeholders from both private and public sectors.

In Q3, we initiated a work with the International Senior Lawyers Project (ISLP) to review various legal/regulatory aspects and studies of the PSD work. Other project activities have been on external stakeholder engagements and recruitment of a portfolio coordinator.

ACET has contracted the Ghana Free Zones Board as a key partner for the SEPZ &#x2013; EPZ Landscape Assessment and Benchmarking Study. 

As an outcome of the September Strategy session, we will undertake a study on the impact of EPZs on the implementation of the AfCFTA and vice versa. The scope/TOR is being amended to extend the consultant&#x2019;s engagement. Expert reviewers are also being engaged to review our studies and provide insights. The team has reached out for further discussion with the AfCFTA Secretariat.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank, the Norwegian Agency for Development Cooperation (NORAD), and ACET are collaborating on a program to support private sector development and growth in G20 Compact with Africa countries, starting with Ghana. The project is on the manufacturing sector, given the relevance of manufacturing to economic transformation and the industry&#x2019;s ability to generate sustainable, explosive growth. To support this agenda in 2020, the ACET program will focus on three work streams: (1) promoting the development of sustainable export processing zones (SEPZ) aligned with Ghana&#x2019;s industrial policy; (2) supporting local content through the integration of small- and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) in the global supply chain and value-chains of large enterprises; and (3) supporting the integration of local SMEs in the promotion of SEPZ.

Q4 2020
The Ghana Free Zones Board has been engaged as a key partner for the SEPZ &#x2013; EPZ Landscape Assessment and Benchmarking Study which started this quarter. Interviews with members of the Free Zones have been scheduled and are ongoing. Expert reviewers were also engaged to evaluate our studies and provide insights.

Additional stakeholders including the Association of Member Companies in the Free Zones, the Ministry of Trade and Industry and Ghana Export Promotion Authority have been identified with preparations for engagement in session.

As an outcome of the September Strategy session, we have completed a study on the impact of EPZs on the implementation of the AfCTA and vice versa. The draft report has been reviewed and is undergoing finalization by our consultant. Plans for using the report to engage interested parties around the AfCTA implementation has been designed. 

Q1 2021
(1) Benchmarking Study - Research is ongoing to benchmark good practices regarding the alignment between Ghana&#x2019;s EPZ and sustainable infrastructure, practices, and firms. Production of a draft study report is in progress and will be informed by the recommendations from the AfCTA study completed last quarter, and the landscape assessment. Next steps include external reviews followed by a validation study with key stakeholders. Prior to this the team also completed a landscaping assessment to inform the benchmarking study. 
(2) SEPZ Model and Retrofit: This activity will support the retrofitting of an existing EPZ into an SEPZ as a test case for development and subsequent replication. Aligned to the activities above, ACET will also support efforts to crowd-in additional investment, however this phase has not yet started. In the interim, ACET will develop a model framework for an SEPZ to be socialized with African countries.

Q2 2021
1) Landscape Assessment and Benchmarking Study &#x2013; During the second quarter of 2021, the team completed the Benchmarking Studies. The draft reports for the landscape assessment and the benchmarking research have been finalized, gone through two external reviews and the comments from the reviews have been absorbed into the final report. The reports are undergoing final editorial for publications.

Validation Workshop: On 10 June 2021, ACET convened a workshop and policy dialogue on &#x201C;Sustainable Export Processing Zones as a feasible approach for job creation&#x201D; at The African Regent Hotel- Ghana. The workshop hosted key stakeholders from the Ministry of Trade and Industry (MOTI), the Ghana Free Zones Authority (FZA), Ghana Investment Promotion Centre (GIPC), Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office (FCDO), private sector and development institutions. Also present were three critical reviewers and discussants drawn from academia, CSO (Civil Society Organizations) and Government of Ghana Economic Management Team. Various media houses in attendance interviewed and featured the topical discussions at the event on their platforms. 

Impact &#x2013; The Ghana Free Zones Authority (FZA) is undertaking a review of the Free Zones Act and Regulations. The FZA and MOTI revealed their reference to the report as a strong basis for the upcoming review of the ACT and other relevant legislative instruments. The parties have also indicated the need for ACET to drive the implementation of the recommendations by championing and moderating further dialogues.

(2) SEPZ Model and Retrofit: This activity will support the retrofitting of an existing EPZ into an SEPZ as a test case for development and subsequent replication. Aligned to the activities above, ACET will also support efforts to crowd-in additional investment, however this phase has not yet started. In the interim, ACET will develop a model framework for an SEPZ to be socialized with African countries.

Q3 2021
In Q3, the landscape assessment and the benchmarking study were finalized for publication. Planning activities for next phase of the project has been completed and preparations to recruit a consultant for the project has commenced.
 
Policy Uptake/Impact 
ACET has initiated a discourse with the Ghana Free Zones Authority on supporting ongoing review of the Free Zones Act and Regulations.  

2) SEPZ Model and Retrofit: This activity will support the retrofitting of an existing EPZ into an SEPZ as a test case for development and subsequent replication. Aligned to the activities above, ACET will also support efforts to crowd-in additional investment, however this phase has not yet started. In the interim, ACET will develop a model framework for an SEPZ to be socialized with African countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a program to promote the development of sustainable export processing zones (SEPZ) aligned with the government of Ghana&#x2019;s One Region, One Park (1R1P) policy. This sub-component will focus on two key activities: (1) diagnosis and evaluation of current export processing zone (EPZ) ecosystems and benchmarking against good practices regarding the alignment between Ghana&#x2019;s EPZ and sustainable infrastructure, practices and firms; and (2) support to retrofitting of an existing EPZ into an SEPZ as a test case for development and subsequent replication. Aligned to the activities above, ACET will also support efforts to crowd-in additional investment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="PSD" crs-channel-code="21000" ref="US-EIN-11-3803281" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Center for Economic Transformation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project officially started this year</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACET is a Ghanaian based organization with an office in Washington, DC</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="99" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="English">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project on Private sector development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">104900</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">25000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">33800</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">16300</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-31">45000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-30">58400</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET PM05 Q2 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">191</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated administration expenses for the period April-June 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="5.ACET PM05 Q2 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">1387</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated communications and Publication cost for the period April-June 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. PM05 Q2 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">77676</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost for the period April-June 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET PM05 Q1 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-31">37967</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost for the period January-March 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET PM05 Q3 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">14063</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from July- September 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET PMO5 Q4 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">8862</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from October to December 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET PM05 Q3 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">2183</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated expenditure incurred on Lecture and workshop from July to September</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET PMO5 Q4 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">893</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated expenditure on lecture and workshops for the period October-December 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4. ACET PM05 Q2 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">2398</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated expenses incurred on lecture and workshops during the period April-June 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET PM05- Q2 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">22792</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost for the period April-June 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET PM05 Q1 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-31">7874</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost for the period Jan-March 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET PM05 Q3 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-30">22843</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost for the period July to September 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET PM05-A Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">9010</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost from April-June 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET PM05 Q3 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">17462</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost from July-September 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET PMO5 Q4 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">6693</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost incurred during the period October to December 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET PM05- A Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">15700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accuulated consultancy cost from April-June 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4. ACET PM05 Q3 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-30">42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative expenses incurred between July and September 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET PM05 Q3 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-30">30383</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consultancy codt for the period July to September 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="5. ACET PM05 Q3 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-30">2398</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenses incurred on Lecture and workshop from July to September 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="6. ACET PM05 Q3 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-30">399</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenses incurred on Communication and publication during the period July to September 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET PM05 Q3 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-30">2293</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Travel cost incurred during the period July to September 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
